
Speaker 1  (01:07)
Hello? Today, you're much of A 

Speaker 2  (01:12)
Call you, haveyou've good for the good perfect. 

Speaker 1  (01:16)
I guess I should start. Let me see, or should I start? Okay, lots of great things happened this week. 

Speaker 1  (01:25)
The very first one, which I was super duper. Excited about that. Was our meeting with lawyer registration? 

Speaker 1  (01:31)
Thank you very much for some kind of referring Mr. Butler, he was so nice and at first, he told us that we'll be better to have another one in our meeting, Mr. White House than he introduced us to another guy, Mr. 

Speaker 1  (01:48)
saxie. If you're from UK so you can imagine at the very beginning. It was a normal meeting exactly. 

Speaker 1  (01:53)
Yes, so I was so nervous about that one because I have to talk with three people. That's why I asked my some kind of industrial partner. He also joined the meeting and it was fantastic. 

Speaker 1  (02:07)
We talked for about 1 hour rather than talking and asking questions, actually V had our some kind of proposal. It was a pitch proposal. I mean, I have to say we talked about it. 

Speaker 1  (02:20)
They loved it. I mean, obviously they told us there would be some challenges and we tried to talk about it. We tried to say that yeah, we know we do have some competitors like the fields. 

Speaker 1  (02:30)
Node and other kind of things. But we try to focus on the fact that we would be Canada based. So we are trying to do that. 

Speaker 1  (02:38)
And I found out the Atlantic Excel recently. I mean, last week, I guess they got the first am certified part from the loyal registration. So congratulation to them and I was also considering I'm not sure if it's possible or not to maybe have another meeting with Sean to see if there is any potential for us to maybe have a little bit partnership or maybe at least give some kind of feedback from them. 

Speaker 1  (03:04)
Because apparently they're so active in this some kind of field, another thing that happened was VP VAT a little bit about our idea. So our idea the first was very simple, but be found out there are lots of challenges because when we were talking with Mr. saxie he told us that okay if you would like to work on this platform, you have to make sure that you have bend your part is going to be certified. 

Speaker 1  (03:28)
It has to be a recipe not just only fun one device. Obviously you don't have only one device. We don't have on one powder. 

Speaker 1  (03:36)
We have everything. So this is another challenge that we have to work on that another thing that we found out was, oh about the Canadian navy angle we talked with Mr. Whitestone and White House. 

Speaker 1  (03:48)
Sorry, he told us that the navy and defense are putting a huge amount of budget on using some kind of additive, manufacturing and reprinting. I knew that one before, because I was talking with a couple of navy people and talis, they told me the same thing, so it means that if at least at the very beginning stage, if you would like to have some budgets and work on it, obviously we need money so it would be better to work through. That. 

Speaker 1  (04:16)
Related to that I was talking with Mr. Defalco, from ngen and next month at the end of next month, they do have this event that all of them end 3 and Gen., I guess N3 summits. So yeah, probably I would be there. 

Speaker 1  (04:33)
Try to some kind of talk with so many people to see that what are their ideas? I mean, it would be after lap to market, but I don't care at this stage. Lap to market is not my goal. 

Speaker 1  (04:43)
I mean, my goal is actually try to work on this platform as much as possible. So he encouraged me, I thought that yeah, why not? It's just 2 days in Toronto, so I would probably go there then I talk with one person from Equinox. 

Speaker 1  (04:57)
I mean, he wasn't in additive manufacturing part, but he gave me some good information about this ROI and equinore, especially with the project that they're going on bedunock. I believe every time I'm your spirit now said it's a big project. Around 10:12 billion dollars. 

Speaker 1  (05:14)
They're still at the researching. Is, I guess it would be some kind of the goal for 20 30 20 30 to something rather less maybe more. I'm not sure, so I thought it would be better to talk with more equinor people to see how is their idea about additive manufacturing? 

Speaker 1  (05:33)
Yeah, that's from my side. Oh, by the way, before I forget, is that you mentioned a couple of names to me, the very first one was about He threw Davis, I guess from a care solution. If I remember very right you had, oh yeah, Heather. 

Speaker 1  (05:54)
Yeah. I'm sorry yeah, so I sent an email but I didn't receive anything yet. I mean, probably, I would send another email to see what's going on. 

Speaker 1  (06:05)
Another one was about from polyunity, so I sent a message to Mr. Stefan Ryan probably he is busy because he answered me once and he told me that we can talk next week. I sent 1 or 2 emails after that. 

Speaker 1  (06:19)
He hasn't responded yet so today probably I'm going to send him another email. Because every time I talk with somebody, they're referred me to polling unity. He said, okay, talk with them. 

Speaker 1  (06:28)
There would be the very some kind of good source and yeah, that was from my side. I'm sorry I was a little bit excited to try to give you everything that I've got. 

Speaker 2  (06:39)
When you know you only have a short period of time. It's like it's called word vomit. You know you just like 

Speaker 1  (06:44)
What it also land yeah, exactly 

Speaker 2  (06:47)
So I put in the chat there. It helps in your communication defense. They release the document there last week, or maybe it was this week where they highlight. 

Speaker 2  (07:05)
Advanced manufa. 

Speaker 1  (07:07)
Definitely, yeah. Yeah. 

Speaker 2  (07:08)
Brayden, so this is their wording on what they are looking for cap. 

Speaker 1  (07:12)
Melodies guess. 

Speaker 2  (07:13)
Why they are looking for these capab? 

Speaker 1  (07:16)
Grandmother's yet. 

Speaker 2  (07:17)
So like when you're talking in the defense sector if you're using their wording It helps in their communication. Is this you know, and if you can speak to how you were responding to these needs, right? So that's a document that's produced by the defense. 

Speaker 2  (07:35)
Just this past week which highlights like I said, advance, manufacturing soap, you know, and advance. Manufacturing is all the is not just Additive, but it is the one of the main components, right? 

Speaker 1  (07:50)
Yeah, got it. Got it. By the way, I see that there's easy repair. 

Speaker 1  (07:55)
Because I'm not sure who is your other some kind of people that you're working with. By the way, do you have any person with the name of Muhammad thereza in your some kind of from laptop markets? In who Mari is mohammedrezza is his name. 

Speaker 1  (08:14)
Yeah, oh okay. 

Speaker 2  (08:15)
I'm not working with them though. 

Speaker 1  (08:16)
Oh, because yesterday in our meeting that we had for the lab 2 market, he was also working in the same some kind of concept. And he was mentioning something about the additive repair. I mean, using the additive manufacturing for repair. 

Speaker 1  (08:33)
I mean, probably I'm going to talk with him because I found out his area of work is very, very similar to mine to maybe gather some knowledge. Would it be okay if we do have this kind of meeting incited up to market? I mean, it's not against 

Speaker 2  (08:48)
That's an interview. Just like anything else right? You know, you can talk to entrepreneurs as well as things. 

Speaker 2  (08:57)
It is all input into getting you towards the end goal right? And like at that manufacturing one of its key use cases is on the repair side of things, right? Because you're looking at Sometimes obsolete equipment, so like equipment. 

Speaker 2  (09:19)
That's been in the field for say, 10 years or something. Along those lines, a component goes down. So, you know, you will have to order that piece sometimes because it's a 10-year-old piece, you know, at the The original manufacturers like, well, we don't make that anymore. 

Speaker 2  (09:39)
It has to be a specialty piece. Here's the cause. It'll take you 6 to eight weeks blah. 

Speaker 2  (09:43)
Blah blah, whereas additive manufacturing can take that design and you know, local source it to you can have it in two weeks. All right makes sense and typically probably cheaper too than going back to the original manufacturer, right? 

Speaker 1  (10:01)
Yeah 

Speaker 2  (10:02)
So that so that repair side of things like, you know, Atlantic Excel, some of the they're, you know, they're relatively new, but some of there Winds is getting doing repair work like a component breaks out and might be small piece might be a bigger piece, but some of their early winds were on the repair side. 

Speaker 1  (10:26)
Okay, okay, that makes sense. And then you're also talking about this obsolete parts. I am also thinking about the river's engineering because some of the people mentioned that I've heard about there is a company plague 3, D. 

Speaker 1  (10:39)
I'm not sure for pronounced break, but they also doing the same thing. I mean, I'm not sure if they are in Canada. Just a name that popped in my head. 

Speaker 1  (10:49)
They do have scanners, and they do scan the parts that we don't have any blueprint for that, and they will just kind of do the reverse engineering. Do you think it also would be useful to work on that area or no I have to some kind of maybe focus it on the other stages of my work. 

Speaker 2  (11:07)
No, because you're looking at from You're looking at sort of like you're making a digital warehouse, right? So you're working with these, and that's, you know, you're working with the manufacturers, you're working at the designers, you're working with the customers who so that you're the one spot shop, you're the Amazon for additive manufacturing, right, you don't necessarily make the parks. You don't necessarily design the products you're just on platform where people go in and do it right, so When you look at You know, we've talked about that engineering side of it. 

Speaker 2  (11:49)
They have to be they have to be part of that. Ecosystem. So let's designing a new pieces or designing reengineering of old pieces. 

Speaker 2  (11:59)
So Atlantic xl Part of their business model is that the fact that they can We're engineering those obsolete east to repair pieces, right? Because go to them to get a part. Get it in like a week or 2 versus ordering it somewhere around the world and getting manufactured. 

Speaker 2  (12:20)
Right? So, whether it is Atlantic Excel, or it is a specialty shop that does that reverse engineering. You know? 

Speaker 2  (12:31)
That is one of those inputs into your warehouse. So that you can connect You know, because you still someone needs to and someone needs to engineer the piece. Someone needs to Build it and then someone has to buy it. 

Speaker 2  (12:47)
Yeah. Right whether or not that's a re-engineered piece or an old piece. The 3 components are still required to be inputs into your Digital warehouse? 

Speaker 2  (13:01)
That's right. Oh yeah, so talking to Plate 3D or whoever it is. It's all inputs on whether or not they be Components into that like. 

Speaker 2  (13:13)
So your time on digital warehouse, all it has to design the pieces that are on your warehouse. You know, and then somebody has to Building yeah. The customer is one that comes and buys it right? 

Speaker 2  (13:29)
So however you develop your Pay model. So like how do those engineering firms or those manufacturing firms get a piece of that pie? But by Being a part of your warehouse right, yeah. 

Speaker 1  (13:47)
Makes sense. Got it ah. 

Speaker 2  (13:49)
So like Amazon, get Amazon. Yes, like the Amazon model. Is that it they take a percentage? 

Speaker 2  (13:58)
The money flows back to the shop. Where you're buying it from, but because Amazon houses, they take what 10% or whatever the fee is, but they give it a platform. For one-stop shop and so because it's the one-stop shop. 

Speaker 2  (14:14)
You look at this component that component. And so you keep ongoing back to the same platform. So that's kind of like what you're doing. 

Speaker 2  (14:20)
You just you're creating a platform that everybody will go into that one stop shop to find the pieces or to make contact with. So on to design a new piece Yada, Yada, Yada, right? Yeah. 

Speaker 1  (14:31)
Oh, yeah makes sense. Another thing that we were considered doing was that actually the main concept of our work was encouraging industries to have on-site 3D printing device, rather than just having that platform. It was some kind of in the main business plan. 

Speaker 1  (14:48)
The reason I'm saying that because I was also talking with people from the navy and defense, they some kind of like that idea, they already have some 3D printing, but they don't know what they can do with it. The judges just were hobby. Another industry that I was interested in was about the Arctic ones. 

Speaker 1  (15:04)
Probably there are the most isolated locations that we do have in Canada. Because of the weather because of the harsh condition, they would like to somehow reduce their some kind of the amount of cost that they have. Because their warehouse they need to be people. 

Speaker 1  (15:24)
There obviously having people cost a lot of money would be there as well. And somehow they're looking for a way to do that. So, having considering this fact that I would like to help industries to have this one part of the problem, I mean, it's a big problem rather than talking with regulations, it would be well talking with oems, because somehow you have to convince them that oak. 

Speaker 1  (15:49)
I'm a trusted platform and you can give me your blueprints. Probably the very first question they would ask, okay, I was the security obviously about the cybersecurity and other parts. I was thinking by myself and said saying that okay? 

Speaker 1  (16:09)
All of the blueprints that if you're talking are IPS, I mean, all of them are registered. I mean, you cannot have it. And use it as the competitor probably they're going to find out they're going to sue you. 

Speaker 1  (16:22)
So it doesn't vorce it. For example, when one oem's blueprint licked, another oem is going to use that. I mean, I'm not sure about it. 

Speaker 1  (16:31)
I was a thinking by myself. But my question is sorry, my mind is not narrowed down right now. But my question is that how I can convince the oems, just saying that I do have the very, very secure platform. 

Speaker 1  (16:47)
Probably is not going to convince them, but how I can convince them that. Okay, trust me. 

Speaker 2  (16:54)
While it's, you know, it is, you know, I'll talk it through. So let's just say because when you're talking about the Arctic and things like that 3D printing, you're really only talking about polymer printing. Right? 

Speaker 2  (17:11)
And polymer printing still has limitations because of the strength and the size of the a particular printer. Right, so what your proposing is that you can work with these design companies. Who put out let's just say you want to print. 

Speaker 2  (17:33)
In unmatched, out of the component for the mouse or whatever like that. So That you want to have a secured platform where yes, the plans go your housing, the plans, but no one can look at the plans until they are purchased. All right. 

Speaker 2  (17:53)
So you have to then find a way of how is that Plans Then? Pushed to the printer on the other side. So there has to be some kind of secured code kind of deal that talks to the printer. 

Speaker 2  (18:11)
So you download and activates the printer kind of deal, but the person on the receiving size can't go in there and manipulate it right? That should be doable. Okay, right like it's a secure file. 

Speaker 2  (18:27)
Whatever like that there are, I don't think it's beyond that. A book beyond capabilities, right? So You know, it's still IP you know, they have their IP for that design if they don't have an IP to that particular design component, then they're not protected regardless. 

Speaker 2  (18:50)
But if the people who have the design and that's an IP design, it's like You know somebody designs this ps. I can. Scan that. 

Speaker 2  (19:01)
Reverse engineer it and create a component, but if I turn around and try to sell that component. You know to resell it? Well, then, the the company who designed that mouse can come after me. 

Speaker 2  (19:16)
Yeah. That is normal distance. You put this out in the marketplace, someone can rescan it. 

Speaker 2  (19:24)
And sell it, but they try to make money out of it. The lawyers from the person who the design will come after you. Right. 

Speaker 2  (19:31)
So that That logic is still there like you're creating that warehouse you're creating that, you know, that catalog of these components that are all protected by whoever designed them, you know, you're not giving away that anybody can look up to them. Somebody pays for it. They download it. 

Speaker 2  (19:52)
So, you know exactly who ends up with these designs. All right, we're talking about polymer designs on that particular scenario, which is not AA Large ticket item, but yeah, if someone comes there and buys 10 and starts selling it on their own marketplace. Well, you have traceability back 

Speaker 1  (20:15)
Osa eh said. 

Speaker 2  (20:16)
That person bought off me, cut Geo, that's you. Can you know The person who owns the IP can do it right. So it's all about you're protecting their IP, you know we're not giving away the codes for free. 

Speaker 2  (20:30)
Someone has to pay for it. It's a traceability from designer to end user. All right, there's no difference. 

Speaker 2  (20:39)
Then, buying it off amaz. 

Speaker 1  (20:41)
Exactly, no a completely like the idea. Cause devil's the exact same thing. I thought, because deriving you that we were working on was about 2 parts. 

Speaker 1  (20:52)
The very first part is that me as a manufacturer. The end user client. I'm going to pay one time fee as purchasing that oem. 

Speaker 1  (21:02)
Not purchasing to be for myself, just purchasing to have it on-site every time. If I want to print it again, I have to pay another amount of money to the manufacturer to say that hey I'm printing this one. Because we would like to keep the track we would like to have the log rather than security on other parts. 

Speaker 1  (21:21)
This thing that you mentioned yes, we have that plan for but yeah, that makes sense that completely makes sense, right? 

Speaker 2  (21:27)
So you're thinking about the Amazon model, right? Like Has the warehouse? Yes, you have that privilege of getting onto your platform. 

Speaker 2  (21:36)
So I think maybe initially has a platform. You would buy the plans and then you sell it on. But the other way is that You are you are Amazon platform. 

Speaker 2  (21:53)
So we partner up your partner with these people who put their designs on there, and then we just take to help resell it. We get whatever 10% of the cost for housing being the warehouse. But 90% of it still goes back to the original manufacturing the original designer. 

Speaker 2  (22:14)
I shouldn' 

Speaker 1  (22:15)
Makes sense. Yeah. 

Speaker 2  (22:16)
So that's a way of your Partners. You're not you're not You're not like the traditional warehouse where you go to these suppliers. Grab hand hammers and then resell those 10 hammers, right? 

Speaker 2  (22:35)
You have to have an ever-evolving thing. Where? Because you're in a digital age, the things can change quite quickly, right? 

Speaker 2  (22:42)
The designs can change quite quickly, right? So and then so I think the partnership with the original designers is the way to go. Yeah, so in the chat in the chat there going back to a previous point that you made about, you know 3D scanning so yeah. 

Speaker 2  (23:05)
At the college, here they have a technology, excess center, this technology access center all over Canada. I think there's 36 of these access centers, but each one has the specialty. This one here is the reality capture. 

Speaker 2  (23:20)
And digitalization, what they actually do part of their business is that 3D scanning they have multiple different types of scanners that they can do that, they can scan something and reproduce it interesting, right? A lot of it is what they use it for is more of like a point, cloud type of like I'm gonna scan the building here. And so I can get a 3D rendering of the building that's majority of how they work, but they also have the capability of the handheld devices, or things like that. 

Speaker 2  (23:57)
To actually scan amounts and reproduce that mouse. So that you could 3D printed Right? So they are another Element that you could talk to on that whole Scanning for reengineering, okay, perfect, right? 

Speaker 2  (24:18)
Third third niche, you know, Atlantic xl, you've already talked to them and you probably should reach out to their, they do it as well, and they do it more on the engineering that is One of their models, where this reality captured digitalization. It's not specific to parts, because they do polymer for that. So they're a little bit more smaller components, Atlantic xl does to reengineering for mechanical components. 

Speaker 2  (24:50)
So it's just as someone else, you can talk to that reengineering side of things. 

Speaker 1  (24:55)
Very excess got it for sure. We reach out to them. I see. 

Speaker 1  (24:59)
We do have around maybe 6 or 7 minutes. I do have 2 quick questions. When I was talking with people, some of them mentioned a name, Brad Elliott, to me, it's from equinore, I'm not sure if you know him that I can. 

Speaker 2  (25:13)
I've already given you this context. 

Speaker 1  (25:15)
Oh, you did oh okay, okay? 

Speaker 2  (25:18)
I think it wasn't our first meeting. 

Speaker 1  (25:20)
Oh, probably. I forgot to maybe send him a message. Oh, yeah, yeah, that's why I that name was so so familiar to me. 

Speaker 1  (25:27)
I heard that so many times okay, that's fantastic final question. Yesterday we had that meeting in our lab to market, and they talked about the TRL. They talk about some kind of fundings. 

Speaker 1  (25:39)
I mean, I asked Randy about some kind of funding, and he mentioned the irap. So I also heard that from my industrial partner about the irap, and it's a very, very good funding part. The thing is that because he also tried to get fun from them. 

Speaker 1  (25:58)
But the problem that he had was, he didn't have any MVP. So right now, I'm working on the MVP, and rather than having the presentation at having the business model. I'm working on that platform. 

Speaker 1  (26:10)
Because I was already working on it for around the year 2I do have a website that platform is right now is just a website that you can just go on it and see what's going on is still on the work. I mean, I have to make it online, but do you think is that a good time right now to maybe contact irap to say that okay, do you have any funding for me? The reason I'm saying that Duane is that before the lab to markets, I was just casually working on this idea. 

Speaker 1  (26:40)
After that, because when you talk with so many people, especially with big names like deloitte, and people from the navy Irving shipbuilding, and so many ideas you get encouraged. So, this encourage means that you have to put so much time right now. I mean, I'm setting up meetings at 10:12 in the night. 

Speaker 1  (26:59)
So I'm just bombarding with emails. I'm sending I'm getting back so it is crazy. I mean, somehow I'm isolated from my own work, which supposed to be my PhD. 

Speaker 1  (27:10)
And I'm putting almost most of the time on it either on this one or just working on the laptop market, things probably in the future if I would like to do that. I need a source. I need the money and obviously this money should come from somewhere from somewhere that they are helping me. 

Speaker 1  (27:28)
I mean, my tax money was good but you know, it wasn't very. It wasn't that bad. I mean, it was also like a laptop market. 

Speaker 1  (27:38)
It was laptop market is also from icax, but I really need to good money and I need a team. Because yesterday we were talking about mvt. I mean, minimum viable team. 

Speaker 1  (27:48)
I need to have someone to focus on this part. Focus on this part. Focus on that part. 

Speaker 1  (27:53)
I mean only me. I mean, my industrial partner is supportive, but obviously he also has other things to do so it would be just me and me. I need to gather up the team and having a team needs money. 

Speaker 1  (28:05)
So do you think just I wrap can help me on this matter. Giving new sub budget. 

Speaker 2  (28:10)
Yeah, so My advice is I cannot say for certain if if I rap is has funding for you or not. They do have funding available, but depending on where you are on their T. RL level right? 

Speaker 2  (28:24)
But I do recommend having the conversation because All that that funding along with the other funding sources out there like coa, like, you know, my text and whoever else they all know each other. And they're all there to help entrepreneurs. Go so. 

Speaker 2  (28:49)
There's 2 elements of that. Is that talking to them? Early helps you set up for success on your application multiplying for funding. 

Speaker 2  (29:00)
Because having that discovery meeting with you, they can say for certain if your product is even if I rap is the source that you're going to, they will be able to assess it out as like, okay. Yes But you need XY and Z in your application, you know could be, you know, you know, just as salon like your project plan and all that kind of stuff say they will help you prior to actually you sitting down and writing an application submitting it and then talking afterwards they will help you construct what will be a successful application so that's having these discovery talks will help you. 

Speaker 2  (29:41)
So that's a they will help you make sure that you're built for success on your application. The other part is that because all these funding agencies know each other and have a good understanding of where they fit in that value chain along their terror level, they may be able to state like you're not quite ready for Iraq yet. But you should go talk to ABC over here and they'll actually connect you. 

Speaker 2  (30:14)
Okay, good on Neil. Right? So it is these discovery chats with the different funding. 

Speaker 2  (30:19)
Agencies are great like I said to help you be a successful applicant, but also point you to the right application. 

Speaker 1  (30:28)
Perfect. So you mean that right now? I because I was just checking their website today. 

Speaker 1  (30:32)
I mean, I was trying to discover what I do they need right now, so do you think right now? I should find someone from the Ira app. Just contact with them and some kind of talk about my idea. 

Speaker 1  (30:43)
Very big picture set a meeting to maybe to show you. 

Speaker 2  (30:47)
It's not a meeting. There's just like, look, this is just discover meeting I'm at, you know, I'm really close to this working on this. I got this idea really close to ndp. 

Speaker 2  (31:00)
I like to sit down to talk about. Irap funding and whether it applies, that's their business. Their business is to talk to entrepreneurs. 

Speaker 2  (31:10)
To do this and they will take you on, you know, if you contact a local rent. Because they have them all over the regions. You could probably get a face-to-face with them and have a good good chat like I said, it's this discovery chat, right? 

Speaker 2  (31:29)
It's a discovery, you know, to make sure that you are yourself are ready to apply. And if that Finding is the 

Speaker 1  (31:40)
Yeah, make sense. And about 1 minute, okay. One last question sorry, I forgot about that. 

Speaker 1  (31:45)
So about this funding part I was also talking with talis, so tell us is apparently they're working on the navy side, and they also support these ideas. The last time I had to talk the guy on the other side. He liked it and he offered me a funding. 

Speaker 1  (32:04)
He didn't specifically mention what was the fund, but it was just talk about how much they can provide at this moment. Do you think also going straight to navy or defense right now and asking them about their funding opportunities is It's a good thing right now. Or no I have to talk with Ira app first to see what they do, and then go to the maybe defense. 

Speaker 2  (32:30)
It's not. It's the way you approach them. It's not about I'm approaching you. 

Speaker 2  (32:35)
So you can pay my bills. I'm approaching you because I have a solution for you. Okay, right, so you know like I said, I gave you the advance. 

Speaker 2  (32:46)
Manufacturing. This is what the defense want. All right. 

Speaker 2  (32:50)
So in your discussion. Yes, you can state that your early stage. But like word like how can we work together? 

Speaker 2  (33:00)
Remember partnerships collaboration. These are key going with your open hand is like, can I have some money to develop my MBA? You're not selling yourself. 

Speaker 1  (33:11)
Hi, exact excellence. 

Speaker 2  (33:13)
Right, go longs like, look. We know that advanced manufacturing is key to the advance in blah, blah blah, like the wording I just gave you, and you know, we're looking at, how can we work together to validate and prototype this thing for talis, you know Gentlemen, so it's using that collaboration partnership. On a language that you're both on that you're both going to be on this journey together, right? 

Speaker 2  (33:50)
And that will help Because you're trying to find that win. Win right like, don't you know going from one ugh asking for money so that I can get an MVP, that's not what we want. We want to let's work together. 

Speaker 2  (34:08)
So that I have a solution that's built for you. 

Speaker 1  (34:12)
Excess, that was fantastic. Thank you very much. I mean the 30 minutes since then. 

Speaker 1  (34:18)
Any final advice for me, what should I do at this stage? 

Speaker 2  (34:21)
No, I saw. I saw some of your stats there. You're knocking out in the park when it comes to your interviews and everything like that. 

Speaker 2  (34:27)
So keep up the good work, you know, just like I said, keep on looking for those 3 elements that you need in your additional warehouse. You gotta have the designers, you gotta have. The builders and you gotta have the bar. 

Speaker 2  (34:41)
So, having conversations with all 3 of those and provide the more on those 3 levels, the more information you'll have on having a successful product. 

Speaker 1  (34:52)
Plasma keyboard. Yeah, fantastic. Thank you very much. 

Speaker 1  (34:54)
Thank you for going some great weekend. 
