
Speaker 1  (00:00)
It's a program perspective. We still have about 35 left to go, so there certainly is time for you to catch up. And achieve that one under interview target that we've been setting out for you. 

Speaker 1  (00:14)
It's important to do that. Because that's your primary data in terms of being able to say something sensible about whether you actually have a viable startup or not. So Keep driving forward getting that data. 

Speaker 1  (00:27)
So again we'll look at your business model, particularly those aspects of feasibility. This week. I throw up this image as kind of an analogy we're starting to look out. 

Speaker 1  (00:42)
Beyond your current horizon, which is customer discovery. And validating that problem exists that your closest horizon. But as I've said before, always good to keep a weather eye on kind of a broader horizon, or maybe over the horizon. 

Speaker 1  (00:55)
So I've thrown this in as a kind of a play on activating, or over the horizon radar, a technology which I might say, is Canadian. Canada is a leader in largely through the work of a company called northern radar, here in Newfoundland and working on this technology, for well for sensing out beyond the horizon, using radar technology and has become quite in vogue in recent months, with the interest in Arctic sovereignty and all sorts of things. So So in looking at feasibility, I would remind you that we are stepping out and looking beyond your current horizon, but I think it's worthwhile for you to be engaging this on understanding what's coming, so you can anticipate sort of what you do beyond your customer recovery activities that we have, you in great engaged in We've looked at the business model canvas in the past. 

Speaker 1  (01:51)
It's organized in 9 blocks, which we have subsequently subdivided into 3 larger blocks, one focusing on what we call desirability. Should I do this? Does anybody want this? 

Speaker 1  (02:05)
And that's largely centered around your value, proposition and your customer segments and their problems, and how you engage with them. Once you've determined desirability, does anybody want this then? As we say we step over and start looking at feasibility, can I deliver on this? 

Speaker 1  (02:21)
And then the final piece that we'll get to, in another couple of weeks, time is the business vital? Does the income meet the expenses on? Why go lose my shirt so again? 

Speaker 1  (02:31)
We're focusing this week on the blue part of your business model canvas. We can also look at the business model canvass into halves if you want. The right hand is all external. 

Speaker 1  (02:46)
It's all of all your customers channels, relationships and revenue or money coming in. Based on the value of your product or service that comes with, as we've said before, lots of wonderful market risk and worry that every entrepreneur has as well as looking at it from the customer's perspective of you know, is this something that I would want to buy. For the price that you're selling for ideally, the answer to that question would be yes. 

Speaker 1  (03:20)
When we look at the left hand side of the business model canvas organize this way, then it's all about the internal parts of your business dealing with again, as we've said key activities, key resources, key partnerships that you need to succeed in delivering on the promise that you have made to your customers in terms. Of the value or service that you're going to provide in exchange for money. And here we get, yes more respiratory vote this time. 

Speaker 1  (03:50)
It's all about product and execution risk. And I actually do what I said that I was going to do. That's the risk of being able to make the product and deliver it to your customer in a way that is, profitable is okay to have a billion dollar company. 

Speaker 1  (04:08)
But if your expenses are 1.2 billion and you're losing money. So can you deliver on your promise in a way that's profitable? And in short that amounts to the feasibility of your business model. 

Speaker 1  (04:25)
There's a there's an arc to this, as we've been showing you all along you started at point 0 with a hunch on a problem. It was certainly a research problem for your perspective. Is it a customer problem? 

Speaker 1  (04:39)
We now have you at Step 1 which is gaining insights into the problem. Doing your customer outreach, so I'm Well, your first step was to develop your hypotheses about your target customers. And then the next step in that process was to engage with them to provide defined this problem solution. 

Speaker 1  (04:57)
Fit You're probably still I know some many in my group are although starting to get clearer. Now still struggling a little bit with problem language fit. When you talk to a particularly a new interviewee, are you talking the same language that they are had one incident this week? 

Speaker 1  (05:18)
Where one of my teams was saying, oh, I'm having trouble getting people to respond to me because I'm reaching out to them. And I'm telling them I'm PhD researcher, and I'd like to get insights on my research, which we corrected quite quickly. Because when people read that they say, well, what the heck would I know about your research, of course, no one point me talking to you. 

Speaker 1  (05:37)
So, I'll say no, but as you all know or should know by now you're not looking for them to help you validate your research. You're looking to them for insights into the field in which they were working in the customer segment that you're targeting on. So that's really about communicating and really about finding that common language fit simple word like, you know, validating my research can throw them all off because they're saying, well, here, I am working in the field of aquaculture or carbon sequestration. 

Speaker 1  (06:06)
I'm not doing research. So be careful with your messaging. Coming down the pipe, which is what we're going to talk about today is in step 2, is finding that problem solution fit. 

Speaker 1  (06:19)
So you're starting to verge on what we call the minimum fiber product. And I'll explain that in a couple of minutes. Once you're speaking, the same language, you can begin to define and to describe a solution that your customers can understand so, you know, we talked early on about, you know, your people saying, well, what about my technology? 

Speaker 1  (06:39)
How you know can I talk to them about my technology? And our response, no talk to them about their problem. But you will arrive at a point in your dialogue with these folks that you will begin to start bringing your technology, your solution. 

Speaker 1  (06:52)
Back into the discussion, but your solution is going to be tempered by what you've learned about their problems and how best to solve those problems. Think back to the late bulb in the room example that Carol gave, you know, it seemed like a pretty straightforward problem until you thought about it for a few minutes and said, well, there's a bunch of stuff here. I don't understand if I'm going to offer a solution. 

Speaker 1  (07:14)
I need to understand a bit more about this problem. And that was the point to that exercise. So we know that you know, moving towards a product or a solution and finding product market fit. 

Speaker 1  (07:29)
It's not just about the idea, it's not just about a design or a topology. It's actually about an assigned solution that fits with the customer problem, and that may acquire some tweaking to what you developed thus far in the lab. So when ideas are enough, but a feasible idea, well, that's called that's next level. 

Speaker 1  (07:56)
So we want to be able to test an experiment to see if an idea is, in fact, feasible before we go too far down the path to core, which commercialization once you get to that stage. So again, I mentioned the key activities means figuring out three things. 3 feasibility is about targeting three things, key activities, key resources and key Partners, and we're going to follow. 

Speaker 1  (08:21)
We're going to focus on some generalities around those as I said before, but it's up to you to figure out the pertinent details that are relevant to your startup, because it's always going to be different. So starting with key activities, these are the things that you must do to make your business work, E things that you cannot. You absolutely cannot trust others to do. 

Speaker 1  (08:46)
You need to be hands-on with your key activities and I'm going to focus on just 2 of those there are others, but for the sake of demonstrating or illustrating I'll focus on 21 being your minimum liable product I mentioned earlier and one being sort of the overall product development. Effort which you will eventually get to if you've got a successful startup. So middle of our product by definition is not necessarily a working prototype or product of any sort. 

Speaker 1  (09:22)
It's basically anything that can be used to get your customers to learn about your product or your service. And how it might benefit them? It allows for you to get customer feedback on that minimum viable product that version one. 

Speaker 1  (09:42)
If you will, and again we're stepping into the future. Here we're stepping beyond customer discovery into customer validation, but just so you're aware this is coming down the pipes. And gives you more feedback on, you know, on how they respond to that product. 

Speaker 1  (10:01)
Does it provide the features that they need the basic set of features that they need and allows you then to iterate on your product and design something or deliver something that's more to their needs. Remember again, this is something you're going to do. Tackle, after you validate that a problem exists and have established that level of dialogue that language problem fit with the stakeholders, you've been talking to some examples of mvps can be as simple as a PowerPoint presentation can constitute an mbp. 

Speaker 1  (10:40)
You don't actually have to physically build something, but you can illustrate with cartoons or whatever what your something might look at. It can be a set of images or a video or something on on the website, perhaps with some background and text to back that up again, it doesn't need to be something physically in the lab that you need to hand to them. And then take hold because they can hold, or you can If you're if you're at that point, you can actually do a mock up or a prototype, some kind of proof of concept that you can show to your customers, and you'll eventually get to that stage. 

Speaker 1  (11:16)
Obviously every iteration of your MVP becomes increasingly more sophisticated as you learn more from your customers. So as you get into this process of customer validation and actually sort of having gone through customer discovery, understanding what their problem is and how they speak about their problems, and their job then you offer that solution says, well, what do you think about this that becomes then customer validation. They then provide you with some feedback on that. 

Speaker 1  (11:45)
And you are in a safe environment because you're both speaking the same language and both working towards the same end, which is solving their problem. Important to remember that you're In VP. It is not a market ready product. 

Speaker 1  (12:10)
Its product version one. That's good enough for your early adopter. So just good enough, it doesn't need to have all the bells and whistles, just yet just the basic functionality that satisfies your early adopters. 

Speaker 1  (12:26)
Those innovators early adopters that you've been working with your targeting those people you're trying to find in this burgers, customer discovery, and the key point is that these folks are willing to take the risk to buy a new untested solution from an unknown startup. This is why you established a relationship with them. Your building trust, they know you're small. 

Speaker 1  (12:47)
They know you're new. They know there's a risk that you might go out of business if you don't get over the chasm as we talked about before. But they're still willing to take a chance on you because they've had those interesting discussions, they know you to be intelligent and thoughtful and knowledgeable. 

Speaker 1  (13:04)
In the area that's relevant to their problem. And so they're willing to give it a go, give it a try with you. MVP development like product development, overall kind of follows these steps. 

Speaker 1  (13:22)
Starting with the idea. Obviously and then building your MVP. Based on your validated hypotheses that you've again through customer discovery, then as I say, the next step of that is then getting into Engaging with your customers and your MVP. 

Speaker 1  (13:43)
So you can start collecting their feedback again. We're starting again into customer validation. Here all part of customer development. 

Speaker 1  (13:50)
If you think back to early workshops, there's 4 steps in customer development. Customer validation. This is the next step once you've gone through customer discovery. 

Speaker 1  (14:03)
Uh The customer discovery process just to clarify, is basically clarifying the I understand you and your problem and the language you use to describe your problem, whereas customer validation getting into developing your MVP is. If I built one like this, would you buy it? So it's a very different conversation, but it's grounded in that early conversation where you started to understand what language they use, and what problems that they have. 

Speaker 1  (14:36)
You can do this with customers you already interviewed. In fact, likely you will go back to these people. You've already established relationship within a conversation with and say, look, you know, it took your suggestions onboard and I developed this MVP, and what do you think about this? 

Speaker 1  (14:52)
It's the logical kind of path to be following you, then use their feedback during that process to learn and to iterate and fine-tune your MVP, and then you do that process again, until you get to a point where you get a market ready, MVP. The characteristics of which are the smallest set of features again. You're not trying to build something that's got all the bells and whistles not trying to anticipate what the market might want in a few years. 

Speaker 1  (15:19)
Smallest set of features works as a standalone product does indeed anything else hung off the side of it in order to make it work. Solves the core problem that you've been working with. These folks on defining and understanding demonstrates your product's value product or service and key point that they're actually going to be willing to pay for and as we said before, sometimes your innovators don't have a budget, they're still very interested, very keen small number of them. 

Speaker 1  (15:52)
But they typically don't have a budget, whereas your early adopters may have a budget in order to be able to help you with a pilot project to help bench test or field test or your technology. So the key part here with the market ready on VP. It's something you can actually sell to an early adopter and have them triumph, and they're going to be willing to pay for it. 

Speaker 1  (16:14)
I'll give you an example from my past life. When I was the director of the center for plight ocean technology at the marine institute, we developed an autonomous surface vehicle. Which was a real life MDP proof of concept if you will, based on discussions with offshore operators, one of the problems that they had was understanding icebergs, which are a menace to offshore oil and gas development on the East Coast of Canada. 

Speaker 1  (16:45)
So the oil and gas industry is particularly interested in icebergs and in particular data that they don't have. One is melt data. How quickly are these things melting into ice cubes that we no longer longer need to worry about? 

Speaker 1  (17:00)
And the other thing is that don't really understand the underwater shape of these beasts, which, as we all know, icebergs, are 9 sort of underwater. So we talk to them about using an autonomous surface vehicle. This was about 10:12 years ago. 

Speaker 1  (17:15)
Now, when autonomy was just sort of in its ascendancy, we said, could we use we wonder autonomous surface vehicle to take water sample measurements in close to icebergs, and could we also fit that autonomous service? Vehicle with a sensor with a sonar that we could use to map the underwater shape of the iceberg. So as you can see from this diagram, we rough the MVP out using the cheapest possible materials and methods, we use basically plywood that we fiberglassed you coated with fiberglass and basically some aluminum tubing and standard sort of hatch covers. 

Speaker 1  (17:55)
There was nothing fancy about this proof of concept. It was entirely a minimum viable product to kind of demonstrate the concept to our client. The initial goal was to test the seakeeping capabilities. 

Speaker 1  (18:10)
So we put the tubes, the outriggers on tubes that we could sort of adjust in and out to see whether that would make any difference in terms of seakeeping in certain sea states. While I was there, we got to the stage of field testing the MVP. I used to use this photo quite regularly with my team to kind of chide them and ask them, do you not understand what autonomous means? 

Speaker 1  (18:40)
I count seven people, not including myself as the photographer involved in this autonomous sea trial. Shortly after this, I left the marine institute. And unfortunately, the new director that came in had other priorities and did not continue with the development of this particular product which I regretted. 

Speaker 1  (19:01)
But I wasn't there anymore, but given where things have happened in the autonomy, the world of autonomy. Airborne and sea drones, I think we were really on the right track here and could have done quite well with this. I will point out that one of the things that an MVP helped you to do is to test for specific design elements. 

Speaker 1  (19:25)
And in this case, we basically used a standard kind of bolt trailer to launch and retrieve this vehicle. What we found the first time we put it in the water, the image on the left. You'll see, there's black. 

Speaker 1  (19:46)
If you can see my cursor but there's black bugs on either side of the hall of the main Hull of the craft, which, when we put into the water, these bunks flipped over. And so when we brought the vehicle back onto the trailer, which is underwater, and then you pulled the trailer out of the water, we realized that the bunks had flipped over and the vehicle had settled onto the bracket underneath the punctured to hold the vehicle. So that took a little bit of redesign and a bit of repair, but it was just an example of how sometimes these mvps can be used to sort of test out various aspects of your product or service. 

Speaker 1  (20:26)
So that's just an example from my past, that kind of demonstrates What kind of path you can be following in terms of building and testing your mbb? The other thing I mentioned is a key activity for you one of those things that you must do. You can't kind of farm up to anyone else is the whole process of product development which Many of you are sort of partly into that process. 

Speaker 1  (20:55)
Anyway, you're on the early stages of that, in terms of technology development. It's basically a complete process that does everything that needs to bring your product to market. Of you, we'll be familiar with this technology, readiness scale. 

Speaker 1  (21:18)
It's kind of a good way to decide sort of where you're going to make the transition from technology development to product development, something you're going to actually take to market. And as it turns out, the business case, which is what you're working on now is typically around TRL. 5 or 56 in that range. 

Speaker 1  (21:43)
Before that is a bit too early in terms of defining bringing something to market that people might want sometimes all you've got is a topology or design. And that's not quite enough when you get up to 4 or 56 in terms of the TRL scale. You're starting to get into something that actually is responding to a business case. 

Speaker 1  (22:04)
And from that point forward, it becomes an exercise in product design and development rather than technology, design and development. Another look at framework for product development. Considering it from a number of perspectives again, as you know where all the perspectives here one we still keep in the technology development is still going to be part of your remit going forward. 

Speaker 1  (22:36)
As a company right now, you're kind of at phase 0 proof of concept, maybe into phase one for some of you, you may have eaten that to a point where you're filing your IP. I don't From a product development perspective, we've talked about proof of concept which is your MVP, then moving into an engineered prototype validating your alpha version. Doing some iterations getting to beta etc. 

Speaker 1  (23:07)
Et. Cetera, the blue line, some of you are already starting to see the relevance of this, in your own startup. The added a manufacturing folks in particular I know are started seeing that regulation and certification are a big part of what they are going to need to do in order to bring a product to market. 

Speaker 1  (23:28)
So that's in their, it starts a little later in the process, but it continues on through, and quite often if you're in a field where you're dealing with something that is regulated, you are going to be the one that needs to be able to demonstrate that it meets the regulations, or can be certified onto the certifying body that your clients are working under so a key part of this, and then there's the whole manufacturing process, which obviously you're not anywhere close to yet. But it's in a whole other sort of cattle efficient terms of what you need to do in order to build and a product and package it and have it market ready, not something that a lot of you are familiar with, but there are people there were, anyway, I'm thinking guys like, Andy Fisher. 

Speaker 1  (24:16)
At mun used to be sort of face and eyes into this whole manufacturing field. He's still around still a good guy to talk to. If you ever get to a stage where up Where you're thinking okay, I need to start manufacturing something here. 

Speaker 1  (24:30)
How do I go about that? So Things to think about that brings us through to the end of key activities, or at least limited perspective on some of the key activities that you're going to need to think about from your startup's perspective. Do I have any questions on that so far? 

Speaker 1  (24:56)
And again, I will remind you that the MVP and product development are just kind of 2 key activities that you're going to be involved in as an entrepreneur with your own business. But just by way of illustrating No questions, okay, I will move on to key resources. So key resources go hand in hand seems logical with your key activities. 

Speaker 1  (25:20)
Once you've defined what your key activities are or what are the key resources that you're going to need in order to execute those key activities. They're the most important assets Required to make your business work. They are the ones that you need to deliver on your key activities and note. 

Speaker 1  (25:44)
I've undergone a underlined need. Not want not would like not would be nice to have need always focusing on as your starting your business. So keeping all that stuff to the bare minimum, to get to a place where you're delivering something to your customers. 

Speaker 1  (26:09)
Don't load up your costs. Front end with a whole bunch of stuff that you in the ultimate day end of the day. Don't need keep everything right down to a minimum. 

Speaker 1  (26:19)
We typically think of key resources. In 4 categories and Leo went over these with you way back in foundations. So you've seen this before intellectual property, which is what you brought into the program background intellectual property foreground. 

Speaker 1  (26:36)
Intellectual property, as well as the intellectual property. As I've pointed out to a number of times that you're gathering during your customer discovery, building up your understanding of your customer needs, building up your understanding of your ecosystem. That big picture look, that's part of your IP. 

Speaker 1  (26:55)
Human resources and how you attract the right people to your startup. At the right time is a key resource. There will be physical resources. 

Speaker 1  (27:08)
Anything simple as just an office to workout of in a computer. Or maybe there's machinery, maybe there's AA A clean lab you might need from part of your testing and manufacturing. I don't know, maybe you need ships in order to be able to test some of your technology depending what space you're in. 

Speaker 1  (27:29)
So these can be quite far-ranging in terms of what they are. But again, limiting it to those things that you need recently worked with an environmental DNA company in St. Jones, who said, I think we need our own bolt to go and go sampling and they brought me into sort of council M on what's entailed in getting a boat, which is for those of you who don't know. 

Speaker 1  (27:55)
It's a significant sort of commitment to be able to buy and run a boat, and at the end of the day they figured out, no, we don't, you don't need to own a boat. We can charge our votes when we want to do our data collection. So that was an eye-opening exercise for them. 

Speaker 1  (28:12)
The last thing, of course And some of your own need, really throughout is financial resources. You know, obviously to be able to acquire all these things. Among all of those, human resources can be as we're learning, humans are complicated. 

Speaker 1  (28:32)
Beings so they can be the most important, but they can also be the most challenging. And one of our mentors from last year actually spoke in terms of what he called a minimum viable team. Which was to communicate the notion that, you know, like you need to be keeping your minimum viable product to just the minimum features you need. 

Speaker 1  (28:52)
You need to keep your team to just the minimum people you need on your team. So I want to dig into human resources just a little bit just to give you some guidance on that. Because that's maybe one of the areas where you're going to start looking first. 

Speaker 1  (29:07)
You know, I need to hire some people to help me sort of deliver on this as I start my company. There are different roles, different types of human resources that are going to play a role in your startup founders that you and your team, your Tl, to a certain extent, your mentor if you decide to give them a more formal role in your company, typically what happens with those is that they will hold a share in the company so they initially won't take any money out of the company. But they will hold a share of the value of company that they can redeem at a future time. 

Speaker 1  (29:49)
Employees, excuse me. Are hired to do a job on an ongoing basis? They can receive a salary. 

Speaker 1  (30:03)
Which you would all be familiar within terms of you know, the dynamics of that they can also be offered some equity, some shares some non-cash pay stock options, performance, shares those sorts of things. So keep that in mind when you're engaging with folks, you think you might want to bring onto their team onto your team, are they the kind of folks who just, you know, just give me my paycheck and I'll go home at the end of the day or do they have a more deep-seated interest. In the company, I'm willing to put in some of my time in return. 

Speaker 1  (30:39)
For maybe a lower pay, and some kind of stock options. As an alternative, those are great folks to have onboard. Because they are verging on sort of having as much faith in the company as you are. 

Speaker 1  (30:55)
By then there are a whole variety of independent contractors, consultants, if you wills that are basically contracted to do specific jobs. You may find, as you get through, you're going to find things you say, no I don't have the time I don't have the skill in order to redo this particular thing. The sorts of things that Carol does in Joanna does, for example, for companies who may want to go and approach them and contract them to do those pieces of work for you at a certain point in time. 

Speaker 1  (31:30)
So different sorts of human resources. All of them will be vital to moving your company forward. But will also represent a cost to you. 

Speaker 1  (31:42)
In some way, shape or form If you go back to your product development framework that we showed before and lay those resources out across the bottom, it shows that you're typically sort of front end loaded with ideas and back end loaded with money. You can typically and a lot do, and this is one of the areas which is which it varies depending on your personal situation. You can boost strap your startup through phases. 

Speaker 1  (32:13)
1 and 2 of product development With support, and I'll talk about this. We talk about revenues. There are supports available through government agencies. 

Speaker 1  (32:23)
You're enjoying one now through my tax to support you. In this program, there are other programs that are designed to help startups move along the path towards being big profitable companies. So sometimes you leverage that up front, sometimes your early adopters will have a few bucks to put into a pilot project and also some of you are at that stage already. 

Speaker 1  (32:46)
Sometimes your family and friends might believe you in you enough. To put up a few dollars up front to help get you to the next stage. As you get closer to product launch, however, you're going to get into a situation where the form of investment is going to become an overriding agreement. 

Speaker 1  (33:05)
And you're going to be looking for institutional investors, Angels or venture funds, or all sorts of things, which is a whole other game, and can be an obstacle when you look at crossing the chasm back to that curve. Through the aspect, every more something to think about The final topic for me around the whole time. Subject of feasibility is partnerships. 

Speaker 1  (33:34)
This is one that's near and dear to my heart. I've mentioned to you an earlier ones. I got bit hard in my first startup by entering into a partnership which didn't quite workout. 

Speaker 1  (33:44)
As I had planned, and so it was a hard lesson for me and one that I'd taken forward in the future, startups. Partners are in my definition, shareholders that are willing to share the risk Of helping you get your enterprise app and running to help make your business model work. They should also be in a position, and this is through some agreement with you to share in the rewards. 

Speaker 1  (34:12)
So that a shared risk shared rewards dynamic here, which is not just sort of a Lucy goosey handshake arrangement. There has to be mutual benefit. In the relationship to both parties, there have to be shared financial goals. 

Speaker 1  (34:30)
And you can be for-profit nonprofit whatever, but you have to share some financial goals as Partners as successful Partners, there may be an opportunity for code development or cointion, so there may be an aspect of your technology or product as service that you don't have the expertise for maybe you can partner with someone to provide that expertise and get delivering the full package of your customer. You may have customers in common with a partner. They may have customers already that you would be interested in selling to. 

Speaker 1  (35:02)
You might not be selling the same things to selling them to the same people. So those could be good Partners if they can share their customer list with you and the last but not least and this is one that I found has worked, or not worked depending on how you play It out, complementary expertise or experience is important. When looking a partner, if you're looking at a partner that has the same experience and the same expertise as you, then you're not really getting the most out of that partner. 

Speaker 1  (35:34)
The most value out of the partner ideally you want to be looking for someone who's expertise and experience is complementary to yours, not something you already have. Why do you need Partners? Typically, it's your, you know, recognizing you don't need to do everything on your own. 

Speaker 1  (35:56)
You need to do your key activities and have your key resources. But you don't need to do everything on your own for a certain company. For a certain startup and you should develop a fine-tuned sense of you know, these are things I need to do. 

Speaker 1  (36:10)
And these are things I don't need to be doing, maybe I can get a partner to do that. Sometimes that helps you get market faster gives you that extra horsepower to help you get to the market faster. Sometimes it allows you a broader product market offering. 

Speaker 1  (36:25)
So if you're able to bundle your product with maybe a product from your or add it to their suite of products and services gives you that broader offering for your product, maybe there's a more efficient use of capital by getting your partner to do certain parts of The product development, for example, or for them getting you to do some of the early stage rnd. Because you are sort of an early stage venture, maybe there's a more efficient use of capital there. That each of you shares in the benefits of Your Partners, or you may have some unique customer knowledge or expertise that you bring to the table. 

Speaker 1  (37:07)
Or they may offer access to new markets. Likewise, you may offer them access to new markets and I'm thinking in particular, I mentioned this before you're in the ocean space now, but your technology, your expertise may be applicable in other market segments. Can you apply that in other market segments for a partner or can a partner who's in another market segment come into ocean's market segment on the basis of a partnership with you. 

Speaker 1  (37:31)
So there's a whole bunch of different reasons that you can enter into these partnerships, but there needs to be that shared values and a willingness to share risks and share rewards beyond just a typical buyer seller relationship. If your contracting someone paying them to do a specific job. That's not a partnership, right? 

Speaker 1  (37:53)
I want to point out that Partnerships are formal arrangements. They're not some handshake type of an agreement. Everybody likes to talk partnerships, but they are formal agreements. 

Speaker 1  (38:08)
And this is why the topic of lawyers came up during our last mentor panel. Because people recognize that if you're in a partnership that's a formal agreement, and you agreed to certain Terms & Conditions with your partner. The reality check-in all of this is typically If you are an sme, if you're a startup You need Partners for the nay of U. 

Speaker 1  (38:39)
And just like customers, Partners can be more or less risk adverse. They may not want to collaborate with a new startup company with an unproven technology that may not be around in 6 months from now, they may look at you as a bit of a risk in that regard. And you'll need to calm them down a bit, assure them if you can This is the reason that partnerships between small startups and large companies often don't work. 

Speaker 1  (39:12)
Because they're holding most of the cards. It is certainly in terms of the depth of their bank account. And their ability to get things done. 

Speaker 1  (39:25)
It's not unheard of four startups to invest countless hours in developing relationships with a larger partner. I'm thinking in particular, things like oil and gas. You know, these big industry market segments, because typically what you're doing is you're developing a relationship with a person inside that company. 

Speaker 1  (39:46)
And that person leaves You could end up, you know, your partnership could end up falling off the table. Because the larger corporation doesn't have the same sort of commitment to that as that one individual had. So they may end up tend to walk away from that partnership, and there always are sort of escape clauses in every partnership agreement. 

Speaker 1  (40:11)
The upside in all this is that there is a tendency in the modern world for large corporations. Sometimes to engage with smaller startups like you more technically on the cutting-edge and more nimble in terms of being able to shift gears quickly. Sometimes that's their advantage to engage you as a partner to do some tech development. 

Speaker 1  (40:36)
Which you can do a lot more quickly than what they would do in hopes at a large organization. I mentioned my first startup earlier. A company called geomatics technologies incorporated doing airborne survey work for a variety of customer segments. 

Speaker 1  (40:54)
We partnered with a company called provincial airlines. They now have gone to the brand pal aerospace. They had to read the nice king air 200 twin-engine aircraft that allowed us to get offshore. 

Speaker 1  (41:08)
To look at opportunities, offshore with oil and gas industry, which was burgeoning at the time, and they also provided us with some cash actually to invest in an advanced hyperspectral sensing device that we put onboard to King air and develop applications for the startup, killing aspect of this partnership was and I mentioned it earlier, we had very different priorities. Uh, parental aerospace and gti in that So we would be looking for good weather conditions to be gathering airborne data. They would be looking for good weather conditions for doing other things for other people. 

Speaker 1  (41:57)
And typically, if a nice day, come open, I called and said, look, we need plane today and they would say, sorry, not available today. How about tomorrow? And I'd say, well, no, it's cloudy tomorrow. 

Speaker 1  (42:06)
I wish my weather window after that happened. Kind of a 1 a dozen times I started losing clients and eventually had to shut down the business. So learned an example there they were good Partners in terms of providing. 

Speaker 1  (42:18)
We thought we had the right ingredients. We were providing an application for the error frame. They were providing some financial and administrative support, but it was just the scheduling we had very different kind of scheduling priorities that ultimately, at the end of the day, the partnership didn't work. 

Speaker 1  (42:35)
So Hawson, something be cautious of so again. Some key things in terms of identifying those partnerships that might be usually beneficial to you and again you know, partnerships are agreements, formal agreements, not handshakes. So keep these, you know you're in your agreement, do you reflect? 

Speaker 1  (42:55)
Do you have the same values? Do you both agree have same values scheduling, which I mentioned earlier in my example? Can your partner move your speed and vice versa on you very. 

Speaker 1  (43:06)
Are you on very different timetables, intellectual property and you've been over this already? You've been counseled to go talk to your IP office at your institution. Get this squared array if you're going to do a partnership. 

Speaker 1  (43:18)
And you're going to be developing something in particular, who's doing what and who's going to own it at the end of the day, who's bringing what background IP to the project, what foreground IP is going to be developed as part of the project all needs to be laid out in your partnership agreement is the team stable on both sides. Typically, if you're talking to a larger company, they're probably more stable than you are. That's just a fact of the matter. 

Speaker 1  (43:44)
You're new and If you are relying on your partner or they are relying on you to do certain things as part of that partnership. Then, there must be accountability, and it must be clearly understood, kind of who's in charge of which tasks and which milestones in that framework. So again? 

Speaker 1  (44:04)
Partnerships is something that's easy to say. Difficult to do, but worthwhile. If you can find a good partner. 

Speaker 1  (44:12)
Any questions on any of that? Okay, yeah, go ahead, my blue 3R. 

Speaker 2  (44:23)
Okay, hey, thank you very much. He was very informative, so I believe when you were talking about mvt, you were talking about 2 of these opec. 

Speaker 3  (44:34)
I think Debbie had a question in the chat. 

Speaker 2  (44:37)
Oh, yeah, okay there we go on. Yeah, I thought it's okay good. Should I start? 

Speaker 2  (44:43)
It's okay. Thank you. So I was saying that, thank you very much. 

Speaker 2  (44:49)
He was so informative. I believe there are two things that keeps a group that leads mvt together. First of all, is a loyalty. 

Speaker 2  (44:56)
The second is money, so I do have some sort of a loyalty by myself. And maybe my partner industrial partner, but it's about the money. Because as working throughout this program as you just mentioned it's a full-time job and last night at 10 or 11I was sorting out 2 meetings, so I thought that it would be so devastating if I would like to continue this part so I need funds throughout this TRL. 

Speaker 2  (45:23)
You talked about from some kind of beginning to TRL. Number nine, can we have some support from some kind of the laptop market team to talk with different industries? I mean again rather than my obviously there should be other governmental funding as well. 

Speaker 2  (45:40)
Because recently, I was following the news and apparently Canada is investing huge on technologies and anything that comes from inside the Canada itself. So I really would like to move forward. But on another hand money matters. 

Speaker 2  (45:56)
So how we should do in that part? Yes, I agree the partnership and maybe finding investors is also good, but right now, I really would like to keep the technology by myself. So what is your suggestion random? 

Speaker 1  (46:12)
My goal is a good question. And I'm glad you're thinking about it seriously. You are right. 

Speaker 1  (46:18)
There are a lot of government programs out there now to help startups in all sectors really big focus on defense lately, but oceans is still big through the ocean startup project and the ocean supercluster. I did give you a link to an online newsletter. A couple of them actually 1001 startups. 

Speaker 1  (46:43)
And there's another one there. From a girl who runs, you know? A week or a monthly newsletter? 

Speaker 1  (46:51)
That contains a lot of the programs that are available out there. So basically it comes down to a matter of view, kind of doing your leg work asking gem and I asking Google, whatever, you know what funding programs are out there that are available to me at this particular stage or to do these particular things you'll invariably find one. Then, you'll need to go through the process of applying. 

Speaker 1  (47:14)
So there is a level of effort there to kind of apply for some of that funding. You may or may not be eligible depending on the stage that you're at. You've got a company established already. 

Speaker 1  (47:25)
That helps. There's usually a few kind of hoops to jump through, but yeah, there's a lot of public sector money out there to kind of support you through these first stages. There are a couple of steps forward in lab to market for sure. 

Speaker 1  (47:40)
You're going to be hearing about some of those during the last couple of days of the program. So we can hold off till land but in the meantime you can either speak directly with Carol, who's very familiar with this stuff or if you'd like to chat with me, I'm happy to do that as well to kind of help you navigate through that. But yeah, good question. 

Speaker 1  (48:02)
And there are resources out there. You just need to kind of put in the legwork to find them and apply for them and secure them. And then once you've secured them, then you cut the eye. 

Speaker 1  (48:13)
Anybody else? Was that Brenda's question as well or Debbie? 

Speaker 4  (48:22)
I had 

Speaker 1  (48:23)
All Debbie sorry I had every hand 

Speaker 4  (48:25)
Like my question is, have you seen partnerships? Come out of lap from our tip that the cohort itself 

Speaker 1  (48:32)
Partnerships come out of lab to market. I have not. There should be by keep encouraging teens to talk to each other. 

Speaker 1  (48:42)
You're doing similar kinds of things. I haven't seen any burri may be familiar familiar. She's tracking the teams more closely. 

Speaker 3  (48:50)
And we've had later stage locked market teams form partnerships through the osp, not this program specifically, but like alumni have gone on to form partnerships after the program. 

Speaker 4  (49:05)
Thank you. On the hind Andy, I have a logistics. Thank you for carefully what we should guide you during partnership. 

Speaker 4  (49:18)
As you mentioned like the time and scheduling, but beside that, like what is the thing that we should well do when we are thinking about partnership with someone 

Speaker 1  (49:32)
Do they bring something to the table that you do not have that you need? But do not have 

Speaker 4  (49:39)
Okay? But I guess that comes in areas right. Like the money or something? 

Speaker 1  (49:46)
Much money is something you do not have unless you're independently wealthy. And I'm not aware, but you have money, they could bring to the partnership, they could bring equipment, they could bring expertise, they could bring market access. Lots of lots of reasons you would look to partner with them. 

Speaker 1  (50:06)
But as I said, it was moving, these are generalities, so with regards to your own particular startup, you need to kind of look through that Lens. And again, I'm happy to spend some time with you to talk that through. If you want to reach out to me. 

Speaker 1  (50:23)
I know that Joanna and Karen Carroll would be as well. 

Speaker 4  (50:27)
Additional skills. 

Speaker 1  (50:29)
So All right. So let me just go through my last couple of slides, and I know Joanna is chomping at the bit to get at pitching. So for next week, I wanted you to give some thought to the key resources that you think your startup is going to need. 

Speaker 1  (50:44)
And again, just the minimum bare minimum resources that you're going to need to think to deliver on what your startup is doing. And also, as we've just talked about what would be your keys to your dream partner and why I've left key activities off this list. Because your key activity now is customer discovery. 

Speaker 1  (51:06)
Eventually, you'll get to a broader list of key activities, but for now we're going to keep you focused on customers covery. But thinking about down the road My key resources, are you going to need my key partnerships. Might you need to deliver on that? 

Speaker 1  (51:22)
So pretty straightforward just to add that to your Chrome presentation in your bm, so you just add it to kind of your thinking. So again, we're at the 45 interview mark should be my next week up to 60. I found this quote from Winston Churchill, which said it's no use saying we are doing our best. 

Speaker 1  (51:49)
You succeed by doing what is necessary. So when we sit down with you weekly and say, how's your interviews coming, we're doing our best. You all know kind of what needs to be done in order to succeed and you need to do. 

Speaker 1  (52:04)
What's what's need? There's all that I can say. Thank you all for your time. 

Speaker 1  (52:13)
I appreciate it and your good questions. And I'll pass things off to oh, we're going to have a bit of a break first I think 

Speaker 3  (52:20)
Yeah, I think we'll take just like a 10 minute break. And then we will come back for joenna's pigeon presentation. 

Speaker 1  (52:31)
Recording stopped at the timer on the go. 
