
Speaker 1  (00:00)
Session just in one go fairly close to the final. We call the time presentation. We decided to actually pull that pitching session apart a little bit and provide this information to you a little bit earlier, especially as you're thinking about. 

Speaker 1  (00:23)
And as we have the break coming up next week, and then March sort of like probably will disappear really quickly. And so we thought we'd actually split this up and start talking and present pitching to you in this first session, and then again in March, when we meet again. And the reason for that is that pitching is really, you know, it's a process of practice of preparation of just doing it over and over again. 

Speaker 1  (00:55)
And it's rarely, if ever that I've ever seen anybody, you know, have to pitch something and prepare the very first pitch they ever did, ended being the, you know, the pitch, that gets them the funding or the pitch that gets them the win and a pitch competition, or even the conversation with a potential customer. And so in this next 45 minutes because this will be only 45 minutes. I'll talk through, you know. 

Speaker 1  (01:23)
The biggest part of pitching, which is ultimately about telling a story right where you are telling the story about the startup and the technology. And the opportunity that we're building, and we're trying to get people onboard of our journey that we're on. And so that is, you know, pitching in a startup environment is really about telling that story about, you know, your business. 

Speaker 1  (01:48)
But more importantly about the future opportunity of that business. And why, whether you're an investor or whether you are, you know? Yes, you're maybe pitching in a pitch competition, but also you know, you could be presenting and sharing this deck, and your story with potential government funders like nrci wrap that funds a lot of innovation and rnd in Canada. 

Speaker 1  (02:13)
I guarantee you that one of the first things they look at is the pitch deck and have you walked them through it right to even debt fund. Like banks and creditors etc, you're going to be submitting this with the rest of your documentation, and certainly obviously like investors. If that's the path, you're going to go down. 

Speaker 1  (02:34)
But pitching is something in the startup environment if you're building a business that something, hopefully you'll get really familiar with and really comfortable with. And give it up when you first start. You might feel like, I know a lot of you felt like this too I think we had this memo actually at the very beginning. 

Speaker 1  (02:54)
You know, talking to just like random strangers in your customer discovery. Well, pitching sometimes is also pitching to strangers, right? You might be pitching to yes, investors and other funders and other folks, but you might not know any of those people right? 

Speaker 1  (03:13)
And so you are always going to be getting in front of new people trying to share with them your story, right? The story of your business and the work that you're doing and why it's really important and so fundamentally though the best pitches whether they're in a pitch competition, whether they're done to a group of investors or even in an elevator like right, the elevator pitch concept came out of that. That's the origin story of the pitch right is like you only had a minute or the elevator ride with a CEO or the owner of a fund, to be able to actually share your concept with that person in that elevator live at the moment. 

Speaker 1  (03:57)
And that was sort of the origin of the like elevator pitch, right? And it is really about communicating your story to this individual. This group of individuals and trying to get them excited about what it is you're doing, right And so there are a couple really important communication and strategies that we want all of you to think about. 

Speaker 1  (04:20)
As you are prepare and think about your pitch. And at the end of this 45 minutes, I'm going to talk about like, what your pitch should look like when we do that pitch at the end of lab to market in March. The first is of course, in a scenario where we have the opportunity to use a deck or visuals is showing an engaging your audience with visuals is so powerful right? 

Speaker 1  (04:47)
That saying that a picture is worth a 1000 words where it's true, right? It can actually get people excited and engaged and actually listening to what it is you're saying When you can show people, it's so powerful. You need to I know you're all and we'll have another session later on, but you're all in building technical products, right? 

Speaker 1  (05:13)
What's really important in communicating the potential of your business. And again, it's like the potential, not only of your technology, but the potential of your business is to move from really technical abstract language that most people won't understand to language and topics that are yes specific. But that are easier for people to comprehend that somebody that isn't technical could actually understand how this would work in their particular scenario, and so making sure that we are clear that we're effective, and that we're speaking to an audience that is not as technical as we are. 

Speaker 1  (05:51)
If technical at all You will talk about this over and over again. But knowing your audience is really important. So are you pitching a group of investors? 

Speaker 1  (06:04)
Are you pitching at a pitch competition? And the people that are judges are coming from universities. Are you pitching to a technical panel? 

Speaker 1  (06:12)
Are you pitching? You know, to a bank or you know, there's so many different groups you could be pitching to, you need to understand who it is that you are talking to, by that sheer knowledge, you're going to be able to adjust your pitch to that particular audience in terms of how you actually present the information. That you're sharing with them, and what it will be, whether that's like it called to action around investment or a call to action, to join you or to help you in some sort of way, you need to figure out how to hook this particular audience that's in front of you into your story. 

Speaker 1  (06:50)
And so this is why it's so important to know your audience, and sometimes it'll be difficult because you might not know everybody or who they are or where they're coming from, but it's really important to think about it as like what's the baseline of this audience. What's their baseline understanding and how can I get them excited about my pitch? Remembering that any good startup and any good founder or founding team will be pitching so many different times and will likely have variations of their pitch and their pitch deck depending on who they're talking to, right. 

Speaker 1  (07:27)
So as you think about your story about your business. And I know from talking to many of you, sometimes you're all really still you're stuck in your technology, and that's okay, because that's like where these ideas originated from you needed to really step out of that place. Right really step out of that place. 

Speaker 1  (07:48)
And think about how do we actually connect emotionally with my audience, how do I connect with these people, right? They're all humans. How do I connect with them about the work that I'm doing, and about what I'm building in a real human way? 

Speaker 1  (08:03)
How do we create a quality relationship with this individual whose group of individuals, right? Making sure that we're telling the story around the impact that this has on a consumer, and then ultimately, on this bigger sort of impact that we have in whether that's community or a different art industry or a type of business. And at the end of the day, you need to make your pitch and your story unique to you, to your startup to the solution that you're creating, and this is why we really, you know, give you all sometimes what feels like a really hard time about like, if you need to talk to your customers, you need to understand what their needs are so you can create something that's really unique to that audience so that you can have those early adopters, right? 

Speaker 1  (09:00)
But in order to do that, you need to have something that's unique. That's novel that can stand out and be competitive against. Whether that's the competition or just alternatives that potential consumers might be using. 

Speaker 1  (09:14)
So really thinking about that will help you. So as you start thinking about Pitching and again. I'll drive you back. 

Speaker 1  (09:26)
Be like you need to pitch not the tech. Although the tech technologies of course important you need to pitch the business. Right? 

Speaker 1  (09:35)
You're pitching the startup now. You're no longer just like pitching. The research or pitching that novel invention you're pitching the business. 

Speaker 1  (09:43)
Then, this is an important not even nuance. It's a big distinction, right? Businesses grow based on the business they might have technology. 

Speaker 1  (09:52)
They might have multiple technologies or opportunities. The technology itself is great important. It's got an IP, but it's not in and itself. 

Speaker 1  (10:02)
The business, right, so remembering that you need to again remember. That your audience might have 0 technical knowledge might have 0 experience in the sector that you or talking about, or that you're building in right? This is critical to remember, and it's sort of like from then on. 

Speaker 1  (10:27)
You can build a story that makes sense and can be easily digestible for people, right? And that's why this is always, like the first thing we talk about is, you need to really make it digestible. For people, you need to think about how to combine the micro and the macro. 

Speaker 1  (10:45)
If possible, right? This is a when we talk about the hook we need to have the audience or the audience members be able, and this is why we talk about like a singular experience. Because that's for a human. 

Speaker 1  (10:59)
It's like, oh yeah I have that experience that person that you're talking about in the deck or that business. Oh, I have that experience. It's easier for people to hook into that right? 

Speaker 1  (11:08)
But you also need to show that bigger business opportunity, the larger market. What does that look like for you? What's that roadmap that only doing one or the other will inevitably? 

Speaker 1  (11:22)
You'll miss a big part of either showing the opportunity and getting them excited about what's possible or you're not going to be able to hook them in that individual human experience, right? Again you need to show and tell You need to think about Not just the numbers, but what's the strategy here? Right in the work that you know, I do. 

Speaker 1  (11:52)
We talked to a lot of startups advise a lot of startups on the path of gaming investors gaining follow-on investors, etc, and Numbers, once you get to that stage, you've maybe got a fundraising round. Maybe you already have revenue as you get further into that journey. Those numbers become more and more critical. 

Speaker 1  (12:22)
Because you now have evidence saying, hey, you know, like, we've had like 700000 revenue last year. And that's up by 40% from the year before when you're early on, before you've raised your first round, when you don't have revenue yet, maybe you're not even in market yet. When you're in this very early stages, everyone that's in the audience, whether they're, especially if they're an investor or a funder will know that these numbers are really not based in your evidence in true evidence you haven't gone out and sold this product in market yet. 

Speaker 1  (12:55)
So you need to figure out about how do I actually share the story of like, how I'm going to enter this market. How I'm going to be competitive through the positioning that I have in the market, right so again in these early stages, when you're pre revenue, the numbers important, obviously from a research perspective. But it's more about strateg, he intact. 

Speaker 1  (13:18)
It And about sharing the vision for what you're trying to create with your business. So you also need to remember, and of course, in this environment of the lab to market, I'm sure everybody would agree you're like, in friendly waters here, right like we are here to support you. Typically, when you go out there and pitch in the real world, when you're pitching for funding, you're pitching in a pitch competition, you're pitching on dragon's debt. 

Speaker 1  (13:50)
And You know, pitching, you know, wherever there's competition. There are other people that you're being also evaluated against. So this is an important aspect of the experience to remember as well. 

Speaker 1  (14:08)
Is that when you get out of the real world, same as like. When you go out there and you know, are trying to apply for additional funding for your startup or get in front of like banks and creditors and others to support you. Remember that there are other startups, other founders that are doing this as well. 

Speaker 1  (14:29)
And so how can you actually stand out from everybody else and remembering that the competition is researching everything, right. They are the best of them. They've got it nailed down. 

Speaker 1  (14:46)
They know everybody, that's on a panel, they know all the guests, they know. The focus they know the room, they know how no pitch they might have pitched already a 100 different times and won a bunch of competitions. So how can you prepare even more? 

Speaker 1  (14:58)
So, you know, for this scenario. Remembering that strategy is critical, right, knowing why you're pitching for what and what the outcome of that ISIS just as important as like, doing the pitch we often see pitches that are like, I'm just pitching. And you're like, well, for what like what are you trying? 

Speaker 1  (15:22)
What are you trying to get out of the audience? It's great to get people excited. But are you trying to get support? 

Speaker 1  (15:26)
Are you trying to get funding? Are you trying to get introductions? Are you trying to get advisors? 

Speaker 1  (15:31)
There's many different sort of calls to action at the end of the pitch that don't just involve funding, right? There's lots of different ways that others can support you in your journey, and so it's remembering it's like how can you get people excited and engaged down-the-line in your work again, best. And this is why we wanted to start introducing this concept earlier on in lab to market is because preparation and practice like it's really important, right. 

Speaker 1  (16:04)
Just like you're doing in your customer interviews, the more you do it, the more comfortable you are, the better you're figuring out, like, oh, maybe these questions. Not appropriate and maybe I need to ask a different follow-on question. Will that same case applies to your pitch right? 

Speaker 1  (16:19)
The more you do it, the more you figure out, what's working, what's not working in your story. What's not working or what's working in your deck right? These working together is the story working with the deck and the visuals that you have. 

Speaker 1  (16:34)
Are you missing something really being able to also think about, like, you know, practicing with other people, whether they're colleagues in lab to market or like, just in your lab, you know, thinking about, like, okay, maybe I need to practice, what are objections that are coming my way or sort of feedback that I'm getting. Around this presentation will help you. Actually make the presentation of certain but your pitch better. 

Speaker 1  (17:01)
Remembering that every time you are pitching, your startup and in this kind of format, just like in the interview process in the customer discovery process, you're getting data points back, you're getting feedback back. To be positive, could it be neutral could be negative? It could be all sorts of things right? 

Speaker 1  (17:19)
It could be questions that you're getting, those all are indicators of how you can adjust your pitch to better, you know, be maybe more in fort a minute or more engaging etc in terms of actually getting the outcomes that you want to get out of that pitch. Again, we know at the early stages. You might not have all the evidence possible, right? 

Speaker 1  (17:45)
You're not on a market. You don't have revenue yet. You're not selling, but you have other. 

Speaker 1  (17:50)
You need to show that your numbers are not coming out of thin air, right? You know, just making them up. They're coming from research. 

Speaker 1  (17:57)
Maybe it's because you've done a 100 customer interviews. You know don't discount that we're like. Oh, good. 

Speaker 1  (18:04)
Okay, you've talked to. You've talked to lots of people, or you've talked to 200 people, whatever that number is, that is evidence that backs up your claims. And so this isn't just some number we came up with, right? 

Speaker 1  (18:15)
This actually makes a difference down-the-line too. Not just in the lab 2 market program. You want to? 

Speaker 1  (18:25)
Make sure that every pitch you make again has that like what I call like the call to action? What's the next thing that you want people to do after they see your pitch? They're gonna invest in. 

Speaker 1  (18:36)
You. Are they going to reach out to you because you're asking for advisors, are you asking for connections in a certain category or industry you can ask for lots of different things, right? But always make sure that you've got it clear. 

Speaker 1  (18:50)
Ask and plan for how to make things. Move things forward beyond the warm. Beyond the pitch itself You need to at the end of there You know? 

Speaker 1  (19:06)
You need to show up and how to best say this is like You need to show up for your pitch and for the company that you're building. If you're not enthusiastic. If you're not excited, then why would anybody else be right when you're pitching, whoever you're pitching, you need to show up with care with enthusiasm with curiosity for the work that you're doing, because you love the work you're doing right. 

Speaker 1  (19:39)
So and remember that everybody else, that's pitching, maybe in a competition, maybe to funders. A lot of The Times I'll tell you investors. Even funders are picking, you know, they're trying to pick what we call like the winners right? 

Speaker 1  (19:57)
And they know that somebody, that's enthusiastic about their tech. That's curious. That's always asking questions, it's taking on feedback. 

Speaker 1  (20:04)
Well, they're going to get a team around this product. They're going to get a team around this startup. They're going to continue figuring problems out as they continue as they continue building their technology. 

Speaker 1  (20:15)
As they continue building their startup, and that is something that people are looking for that. So the audience that's listening to pitches is looking for are you enthusiastic? Are you knowledgeable? 

Speaker 1  (20:28)
Are you open to feedback? Are you like just, you know out there? Trying to create the environment that would allow your company or your technology to grow Look. 

Speaker 1  (20:44)
If we don't expect you to become like the best storytellers in the world, we know that storytelling is really hard. And you don't need to come up with some like Wild creative, you know, story or novel, but you need to think about how can we actually simplify the complexity of our technology or the complexity of our research, or even the complexity of our startup, right? How can we tell this story in a way that people can engage with and understand and so this is where we really think about, like pitching. 

Speaker 1  (21:19)
As a bit of like a creative art and a science cause we know actually there are formulas for the things that we need to include, and when we start it all sort of feels like this again like you're like, whoa, I have never done this. This isn't like a school presentation. This isn't you know, a thesis presentation? 

Speaker 1  (21:41)
This is a pitch, it's something different that perhaps some of you have never done before. And it can feel very foreign and there are these elements that, you know, the audience is looking for in this pitch presentation that you might not be accustomed. 2 right at the end of the day pitching is really at the foundational level, about finding the right people to join your journey, you know, in this scenario in this visual, it's about finding you know, when you're pitching to investors, it's about finding the people that are going to give you the money that believe in you. 

Speaker 1  (22:17)
But it's also about finding their other right people, right? The supporters, the advisors, the people that are going to be your confidants. The people that are going to be connectors, they're going to introduce you to lots of different people. 

Speaker 1  (22:27)
So remembering that is going to be really key here, it's about finding the right people. And when we talk to investors And we work with companies to prepare them for pitching. This is specific to investors, but we'll help anybody pitching to any audience is really answering these 3 questions. 

Speaker 1  (22:46)
Because this is what investors are always looking at. Why are you? Why are you pitching me this startup? 

Speaker 1  (22:58)
At this time so thinking about like, why am I the person that should be or me or my team? Why are we the best people positioned to do this? Why this technology and why this startup? 

Speaker 1  (23:13)
Why is this the thing that's going to get people? You know, to disrupt an industry or create solutions in the world. And why is now the time to build this technology? 

Speaker 1  (23:24)
And this startup is the questions that we often see get thrown at founders or founding teams and sometimes founders get really like I don't. Yeah, you know why, you know? They might have a great pitch. 

Speaker 1  (23:38)
But they can't answer some of these questions. So just in the back of your head thinking about this, can I answer these questions? And can I ask, can I answer these through, you know, my story and for any of you if you've ever done any kind of You know, literature, training or creative writing, you might be familiar with, you know, the story arc, right? 

Speaker 1  (24:08)
Essentially, the story in 3 acts, and in act one, you're setting the story up right? You're introducing the protagonist, which in any pitch scenario. It's going to be like your startup is you're really the hero of this journey. 

Speaker 1  (24:28)
You are going to throw down the problem hook. That bend the dream you have. And what's standing in the way right like what's the problem? 

Speaker 1  (24:37)
If you don't have a problem, you don't have a story, right? You need to show us what is the problem that you're trying to solve. And why is that problem so important? 

Speaker 1  (24:50)
A lot of The Times that can be a really great entry point into answering those questions of why this and why now, because the problem is persistent and affects a large group of individuals or regions. And when we think about the story, arc It's the problem hook. And the definition of the problem is actually the first big aspect of your should be the first big aspect of your story. 

Speaker 1  (25:18)
Right? It's part of this setup of act. One. 

Speaker 1  (25:23)
Throughout act one you start introducing your solution. Because ultimately, like a problem with no solution is not really a compelling story, right? You need like you need the hero. 

Speaker 1  (25:37)
And so you need to really think about setting up your solution to this problem. So that we can we or the audience can really CU the startup or the founder as the hero here right? And then, as we dive into act, 2 You gotta tell us about the drama. 

Speaker 1  (25:57)
The drama of this problem that you've been talking about, right? You can talk about, like the challenges with solving this problem. You can talk about the trials and tribulations that you've had or with customer discovery, or that the customer continues to have. 

Speaker 1  (26:14)
And that could be ultimately getting in the way. Sorry that could be getting into the market. Chaos, right? 

Speaker 1  (26:21)
You start talking about, you know, what's happening in the market you can talk about competition, you can start talking about revenue models or potential revenue models. If you don't have This conflict or friction that we talk about in act 2. You don't necessarily have that drama, right? 

Speaker 1  (26:44)
You don't have an emotional connection. You need to figure out, how do we tell this? How do we get capped? 

Speaker 1  (26:52)
How do we get the audience captivated and a lot of this, and what we're creating and what we're doing, and so it isn't just about the problem. It isn't just about the solution or the technology you're building. It's also about what's happening out in the world, right? 

Speaker 1  (27:05)
It's the market, it's the competitors. It's the trends and pressures that are happening. That's making essentially the ideal scenario for you to enter and try to build a company that has huge market opportunity. 

Speaker 1  (27:20)
So then we dive into act 3, this is really the resolution of the story, and in the pitch we're thinking about this right. This is the description of like where you're at your results that you've had today the traction, you've had to date for you, this will be the traction, and the validation you've gotten through custom discovery in a later stage, if you're pitching, you've got revenue, you'll tell us about like, how much revenue growth you've had. Or you'll tell us about how many customers are signed up on your wait list, right? 

Speaker 1  (27:58)
There's lots of different ways to sort of talk about traction, that isn't just revenue in the resolution you're also going to tell us about, like, what's to come, what's the future look like. How do we actually get engaged? What's the vision that you're trying to create for the world? 

Speaker 1  (28:17)
And for the business and ultimately, for the world. So these are important aspects to think through Ok. I am gonna talk through. 

Speaker 1  (28:30)
We're not going to actually watch any of these videos. I'm gonna talk you through what I want you to do Uber the next essentially, two weeks till we meet next time. In this deck and of course we'll have this deck after this session in this deck. 

Speaker 1  (28:49)
There are a series of actual real pitches that founders have done these founders have been fairly successful in pitching their businesses, and they range from technical products to more consumer facing products. Your homework will be over the next two weeks. Aside from thinking about how you apply some of this to your own scenario is to think about You know what story telling techniques Maybe made this pitch engaging or memorable. 

Speaker 1  (29:23)
Was there something that really caught your eye? The second question, how did the founder actually build credibility? And then how did they connect with the audience that they were pitching with? 

Speaker 1  (29:37)
So you might not like know that outcome of this pitch, but perhaps you as part of the audience, you're like, oh that really got me, you know, maybe it was this personal story. They put in, or maybe it was this like really trying to write non-stop, and they had at the beginning of their deck. Think about what built credibility, and what built connection for the audience Then, I want you you know, to To think about, like, in the pitches that you'll see, and some of them you. 

Speaker 1  (30:11)
Now are going to see visuals per se because they're not necessarily visual, they're more about the people pitching live on stage. Think about what made this pitch successful? But in the context of clarity and being compelling and exciting, was it the structure? 

Speaker 1  (30:32)
Was it the delivery, was it the personal story? And so do I want you to to Take these questions in mind you in the deck. You'll see they're these all have links to the actual like videos online, so we have the odess pitch. 

Speaker 1  (30:53)
We also have cheekbone, beauty pitch. We got medmi pitch, and then we've got a smart suites. Kerabosh pitch, and you'll see a whole range like you'll see our whole range of variety in terms of types of pitching structure. 

Speaker 1  (31:13)
Obviously some of these founders are pitching and dragons dent. Some of them are pitching on stages. But it will start giving you ideas of how to do this. 

Speaker 1  (31:24)
Okay. Also, we know that when you pitch at the end of March, you're going to be pitching online, you're going to be pitching over zoom, which is obviously different than pitching on a stage or in front of the dragon's live right. So we know this, but there are ways to be able to structure your story structure. 

Speaker 1  (31:45)
Your decks in ways that could be really compelling. As So that's your homework. Those pitches thinking about these questions. 

Speaker 1  (31:56)
Okay? Then, as you start thinking about your own You know, pitching story and the story of your startup of your technology. You know, there are different ways to tell a story right? 

Speaker 1  (32:16)
Sometimes it's a personal story. So you tell them about the stories context is wrapped around your personal experience and your reason for doing this. For reason, for finding the solution, it could be something around And around the values that you hold, and that are the foundation of your company. 

Speaker 1  (32:41)
Maybe the stories are really built around community and collaboration. It's about how do we also become part of this story. Because it's important to us, too, and sometimes the story is about knowledge and education. 

Speaker 1  (32:59)
It's about like, hey, we're going to get you engaged. Did you know this problem affects this many people, or is this this size? And so there's lots of different ways to tell a story of a startup, I've seen it all from personal experience, oops to whoops, my gosh, my sorry, my My scroller has gone wild here. 

Speaker 1  (33:24)
There's lots of different ways to tell the story. It has to and should be unique to you. And your experience and the startup that you're building That's what people get excited about when story is unique. 

Speaker 1  (33:40)
It's personal in some shape or form again, doesn't have to be your personal backstory. It can be wrapped in community values. The information you hold lots of different ways to do that. 

Speaker 1  (33:51)
So I challenge you to be really To think deeply about how you can tell the story, not just of the science or the research, or the innovation, but the story of the startup, like what are you creating in the world that's going to be so special? And as we lead into our final pitch, which will be in March, that all of you will do. This is a bit of a formula for that final pitch. 

Speaker 1  (34:27)
The picture will be 10 minutes long. It will include here or take the 10 slides that you could choose to include. I mean, we've seen all sorts of things. 

Speaker 1  (34:38)
If you're able to convey this information in some other shape or form or like, hey, we're all ears. But this is the good formula to follow again. Sometimes you can sometimes I've seen founders sort of like mix things around. 

Speaker 1  (34:52)
That's up to you. But the 10 slides are really again. The problem, the customer, why? 

Speaker 1  (35:01)
Now, right, this is like Why is this the time to do this? The solution just like your tech and your startup. The market, so this is where we talk about, like target markets. 

Speaker 1  (35:14)
Sometimes, you know, founders will have the addressable market. They'll have sort of that nesting circle diagram, you know, the competition. Then, the model that you're trying to actually build here. 

Speaker 1  (35:28)
What is it that like? We know the product or service or the tech, but like what's the business model here that that's what people want to know how are you going to make this into sustainable business? And then you're going to talk through validation. 

Speaker 1  (35:41)
This is your traction, right this. In your case, is the customer interviews. It's maybe sign ups, it's in some later stage, it's revenue. 

Speaker 1  (35:50)
It's customers etc et cetera, right? And then towards the end, you sort of have that resolution, right? You talk about the roadmap and you talk about the team in the pitch scenario. 

Speaker 1  (36:02)
Unless you're wrapping your story around your own personal sort of reason for being here, typically, what we see is the team slides show up later on in the pit. All right, so layered on top of The final pitch in the story arc, it could look something like this, right Again, it isn't necessarily like prescriptive, but you must do it in this way this for those of you that are like I don't even know where to start yet, you've given me 10 slides, I don't even know what to put on those 10 slides, let alone how to frame. 

Speaker 1  (36:44)
It around the story. Well, this is a disturbing point, right? It's like thinking about it like in this sort of hear their story in a way that's meaningful to them. 

Speaker 1  (36:54)
And also aligns with their style and their personality and their business. Right like this is where we want you to also have a bit of like that personality. What's your business all about right, like? 

Speaker 1  (37:05)
What are the values that this business holds? So those are all in important considerations. As you start thinking about this again, you don't have to have this pitch ready for next week. 

Speaker 1  (37:14)
You've got when are we like you've got almost Like 5 and a 1 five weeks, let's say five weeks right to prepare those pitch. Trust us everybody before this cohort had like two weeks, so it was a lot to lay on in like to create on two weeks. We promised you like everybody got there and even in a 2 week period you have more time you have more time to start playing around with what this could look like for your particular startup. 

Speaker 1  (37:52)
And I will end on this slide and I'd love to see if you've got questions about the pitch. Can't see anybody so if you've got a question, please just like come off mute or put up your hand 

Speaker 2  (38:15)
Um, yeah, and then okay, John, can I start enough? Okay, perfect. Thank you very much. 

Speaker 2  (38:22)
I do have one comment. I do have one question the thing that you mentioned about the laptop market. One of the thing that I really like is that so far I reached out to around the 4 interviews and every time I kind of start a conversation, I said that hey, I'm from laptop market, I've did 4 interviews with different industries, and there's some kind of their eyes are going to pop. 

Speaker 2  (38:41)
Up and they're going to give you more knowledge. I like that one. My question is that by nature? 

Speaker 2  (38:50)
I'm a little bit, I cannot say extrovert. I'm energetic, and I remember at 1 point we had a competition about our PhD piece as a doubt. So I did a lot. 

Speaker 2  (39:01)
I mean by hand the gesture. I'm a little bit tall, so everybody would see me. And at the end of the day, one of the professors told me that why you can be normal. 

Speaker 2  (39:10)
Why you're just acting as the rock star? I mean, I really like that idea. But sometimes it is too much how we can understand that we are too excited or if we shoot some kind of calm down a little bit. 

Speaker 1  (39:27)
And I will. Well, first of all, okay unfortunate that somebody actually told you that I would say? I have never in my life. 

Speaker 1  (39:40)
I mean, Carolyn, Randy can add or maybe you can and Johnny. You've all seen lots of teams pitch listen in all my time in the world of startups which is close to 20 years now. I have never in my life. 

Speaker 1  (39:55)
Been in a scenario where an investor or A funder or even an audience member said. Oh, that person was way too excited about their business. Oh, they got too much energy for this. 

Speaker 1  (40:07)
I have literally never come across that in terms of feedback. I think there's scenarios where people are like tick, cocky or 2, you're leading with their ego and everyone's like, oh I don't believe you, you're like, you're just, you know, selling snake oil here, so there is a balance between being, you know, really excited and enthusiastic. And like making sure that people really believe you and trust you, because you're building relationships, but I would say, like, I have never heard anybody be like, oh, you're too, you're too energetic, like there's too much enthusiasm for your startup. 

Speaker 1  (40:42)
I don't know Randy and Carol. If you want to, if anybody wants to sort of comment on that. But 

Speaker 2  (40:47)
Yeah, okay, that's good too here, because I just want to make sure that the next time if I would like to have a pitch doesn't matter that if I just be too energetic and try to pop out that the screen. And some kind of kill that guy. Well, okay, thank you very much. 

Speaker 1  (41:06)
Debbie. 

Speaker 3  (41:09)
My question was a differentiation. So when I was um Trying to propose a solution. I want to save things like I can do this X times faster or X amounts closer or Y amount's cheaper and I don't have any of those numbers. 

Speaker 3  (41:36)
For a couple of reasons, one I've seen that the people that I speak to are extremely I think it would require 2 or 3 calls to be able to To be able to get them to trust me enough to say thought about costs. A couple of times people have A couple of times I think, in the beginning, we were ready. Like Click on a buck when I talked about the price and how much they spend with their solution right now. 

Speaker 3  (42:15)
And sometimes people don't have a solution right now. And I think they're just doing something manually. And so you're proposing to automate it. 

Speaker 3  (42:23)
So you want to estimate the cost in their entire operational workload, which is the number of how much infrastructure is spending, how many people they're doing? How many people they're employing? And that's that More often than not I've realized that people don't know That information of the tip of the head and had taken back when I asked them had they thought, but a couple of times on the way, I asked the question, I think I'm not very comfortable talking about money, and I think that shows When I'm speaking to other people, and so they, I'm smiling to get better at that, but I feel like I haven't had I haven't had interviews where I was able to walk away with like a number. 

Speaker 3  (43:13)
Number that says, oh okay, this is how much it costs me today. So how would I estimate this is my solution? As exposing cheaper? 

Speaker 3  (43:26)
How would I estimate that 

Speaker 1  (43:29)
Well, I guess my question is like, how do you know if that's true to be true, right? Have you validated this cost assumption that you have about your product being cheaper than the alternative, especially in the alternative, is not the customer not using any solution. Right. 

Speaker 1  (43:49)
So I'm likely unlikely that the people you're having conversations within customer discovery will tell you the right number. This is why you need to do The research right around industry around the cost. You know, I mean, those numbers are available out there in terms of what customers and businesses are paying for all of the variety of solutions. 

Speaker 1  (44:16)
So, and in the event that you're like, I have no idea where to start with that. If you don't have your or sort of like those numbers, then like I would just honestly start by looking at like going to AI and asking at like, what are the industry standards for these kind of costs. Or for this kind of right expense, I think, without Without that data, you won't be able to pitch on the price point and most investors. 

Speaker 1  (44:44)
I would say. Not a big enough difference. That is the price differentiator. 

Speaker 1  (44:52)
Is not enough to be compelling? You need to be a community part of the like a trio of differentiators, but it cannot be the only one. And it's unlikely that, yeah so like really thinking about that. 

Speaker 1  (45:06)
And then thinking from a research perspective on the research for the business, like, what do people pay an industry for this solution? Or not, the solution? So 

Speaker 3  (45:18)
Onto, how do it again? Maybe the combination is becoming award cost, and maybe that's something you want to talk about today. But the other question I had was about estimating the cost for what it would cost. 

Speaker 3  (45:30)
I know how other than my time. And I know how much a camera costs. For example, I thought I've spoken and got codes for cameras. 

Speaker 3  (45:40)
I know how much my time costs. I know how much a GPU costs. And so But then the reserve's entire conversation about how much I'm going to place it at right and how much time it's going to cost me to develop this solution. 

Speaker 3  (45:58)
And I am not quite sure. About how much time it's going to cost me a solution. Because I am not quite sure what the N product is going to be. 

Speaker 3  (46:09)
Because it's looking like it's quite it's a little bit different for everybody. I'm talking to the N product. 

Speaker 1  (46:17)
Hmm, okay? So. First, like understanding your costs. 

Speaker 1  (46:22)
And like obviously like, Randy's gone through all the various parts of the business model canvas. This is an important part of like, is this business actually feasible like, right like you need to understand those costs. And it is your time, it is the time of developers. 

Speaker 1  (46:37)
It's the time of like engineers. It's the time of the research and development team building Pilots running Pilots testing them. Depending on the business, right, it changes what that cost and that timeline looks like, but it's really important to be able to at least like have ranges of right. 

Speaker 1  (46:57)
You have ranges of what this is going to cost me like a 100 grand over a year to like, actually build this pilot. And you do, you'd absolutely need to know those costs even in a rough format to be able to understand the cost structure for the business, what it could be so that a you can actually like go and find funding to support the bill, like for you, to actually support that. And then secondly, for you to actually know again back to that argument like, is your product actually cheaper? 

Speaker 1  (47:31)
Or is that just an assumption you're making? Because I think pricing is something you do later, like not later, but like you need to understand your cost structure before you can price the product properly, especially for highly technical enterprise B to B solutions like pricing is a little all depends on the solution. But this is why I say on this horrible to say, but like in years past we didn't have AI to help us see like, oh you know, whatever Claude Chad, whoever you're talk, it's like, can you help me understand what the industry standards are for this type of product for this kind. 

Speaker 1  (48:09)
Of cost structure like you can go with some like good clearing. You can get some good data there to help you at least understand and think about what a cost structures are looking Thank you. Oh, and we'll go yeah, Randy's going to go over cost them pricing in March. 

Speaker 1  (48:28)
But again, like, I think pricing is sometimes 1 of the trickiest bits of actually of building any business. Because there's always fluctuations and other pressures that and inputs that are not in your control, so you got to figure out. How do you price the product in a way that you stay competitive in the marketplace? 

Speaker 4  (48:53)
Yeah, thank you so much honor for representation. I just wanted to ask on which part of the pitch will need to spend most of our time whether you develop the picture. So what part we should spend like a lot of time or we need just to divide them equally. 

Speaker 1  (49:10)
I mean, it's, I know, Randy's formula is like a minute of slide, which is a good right like it's a good default like a minute aside. If you've got 10 slides, but sometimes That will vary depending how quickly like you want to tell that part of the story, right? Maybe you'll spend more time talking about the market, or maybe you'll spend more time talking about the business model, or maybe you'll spend more time talking, like, leading up to the actual. 

Speaker 1  (49:44)
To the solution, typically what we want to know, though, within the first 2 minutes of a pitch is like what the solution is, so you want to get to that point fairly quickly. 

Speaker 4  (49:58)
Yeah, thank you so much. 

Speaker 2  (50:05)
You mentioned a very good concept about the elevator pitch. Imagine that you're going to, for example, an event or conference, that we have to some kind of talk so fast. And maybe try to get their interests in our product or platform itself. 

Speaker 2  (50:19)
So obviously we don't have that much of a time. Maybe 1 minute or 2 minute this is that the slide section or this is not about showing them that what I'm doing this is just warps. So how am I supposed to some kind of gain their interest to maybe invest on my work on that. 

Speaker 1  (50:40)
That's more of like the elevator pitch right? That's like your 62nd or 2 minute pitch, where you're really gonna just focus on, like what's your business all about? It's like what are you building? 

Speaker 1  (50:52)
And why That's really like in a short, you know, you got a minute or 2 minutes to talk to somebody, that's what you're going to focus on, you know, I'm going to talk about, like the business model. You know, I'm going to talk about the traction. You've had you're going to talk about, like your solution and why you're building it right? 

Speaker 1  (51:11)
Like, that's sort of the focus. And then if people are compelled, they're going to be like, oh interesting, like, what's the size of the market or like interesting, like, how long have you been added, like? Do you have customers? 

Speaker 1  (51:23)
Do you know like so, that's what I would if you're in a scenario where just meeting people. 

Speaker 2  (51:28)
So do I also have to consider about the matter of The funding at the end of my first, some kind of 60 seconds or 2 minutes. For example, I do have a plan of raising the fund for $2 million for this project. Should I talk about it or no I should have to wait for their interest. 

Speaker 2  (51:46)
Then talk about it. 

Speaker 1  (51:47)
No, I don't. I don't think you're like unless you're like having an investor meeting. You probably wouldn't be talking about it. 

Speaker 1  (51:55)
In that first introduction. Remember that and we'll talk about it in the fundraising module when we get to at But meeting investors and getting them onboard is really about building relationships and to build relationships. You've got to build trust, you've got to build interest, you're not going to ask them for money in the first 2 minutes, you meet them except Also okay, I'm pretty sure I'm like 8 minutes over time. 

Speaker 1  (52:25)
So if you've got any other questions about pitching, put them on slack, we'll be following up with all of you on this. And during our next office hours and the week that we meet in March, I do want you as homework to really like, take a look at some of the pitches in the deck. And think through what worked, what That's we'll take a 10 minute break. 

Speaker 1  (52:54)
And then come back for the scrums. The recording stopped. 
