
Speaker 1  (00:01)
A word that all the words at all, if completely understand that you were a little bit busy. So By the way, thank you very much for having me again. And congratulation, by the way, for that $200 million. 

Speaker 1  (00:13)
Apparently that you got from the government. That is a huge breakthrough. 

Speaker 2  (00:18)
I did not 200. That's a 105 divided on 3 companies phases. So what will receive is 8.3 right now. 

Speaker 2  (00:28)
But still, there's good money, and I think we have a very good chance of winning that contest. But we are pretty happy about it. Nevertheless 

Speaker 1  (00:36)
Perfect, excellent. So without her to do it, let's just talk about it. I mean, how much you remember about my project? 

Speaker 1  (00:41)
I mean, you remember anything about our last conversation? Or I have to listen to speaker. 

Speaker 2  (00:46)
We're talking about utilizing AI for ERP and applicable to additive manufacturing and such. So you looked at the 2 segments of it. Once it is for either manufacturing inspection. 

Speaker 2  (01:04)
Well, printing and the second one was really to ensure we have some Management of enterprise resources and planning and such. So that's what under what that happened at 

Speaker 1  (01:18)
Exactly. Yes, I mean to recap that one. Because, again, from our last conversation to right now, it happens for I guess one month or 2 month and between that between such I had also around 40 to 50 other interviews. 

Speaker 1  (01:34)
So after that, I found out that, yes, that having managing the some kind of espare parts is also another issue rather than just using the 3 give printers. But the reason that I do have this call again today is not just the interview. I was just going to ask you because you as a company that working in aerospace like are very, I can say, rare niche niches, that actually using 3D printers. 

Speaker 1  (02:02)
So you guys can give you a very, very good feedback. So at this point you mentioned from the last conversation we had you mentioned that you are using the 3D printers that is a really good thing, but I really would like to know that if you would like to have a software that you can some kind of apply to your some kind of procedure, what that software, actually looks like from the AI perspective. From some kind of the organism from the software that actually can connect different kind of 3-D printer facilities, because I mean, I was talking to other companies that they told me that okay, if you would like to have the 3G printer, obviously, if you don't have all of those capabilities to have the printing everything. 

Speaker 1  (02:44)
On-site, at some point we have to borrow some kind of from others as well. I mean, unlike one of the awards that people use that is just like the Airbnb for 3D printers, I really would like to know your idea about the whole some kind of application and how actually I can make it useful for your Indus or other ones. 

Speaker 2  (03:07)
So in our case, we're a little bit in a different niche. Given that vel 3, D the company with whom we buy those printers, they have already looked into this as in. They sell you the printer as a turnkey solution, so they have developed a software that will do the slicing that will facilitate Basically, they'll allow you to assess if the part is printable or not. 

Speaker 2  (03:38)
And once the part is printed, they will record every slice that was printed inspected so that you're able to complete that inspection during the principal. Even throughout the printing process and during the print, you're able to see exactly what's happening with your part if it's printing, well, if it's going well and such, because specifically other companies had that problem. That was scrubbing. 

Speaker 2  (04:03)
I think of us, I think of other companies where Yeah, learning how to use a printer was so velo. By reducing the barrier to entry, they're increasing their customer base. And they're able to sell more printer, which I think was very, very brilliant. 

Speaker 2  (04:20)
So in our case, the printing process is It is very, very seamless, we have something we want to print. We send it to uskar, who's one of my staff. He's one operating the printer. 

Speaker 2  (04:32)
He tells us, okay, so I'm gonna slice it 23 days later. He'll say, well, the part will be ready and 45 days, and we go pick it up and we continue. So from design to print I have seamless is really an understatement, and given that we're not like renting an in part per day, it's very easy to track, but there's still going to be the same printer is still going to be the same machine. 

Speaker 2  (04:57)
So we may have to have a process like, or maybe software that will allow to Trace, every part on the witch printer is being printed, but it's not really like this is something you can do with an Excel sheet like I will not wake up in the morning. And say, oh wow, I wish I really had that given that at the same part on the same printer but you have 4 of these printers or 5 of these printers and the printer will be spitting parts and sometimes you know, work sometimes not going to work, ensuring that the printer functions you know available 3 needle. 

Speaker 2  (05:33)
Sell it as yeah, you can use the printer 24. While that's not true, every company will say that, but this is not true, because you have to have some downtime time downtime, time so that the printer can be refurbished, can be you have some maintenance to do, so you want to minimize your downtime. But this is again like, push comes to show if you buy an extra printer and this is addressed And when you're having, you know, $50 million equipment, paying an additional 3 to 4 to ensure you're really printing at the cadence, you're looking for is not a big problem, but that's again, so the good thing is, while you're addressing a relevant problem. 

Speaker 2  (06:16)
The bad thing ville has thought of that in a certain way. So your market will be mostly confined and my understanding, and you know who am I to say will be confined to us machines or companies now using velo from what I understand but again, I may be wrong and I'm sure that your idea is very dynamic, as changing and shifting based on what you're listening from the people you're talking to, but, yes, so right now that is how we are able to operate from printing to from basically designing to utilizing the partnership. 

Speaker 1  (06:53)
That's good to know why the way at hearing that some kind of brutal honesty is one of the criteria that I have to have. For some kind of work that as I just mentioned, we are still at the customer discovery, it doesn't mean that we power so much money on it. And say that, okay, here's the solution. 

Speaker 1  (07:07)
So I have 2 more questions actually, because the first one is 1 of the most important one that so many companies ask for me, they say that, okay, imagine that we already have that 3D printers by ourself and who is going to be liable for that one thing that you mentioned to me is that because before that I talked with the gkn, I believe the aerospace and it told me that we are a little bit hesitated about using the 3D printers, but one thing that you mentioned is that in the normal airplane that the specific part should last 40 years, but in our work, it should just last 4 minutes. 

Speaker 1  (07:41)
So we don't have maybe that kind of worries about the human lives. Yeah, yeah, but one question is about the liability that I have, I mean, the velo or other companies, when they some kind of give you the 3D printers obviously they have to give you assurance or guarantee, I know the quality assurance and some kind of other part exists but still someone should be responsible. My second question is about the usage of AI. 

Speaker 1  (08:07)
Because after talking with so many people I found out that most of them, they're really interested in AI. But the issue is they don't know how to use it or where to use it. Someone said that. 

Speaker 2  (08:20)
How if you ask me? 

Speaker 1  (08:23)
Yeah, I mean, don't know how to use it. And if they know they still have to find a place for that, I mean, someone told me that we needed an inventory management, someone told me that we needed in knowledge gap management. And where is there some kind of your use case of AI over here? 

Speaker 1  (08:39)
So one question is about liability and one of area here, yeah, yes 

Speaker 2  (08:44)
For me, I use AI to help draft emails, and that's the best use of emails, because It can be relevant to other things that 'S.A. longer topic, but for the quality assurance. I think when you are in O. 

Speaker 2  (09:00)
M you cannot delegate that responsibility and you cannot really shift the blame on the company, making the printer the company making the printer they're giving you a tool. They're not giving you a solution. You are the one using that tool to build a solution and you have to ensure that the solution you're putting forth respects, the quality criteria that you're selling for customers, which means you have to print parts, you have to do your quality assessment. 

Speaker 2  (09:27)
You have to understand the materials and the characteristics of these materials through your own testing procedure. Printing 3 year printing is still a manufacturing process. And it still involves some engineering. 

Speaker 2  (09:45)
It's not like the magic where you press a button and the part is perfect. This is, and it will never be like this. I mean, maybe maybe in 1015 years. 

Speaker 2  (09:54)
But the way we're leveraging that tool we're using printers, the same way you use any other manufacturing process, where after completing your build, you have to do your own quality assessment, and you have to do your own quality assurance, and you have to ensure that what you're manufacturing. Respect. Validated requirements that are given to you. 

Speaker 2  (10:18)
So that's really what is very, very important. So in our case, we have built processes in-house, to validate the characteristics of the materials to validate the performance of those materials. And such so that has not necessarily changed or influenced how we do things to your other question about AI. 

Speaker 2  (10:43)
AI can be a very powerful tool if you use it in a way, to support your engineering and decision-making, and to help you better understand the environment for which you're designing or to better understand the interference of different fields or disciplines, you know how your turmoil will affect your dynamics and vibrations and such-and-such, which is something you would expect an engineer to know. And it is mostly the case. But it's really, you know, if that AI help you reduce or help you avoid One problem out of 50 out of 50 cases, where, you know, let's say you have a failure rate of One out of 50 I am on your engines or your builds, or whatever. 

Speaker 2  (11:38)
If you're able to use AI to make it one out of a 100, that's already great use action. But that's the thing is, so far. We've been using it but not necessarily for engineering as much as it is, you know, emails and you know, documentation and stuff like that. 

Speaker 2  (12:02)
Yeah, there are definitely other ways, but I'm not an expert in AI. So this is really where I will. I will. 

Speaker 2  (12:10)
I will refrain from giving recommendation. You know, I know how to build engines, rocket engines, but I'm not the AI expert. 

Speaker 1  (12:17)
Yeah, two things that you mentioned very cut my eyes because the first point was about the liability I went to and 3 summits. I mean, two weeks ago, and talked with a different kind of companies, and I talked with three different companies, and I asked the same question about the liability, and they were very conservative said that. Okay, we are just sailing the tools I mean, at the end of the day. 

Speaker 1  (12:40)
You as a manufacturer have to make sure that everything works fine. Because apparently liability is a very, very important thing that nobody wants to get responsible for that. I believe you can imagine that how costly, and how some kind of important would that be if you want to sell you something? 

Speaker 1  (12:56)
And I cannot guarantee everything for you. You are the responsible for that about the second 

Speaker 2  (13:02)
But I think where you're talking about specifically, in the case where companies are using three different printers to manufacture parts for other companies, and these other companies are the oems when you own the tool and you are the oem. Yeah, that's an easy question. You should not. 

Speaker 2  (13:24)
And you cannot defer liability on the producer or the printer. You are the one making the engine or the rocket or the satellite. It's your responsibility to ensure that this is, I think it's a very lazy thing from companies who say, oh well, that's not my problem. 

Speaker 2  (13:42)
It's of course, a problem. You are the one selling departure. The one manufacturing designing engineering, so you have a responsibility to ensure that the part respects the quality standards that you're offering. 

Speaker 2  (13:54)
And you're selling, but there's a case where it's a little bit more nuanced, which is you are making a part add for a company. And that company is the oem. I think it's the same thing. 

Speaker 2  (14:07)
You cannot blame the printer manufacturer. Because the power to manufactured for MDA is shipped, it's up to you to understand the characteristics of the printer and what the printer can provide and that the part is bad, just don't buy the printer, you know, just all companies making three different printers will allow you to print parts with them so that you can try, and you can get used to the process, and you can really know the limitations of that process. It's up to you to explore those options before you make a purchase. 

Speaker 2  (14:39)
That's I hope that wasn't the majority of what people are selling. What people are saying if you spoke in 250 companies, and they're all looking to defer liability. This is what are we doing as a country. 

Speaker 2  (14:51)
You know, you have to be owner and responsible for the parts you're producing regardless where you situate yourself and the value chain. 

Speaker 1  (15:00)
Exactly, it completely makes sense. And I want another thing about AI that you mentioned obviously in this conference. I saw that how AI was some kind of at the very beginning. 

Speaker 1  (15:10)
I thought that people don't know how to use the AI or if they know they don't know where to use that. But at this some kind of event I saw that there are different companies that actually using AI still there are limited amounts of numbers. But that is a good news. 

Speaker 1  (15:24)
That apparently everyone understood about the AI capabilities. Another thing you mentioned about using AI was one of the phrases that one of the people mentioned that is that everyone thinks that AI is going to steal their jobs. But AI is there to help you as a side eye as you just mentioned. 

Speaker 1  (15:42)
If AI even can handle one out of 50 or 1 out of 100, that's still a success, right? We're talking about million dollars project that was fascinating to know that 

Speaker 2  (15:52)
I will not replace people. AI will replace tasks. And when you see it that way, it's a very eye-opening, you will not replace an engineer. 

Speaker 2  (16:04)
You will ensure that that engineer can do more with the same tools, and you will ensure that some of the tasks he's looking to do can be automated, but you will still need to have someone, maybe you'll need less people for sure and that's okay, but you won't replace like basically. It will change how we do our work. But it will not change it by removing the task of analyst, it will change it by ensuring that some of the work that these analysts are doing can be automated. 

Speaker 2  (16:35)
So it can do more work with the same amount of people. 

Speaker 1  (16:38)
Exactly. At the end of the day is about increasing the efficiency. Or obviously we cannot replace the human and test level. 

Speaker 1  (16:44)
But the app does very fascinating. I mean chat. I mean, I know it passed the death 50 minutes. 

Speaker 1  (16:49)
But right now, still, I'm working on the process, I mean, I'm a step back a little bit right now to some kind of freshman mind. Because in 4 months it was very, very compact. I talked with Elon 70 to 73 people, so there were so many people I have to gather knowledge again. 

Speaker 1  (17:05)
But at the end of the day probably I will ask you I know how busy you are, but maybe in the future I would ask you again say that hey I do have my MVP right now because I'm working on an MVP. So I really would like to know your feedback and maybe other people about that specific suffer that how actually it works? Maybe someone said that no, this part is wrong. 

Speaker 1  (17:25)
This part is right? So is that okay if I reach you out? You say that hey, I do have my MVP. 

Speaker 1  (17:30)
Are you ready for having another kind of maybe 1520 minutes meeting? Do I have that permission going on? Yeah, yeah, perfect. 

Speaker 1  (17:38)
I just want to make sure by that. Okay, that was fascinating. Thank you very much again for your time and consideration and appreciate it. 

Speaker 2  (17:45)
My true pleasure enjoyed the rest of your weekend and calculation. Thanks, take your boy. 
