
Speaker 1  (00:01)
So nice time to do simmer. So we are here today for the yeah, defence innovation on the role of aid manufacturing session. And so we've got an amazing panel coming up my colleague from the BBC aggre roles most of the water of the plant with some really some of the names. 

Speaker 1  (00:20)
Canada's leading innovatives, including one that my fun, strong Morse has done, which is BBC's new defence. Hung funded so fan. I think it's going to be super exciting. 

Speaker 1  (00:30)
It's great to be here in Toronto, and we're at a time when the advance manufacturing technology communities are being asked to do a lot of things very quickly. The competitive nature globally, of course, has changed in a dark factories, to evs. We all feel the pressure on top of that. 

Speaker 1  (00:49)
Geo's geopolitical situation is changing, and it's a real mindset change seeing some of the things and learning some of the things a couple of months I've been now running the strong north defence fun with actually more heightened than that, we have to get added and stimulate our defensive industrial base. And that add advanced manufacturer is absolutely core colour, so there's a lot to do. There's a lot of couple flowing in, so there is some hope and some support in the sector has been challenged both competitively and financially at strong north. 

Speaker 1  (01:22)
The stronger refund is $300 million combined with the previous deep tech fund that BBC ran we manage the platform for knowing bdc received 6 billion, which goes across all of the business lives in the track, but that's a second, so it's not just the stronger adventure fund is kind. Of the thin tip at the wedge for some of the most new high risk in innovatives in the So our mandate is both sovereign and financial. We have to make sure that after the fact the capital on adventure capital Fun, so it is high risk of its nature. 

Speaker 1  (02:02)
Well, we're trying to go the fadually responsible. That's master one and master 2 for our team. Is detensive Solver renews industrial strategy dot-coms released about a month ago that a combination of the Defence Minister? 

Speaker 1  (02:17)
The Prime Minister of the minister of industry and the minister of procurement and it outlines what things are Canadian forces and NATO Partners, not just our forces but our commitment to NATO. And the thing so you may or may not know this that NATO and the allies get together inside what technology should be led at mastered by what countries in Canada has a certain set of them. They're in the strategy. 

Speaker 1  (02:40)
If your company's can contribute to realising the goals of the strategy, then you would be eligible for funding potentially by the defence platform at BBC rid large, and many other programmes you will have heard of roughly speaking, in order to the government, just announce that the defence has gone to 2% of GDP spending, and it's aiming to get to 5% / 2032 that represent something. There were 200 to $280 billion of incremented spend and in this year alone I believe it's over 18 billion 6 of which meant to BBC somewhere in the 6, I'm confident on the other number. 

Speaker 1  (03:21)
It's an estimate, but that is there is a lot of effort. So my fun is trying to be, as I said that the tippolos here we go, in where others want. We are trying very hard to break the logic. 

Speaker 1  (03:35)
Some of you, and some of our most innovative people in this country have ambitious goals. The very risky, because they're their defence defence means one or a few buyers. It means limited access to exits. 

Speaker 1  (03:49)
And capital is hard to become by, but Your defence of this country requires substance. So what do you do? So it's hard one, and our team basically scrattles that gap. 

Speaker 1  (04:01)
And we often have to, you know, proceed bravely in cases, were balance sheets because of the many years of underfunding in the defence sector a balance, they're not pretty. And so we lack private equity firm, we were renoving and then invest. So we are different. 

Speaker 1  (04:18)
This is different than other units of BBC the other traditional lines are still held by the fidual responsibility and so more traditional we will try and write things and invest in things but we can't do. And some are just too risky, they want a lot of day, it's just not traditionally responsible, and some they're interesting that they don't need the sovereign tests so that I hope gives you an operator's Filters and lands to understand sorry, okay, so moving on from strong north, there is our family of funds of eacher runs the IT F which is the industrial innovation, metro funded BBC. 

Speaker 1  (04:55)
It's been around for a number of years, very successful fun. And they focus on industrial innovation with each year to tell you about that, we have other funds that focus on everything from diversity goals to climate, etc. To growth. 

Speaker 1  (05:10)
Underneath strong north heart check sizes, typically 210 million, typically around is double that. So we are mandated to try to lead so I can have the report we'll talk a little bit on the panel about one of the companies who recently funded. And if our goal is to break the log jam and give Canadian entrepreneurs, the rocket fuel in some cases, very literally, you know, we have achieved that we're very proud of that, but it's very difficult. 

Speaker 1  (05:36)
So engaging with us, we will try everything we can. We try never say no. We try to say yes, if and the gift is the things you've got to go fix, it will try to help, but we can't do them all. 

Speaker 1  (05:47)
But we remember only 300 we wish we had more. But that's our role. And that's our goal, and we've had some early stage success. 

Speaker 1  (05:54)
I'm only going to have this about a month, but I think consulting to be easy for those 3 or 4 months. So very exciting, very purpose built work and our Prime Minister is later a great challenge and very decisively acted with financing and programmes across ago to enable this capability, the climate yum. So geopolitics, the rise of tensions. 

Speaker 1  (06:17)
Globally, we all read the news, I'm not here to defend their fears, but economic stimulation of the defence sector in a time like this would seem to be approved. Will it all be seen 10 years from now and has exactly the right thing to do. Because we, in fact, had to get ready to participate in the defensive, NATO or ourselves, or whatever role armed forces are called upon possibly Use this old basically a show of NATO man to save you not see, and it's deterrence, but in the same time we're stimulating our economy and then, as you know, defence often as the wars have caught even whether there is or not, a war defence often leads with technical innovation that then turns Google use. 

Speaker 1  (07:00)
And our fund is very much looking for you to bring to us opportunities to lead in defence, but also tell us about the deal use commands, helping you help of our society. So those are the ideal projects because defence, unfortunately, the procurement of defence waxism, lings training an army does not require the purchasing the fielding, an army does. And so the sector suffers from capital availability of revenue, which is sickable, but this is the time now. 

Speaker 1  (07:29)
The tensions are all over the news, and so it is the right leadership decision to preparis, so with that, the manufacturing sector is absolutely core and you've got to rethink everything and from where you source. Your components, because now there's just a political risk. They're actual requirements. 

Speaker 1  (07:46)
Now, that componentry be sourced, you know, from NATO or from countries that there is already a risk of industrial espionage, and these are real things, and these are all about bip grade. I simply run a pipeline of investment against aid goals, but to deny that these things are there. The US has recently banned Wi-Fi repeaters coming from the countries like China, and we all know those of us that have been in defence long enough know that. 

Speaker 1  (08:14)
You don't know fighters with parts that come from countries that may be novellang with you, so now that responsibility is something you need to consider. You're an advanced manufacturer here in Ontario. And now you have to consider where am I getting my cards, because my customer is starting to ask for full life. 

Speaker 1  (08:31)
Cycle, a lot of them mental sources. So we understand that you have changes, you also have to figure out how to scale trade barriers are changing economics radically for you. It used to be by the cheapest by the cheapest. 

Speaker 1  (08:45)
Now you've had geopolitical considerations, you've got reliability of your customer and almost sudden you have to source differently. That opens opportunities but for finance use, like our team. It's also difficult so if you want to stand up with rushless motor company to address the drone market demand which currently dominated by China, because the labour component in the motors is SO high it's only efficient place. 

Speaker 1  (09:07)
But now a sudden if you're signing to defence. They want you to not get that from there. What do you do? 

Speaker 1  (09:13)
So we also all collectively, and it's really hard. We're all swamp around a lot of stress. We have to think about a full life cycle value change, and so our team is trying to figure the we're only 300 million. 

Speaker 1  (09:26)
But we have to dig ambitions. We're going to be really smart about So if you're thinking that might be too much evs have landed on our shores, the Prime Minister made decision to let a certain amount in because consumer benefits, but at the same time understanding how did that becomes abnomin, as 30 years of directed industrial policy in China against the entire supply chain? Starting from the base component of the end Lazy fair politics as you can see, our Prime Minister clearly thinks it's time for directed policy. 

Speaker 1  (09:57)
That's why the defence industrial strategy uses, because we're competing in a world of people who are planning decades ahead and actively moving capital and resources against it. We're doing the same, we're certainly doing it in defence, I'll suspect strategy will follow so if you're feeling these things we see it, we will be trying to be sensitive to all of that. We're also overloaded as a team just rering this fast as we can, but we see all these problems. 

Speaker 1  (10:22)
So it's okay when you come in diligence with our fun tells us, I think we Now we expect we're still going to try and figure out a fun so with that, there's the intersection of supply chain scaling, and IP protection. That's another big thing that's coming out there and you've got to focus on doing use. We're not asking too much earlier. 

Speaker 1  (10:42)
We are but the situation goals work. There's not much what we can do. So every time you think about your situation, trust me on the funding side, it's no different. 

Speaker 1  (10:50)
We have to think about everyone of these 200 companies at the time, and it's very difficult, but we're getting we're going to talk about some successes today. We're going to win this enormous athletes, too big for us, but we're trying to win up one much more. So that's our focus of strong. 

Speaker 1  (11:04)
We are looking to be a first mover. As I said, the capital to break these long nams weird, we have to win the best amount of people and we'll continue to do that. And we want to crown capital in so other venture financing Partners. 

Speaker 1  (11:19)
You will see a show up if you have a lead investor we will not look to replace your lead investor we will look to follow-on in that case. If you cannot, I believe investor and you meet all the other criteria we will lead. That's what we do. 

Speaker 1  (11:37)
We're going to talk about some of the cases we've done that today. So we're attending, though we don't supply the whole round. That's one thing. 

Speaker 1  (11:44)
You must, we need this indication outside validation? Because master one financial says the taxpayer wants to know that the investment we put into wasn't the speed AR dealing, it had market ricing to some Very difficult in the fact so we need on defence crimes, IT D credit. I'm sure most of you often know that is because it is hard to syndicate defence skills because revenue uncertainty value of death, single fire or limited access. 

Speaker 1  (12:10)
But the country needs so to taxpayer, we say we're doing both, and we're trying to find the best deals that strategically do the most, but it's not easy for you for us that we're going to do it. So these are the ways in which we address the gaps in the non well served defence funding market, particularly in advanced manufacturing We're accepting that speed improves with repetition and scale and not a cautional model. So we need to go faster and we're working. 

Speaker 1  (12:39)
All right, so our defence platform I've talked a lot about strong north, but both of the Catholic I've spoken to about 300 million and type of the sphere. But really? It's 6 billion. 

Speaker 1  (12:49)
So where's the 5.7 billion? That's in the traditional activities of bdc across the country. You all know BBC is offices across the country and several 1000 people working for it, most in direct facing of customer and trying to figure out trying to direct you from your account manager. 

Speaker 1  (13:06)
They now know we exist at strong north, but they also know that there's like 17 billion of capital that needs to be invested coming from traditional corporate financing to finance skill production, diversify your markets and participates in defence and industrial programmes advisory service that will help you increasingly with procurement, operational maturity and supply. Chain immigration, the advisory services team is working to educate themselves and become experts in procurement for defence because it is not easy. 

Speaker 1  (13:36)
Defence procurement is very difficult takes a long time. There's a lot of special requirements. It is seem to be bureaucratic, it is seem to be slow, but that's because of the incredible complexities. 

Speaker 1  (13:48)
We'll identifying, but one of the leading experts on this thing is, sand the grant economy, and we might have a very distinguished mostaches. One of our skater snaky reserves too okay, in terms of investments, it's not just strong north that has access to defence Gavit, the growth fund the seed, fund the climate change. Fund the diversity funds they all draw from their 5.7 billion. 

Speaker 1  (14:15)
So you don't need to just talk to us. We're the deep tech strong north defence line, we're the very first very high risk apple that goes in, but if you're a pure seed looking for a check of a million dollars less, you need to talk to mark Smith seat, funny, he actually did the initial defence 2 defence investments that came out. Of the announcement, starting November 1 of the CEO's On Canada's great entrepreneurs to cigarette there, you're going to hear more about that incredible soon. 

Speaker 1  (14:46)
The team applied from still being built. So I'm alleved with the one thing you do engage, you're probably get a first meeting quite quickly with strong or the other managers manage their owns. Ours is three people hoping to get to a team of 12 to deploy the capital cycle time as slop. 

Speaker 1  (15:02)
So I'm going to apologise, you'll typically meet us. We might hear from us for Olympic 2 Until we get around you but all clearer service time. If you get much much better by the end of the year. 

Speaker 1  (15:12)
Alright, there are role communs consistent of BB. C even with these new changes, we're here to support and connect Canadian SMS to anchor manufacturers and scales and power the innovators that turn technology into capability, particularly in defence, if we're going to play to our strengths on this new environment. It's because of the companies like yours. 

Speaker 1  (15:32)
So defence is about packnical leadership. What has really driven on the world work? Those World War 2 is the technical leadership of the west. 

Speaker 1  (15:42)
We need to maintain it. It comes from you so you need to find those ways to be innovative connect with. We have an incredible deal of researchers in this country. 

Speaker 1  (15:53)
I've spent a career working with many of them find those people find those advanced innovations and think on a global scale. And when you meet us, we will try to leave you even if we can't plunge. We will try to leave you with yes or no, but if you did these, we'll try and coach you. 

Speaker 1  (16:12)
I'm going to BC in this space differently because our mandate is financial cancer. So with that, I'm looking forward to the conversation today, I hope, by the examples that you will see by the leaders in the entrepreneurs that a nature is going to out on the panel that you will get some examples and get some inspiration. Let's reinvigorate Amber's defence industrial base for sovereignty and for our one safety. 

Speaker 2  (16:48)
A request for palace to join me on the stair as well. These sessions are philans are really investing, right? So I'm hoping everybody's calculated and ready to go, because we're going to be hearing from the children who Canada, one of them is putting their Roos in fit. 

Speaker 2  (17:05)
Bringing medal? Have a good manufacturing of collap to scale. Anyway, so, thanks, Peter. 

Speaker 2  (17:12)
So I'm not tiger. All the magic partner of the united innovation mention fund you know, I called Belfast not set with Peter, we've got Mikey members of alpham scale this evening and those go there fantastic I'm looking around for a dinosaur innovation. Metro fun. 

Speaker 2  (17:29)
I call it as the heavy lecture after the sport and leading series a armours. Startups, since 2019 our focus areas have been in a fast manufacturing robotics mining, as well as the full value from arm to forking fut, you know so, and this is kept the base, right? So we are very patient capital, even if we're leading or following a series a we help the companies to go from there to BC and scale in now one of the examples there, if you hear is, you know, in the 2016 for ski investment and the national in emission came in 2021 and we still kind of double down double down until the company was scaling beyond us. 

Speaker 2  (18:11)
Right? So we're here, we have patient appo, we're ready to support you and You know, looking forward with his organisations with analyse and one thing I want to make it when we were putting this balance together, our goal was not the critic on policy, but it actually helped understand what it takes to ensecue as you go through a changing frameworks or policies. You know, over a decade, policy will change, right? 

Speaker 2  (18:35)
And we can't, you know, assume that the frameworks go to stay a constant, you know, 3 or 5 years cycle. And then these people have built over the last decades in Canada. I think combined you're talking about more than 50 years of experience and building companies here on the stage. 

Speaker 2  (18:50)
Right. So that's the goal today. The conversation is, you know, how do you build as uncertainty becomes more and how do you find where to navigate and certainty? 

Speaker 2  (19:00)
So with that, I'd like to get a 1000 introduce themselves, and then we kind of get into the Q&A so maybe we're starting with before at the P. N. 

Speaker 3  (19:11)
Sure, thanks. Great speaker bences back. So this is this is very exciting in terms of my background. 

Speaker 3  (19:19)
I grew up in the family defence business. We need something called signature management. So we confused signatures, radared meghism and mostly all of our B responded in Canada, but we Sol, primarily in the US and I found it a company called O nex helping The world's largest defence crimes managed their offset obligations. 

Speaker 3  (19:40)
So Canada purchase IDS but worked a lot of ITV's so next to 2020. That's the perfect companies. What watched we have to say it's my big songs. 

Speaker 4  (19:56)
Everyone I'm here, the priority of occasions to the design building. So it's a factory Toronto. And we're used to bring real-time information from space back Qualifiers, they progress too far all way to hypersonic weapons that are approaching a far north and I didn't want to take a brief moment that today's a pretty special day in space. 

Speaker 4  (20:21)
Everybody should all recognise, we have terror jember, he hands it, that's how to do a move. It'll not only be the first Canadian to go up the move, but also more currently the first non-american heading out and around the room, so keep a close watch for his launch. That's coming up there once his game too. 

Speaker 2  (20:39)
Yeah, and I have hungard in trapped up there. It's meals always humble, but keflar arguably right now is the largest satellite feed up, we're really kind of the battery 2 satellites in space, a lot of people don't know about it, and they're building them right here in the city in front, right? So thank you, Mia 

Speaker 5  (21:00)
Thank you for the reminder of you. I don't like that. Everybody wants to stay from pay off the same way that means I have kept Nick upside and profounders, yeah, and CEO like atmospheres. 

Speaker 5  (21:14)
So we start coming back in 2015. So what we can do is we make medal power malloys, for had a manufacturing. So, promoting out manufacturing, slow, expensive, so our mission from beginning was designed Absolutely, barriers to scale investriment out of the manufacturing. 

Speaker 4  (21:35)
So our 

Speaker 5  (21:37)
Alan Turing, 510 times faster. It's announceful. And basically reduces the cost for customers to prints maybe 80%. 

Speaker 5  (21:48)
What's it in the industrial zone for production? So our customers tend to be automotive defence companies from all over the world and so yes, really. Our mission is to bring out of manufacturer in major. 

Speaker 5  (22:01)
Of course, you're very focused on clean tech, which with BBC approached when I'm starting quite a while ago on that. In the last 12 months, the whole breakdown, global supply chains and wrapping up fancy and trying to be more nibbolently perps, where you need them, more versatile is really all a sudden driven our business in a question. 

Speaker 2  (22:23)
You should think ultra precise when you think about standard manufacturing. Nonpropre. 

Speaker 5  (22:31)
Oh, diversites, that's right now. 

Speaker 2  (22:34)
Yeah, have you all know? So if we ask them to interviews, we'll probably understand Alright, so we'll start with a campby, you know what? This is kind of the context, a lot of your builders, and you're building kind of you know, why do you build Canada? 

Speaker 2  (22:52)
What was the challenges and before the kind of drivers allowed to go? And how do you scale in the last decade? While you're building a kind of talent supply chains when it's on 

Speaker 5  (23:03)
Thank you. So Our businesses were really designed for Canada. In the way. 

Speaker 5  (23:12)
So just be down spreaking industry. Personally, I red. It's a lot of time thinking about headwinds and strategy and the Barris and wrings are not a bit so I thought the next time I do this. 

Speaker 5  (23:28)
We're going to think through those things, clinical founder. I didn't have a particular passion for material science, but I really try to do is design. The business stuff would leverage, you know, like it's if you're starting a new company. 

Speaker 5  (23:39)
What are your strengths or the opportunities? How do you go to entry and sure enough? What I finally zone down to is, you know, cans very strong movement. 

Speaker 5  (23:48)
It's incredible background material science, right back to the all candidates. 3 aerospace. Background, which is really helpful our understanding markets and surprisingly, multidiskiplinary group of engineers. 

Speaker 5  (24:06)
So and today, you know what we do is we basically take $5, aluminium and exporter for $100, power and enhance that, as now, with special reverse, like scanny, which are really a unique chippoint we have them great points leverage, so basically we couldn't have done this about candidate, Canada. Has been this? We're in a lecture in the string so I can't because I'm a real believer, you know, a car starting this picking which one to be in once you're in a certain business is really hard to make money. 

Speaker 5  (24:38)
You're not have the right kind of one. So, you know, I think we're in hand because we couldn't have been anywhere else and we wouldn't have got me at the start without being can. 

Speaker 2  (24:48)
Mean anywhere add than that. 

Speaker 4  (24:50)
Have very different point of view. The woman inside a shared, but I'd say objectively. He felt it back when we started the business. 

Speaker 4  (24:58)
Being Canada is a bad decision. Just like that, want to open up with that. If you think about the environment that existed around us. 

Speaker 4  (25:06)
You know, a decade prior there was unpopular to talk about defence tech to use technologies, but this crazy person, trying to build launch and operate lasers from space with UV. It's just in comprehensible for the ecosystem, and you know, being Canada is just a disadvantage altogether, you know, whether they're being capital access or being kind of mentorship. On other cases, in an entrepreneurs back and it help you, you know, live the story through their eyes and make, you know, accelerate your decision-making. 

Speaker 4  (25:40)
So the fun fact is, we got accept that into one combinator in 2016, turned that down, and I had a very unpleasant phone call, Sam Alli, that kind of repeated to us, like why are you doing this? Because they ultimately wanted us to read us on the US which is Teach very lost, we are our sound trick. We manufacture problems on spacecraft and what anchored us here in Canada Lisa at that point in time. 

Speaker 4  (26:06)
I'm fair account on access. So coming from the university where the masters and kd, I could become the top 50 people that I would hire instant. And you that they were top 1% of world capabilities and advances. 

Speaker 4  (26:17)
It's not something I could have done in the area like I'd be one of many that are entirely accessible. That's why we made the decision about that point in time, by fast forward. It's kind of paid out, and now, I think we're seeing an environment that supported around us. 

Speaker 4  (26:31)
So we've come full circle, right? It's it's really different today. I don't think people To find existed while ago, it would have been popular to talk about. 

Speaker 4  (26:39)
And we're now circle unfortunate to be an environment support of the can spur on an next generation of an entrepreneur. To get back to that and see some of the companies that are working on the defence industrial strategy, but that's a bit of reform. We've seen a time period and the only thing that we kept anchoring ourselves on is like control of things that you can control, which would, you know, we joke that we've been through pandemic a couple wars, and a few other things in the course of building the business, which has been pretty interesting and so seeing all those various phases of the world in their shifts can help to stay from what we can't control in today. 

Speaker 4  (27:16)
It's a very rich environment for us to be able to go in build new technology capabilities. Serve defence to use In many manufacturing projects 

Speaker 2  (27:26)
We've got anything from you. 

Speaker 3  (27:28)
So I think Canada is really good at kind of that early stage RND funding, so we get sprinklings of programmes like the ISD programme and DND's programme, we have shred, and you know, a great point about talent. So like that early stage has, I think been pretty good for a long time. Capital's always been a huge problem. 

Speaker 3  (27:48)
I think about landing zones with one competitor in the world. Doing extremely high altitude military drones, this lady dones has better flights and is like more better history, better technology. And this one, competitor of ours has raised to over 200 million Canadian, with the same amount of revenue and for us. 

Speaker 3  (28:07)
Before bdc's fun came around, there was just like no ability to raise any money we'll boost strap me in aerospace startup. So capital has always been a problem. It sounds like we're solving that that's great. 

Speaker 3  (28:19)
The next problem is procurement. Defence is a very strange, different unique supply and demand dynamic that you don't get in the commercial market, and then the US they have all these contract vehicles that they can move very, very, very quickly, from R indeed directly into large-scale. Procurement, so I think about my family business. 

Speaker 3  (28:39)
We've moved everyone and everything down there to respond to an art like human opportunity that was creative, unique and moved quickly in Canada. We still have art of peas that we're talking about 789 years later, the DIA is changing things and like this summary procurement that just came out was like from start to end was 3 and a 1 months, and it's going to be $60 billion. So I agree, and I do believe things are changing, but in terms of building a defence company in Canada, we talk about a valley of death in like regular pack. 

Speaker 3  (29:15)
I would say it's that times a million I mean, the fact that Mina is still alive is like a miracle because to get from already commercialization to actual sales. If you're doing something really innovative in defence and innovating on Harbour side is just it's really hard. If you don't have a buyer that wants to buy in a creative and fast way. 

Speaker 2  (29:38)
The mentioned apple, like so, and building sort of capability, often requires a lot of horizons, like so new experience and ethical in Kevin, lena. And what types of capital, missing strategic corporations? Government programmes, you know, have actually been most compatible the building Canada, you mentioned early stage. 

Speaker 2  (29:57)
But you know, and where are these incentives didn't miss align? And where do you think those gas will be filled with the framework setting announced, you know, and I think a lot 

Speaker 3  (30:08)
I think there's just too many. There's too many programmes and you have to do like a huge exercise to get the money and you have to write like 200 page essay on why you're great to 7 or eight different programmes. I think it would be much better serve if we took the shred programme reformed it in some way, and so it was just part of your tax return if it was just simpler. 

Speaker 3  (30:30)
These are monfied on the spending dollars. Can we get some funding against it? And they something like that would be better. 

Speaker 3  (30:37)
But I mean to answer your questions to what funding is available. There's a lot. I mean, I used anything everything. 

Speaker 3  (30:43)
I could get my hands-on a multiple different situations, there's like shreds, there's higher app. There's everyone here that we probably knows them all. So there's a lot of little things I think if we were to do a big reform, we should step back and try to make it more streamlined and simpler and like one programme. 

Speaker 4  (31:03)
Neighbour, like one thing we can have to do. What are these sources are interesting when they're not relevant? The singular? 

Speaker 4  (31:12)
Most important thing for Canada to do right now is be a buyer like I am your customer. I will apply this good for you. We have a defence industrial strategy that speaks to, you know, these are the things we need as a sovereign capability set, you know what we're guess in our way. 

Speaker 4  (31:29)
For any of our success to happen was all driven by well, I've sold guids to the US base force, I sold goods to the European space agency to the UK ministry defence, and all that happened, and now we're qualified entity, and I'm just coming back because to Canada sells. The same kinds of capability only now in our journey, because when our team is potentially, the vaccare, reliable partner when we continue for international defence. And commercial customers and so the one colour, a capital that Canada movies double down at large, and I think we're seeing some signs of it is like, how do I be your customer. 

Speaker 4  (32:11)
You know, above all, those that is the simular most important thing I think drill at home and we get, you know ready. Viries that are no longer measured by their options analysis over a 3 artery, they're measured by what capability we're able to feel in that role of a time period we're going to see it's just such a dramatic one industry. Oh, yeah. 

Speaker 4  (32:31)
I think from that point you cryed in outside, private capital, you cryed in that investors, you proud in Wall Street, and all of that becomes accessible. We'll just starts from being the right buyer of your D capabilities. 

Speaker 2  (32:46)
Yeah 

Speaker 5  (32:46)
Yeah, definitely grew last You know we sort of calling that our technique comes from 20:15 to 20:25 to get this far. So we've had to put in 1890 million dollars investment to get this far. The prize is that it's a multi-billion dollar limited power industry, but the company has started from Familiar, most Pte. 

Speaker 5  (33:08)
Canadian investors over 100 investors is like a like individual Canadians. All that credit in the world so progressing the to me see which is a small business adventure capital, past credit, where we're actually made individuals to Google sorts of things but then we got into we got into the series a USB C with series, be very fortunate for mccame. Corporate, we're going to I p's yes, the clean technologies. 

Speaker 5  (33:32)
I can just see the shreds make this kind of all of the above that between a huge gap in candidates. Just adventurers some series that kind of thing is my Canada, and we almost went with a couple of US rapid equity firms because it's so much more money, more ambitious, and it's tough, so the neat thing was something like us when I'm your sovereign. I think we're really arrived. 

Speaker 5  (33:57)
We're going to kind of companies should be granted up there multi-billion dollars a woman of power supplier for the world. They were set to do that by most investors. We're happy to wait. 

Speaker 5  (34:10)
You're not interested in building a sovereign capability. So you know, somebody has to be able to make those calls. It's really interesting hearing a word to leave because that we have full of people that will follow, but the old strategic leads Is this community? 

Speaker 5  (34:27)
It's army? 

Speaker 2  (34:29)
That's the cube for you, Peter. Due to talk to the moment this season, so I don't know. We haven't officially announced that the media, but maybe you're keeping a little bit of tabs on that but share the experience right? 

Speaker 2  (34:39)
Because what you're hearing from the goal is, you know, and the team is consistent. Early capital might develop our need PC. Individual, but even in our fun we've experienced that suis MB is missing where we want to play, we come and be. 

Speaker 2  (34:52)
And then you said the same thing and you know you said the same thing because I know what if your captables quite well and the GMP's are all the US messages and not not nice can you investors? Speaker you're going to talk about how commission was built you can have? Carried that forward, and we were the catalgar. 

Speaker 2  (35:08)
We were the cataly catalyst to dream editional catal. 

Speaker 1  (35:11)
Yeah, sure, I mean it's so the situation we find ourselves in is that the mandate is to leave these things. So Prime Minister issues, the direct that makes a decision defence industrial strategy is issued all the ministers get around. We then take that general peer dog leaves the Canadian armed forces joins as VP strategy at bdc Joe Regan and my boss, who runs direct apple metro programmes a series of funds bike on his consultants. 

Speaker 1  (35:41)
They're looking forward defence across BBC plus legal plus business plus yep, deck loss built operated and also finance. So, luckily, you know, by neandering English through the world of deep tech in defence in Canada, the US ended up with that criteria, but I believe it could be the mandate to lead But as I keep warning everybody, the risk committee doesn't, you know, really hold them the filter that why? But what we've been able to do is find these situations where you have Katie entrepreneur very often, not always, but maybe a third of the time. 

Speaker 1  (36:22)
They're Canadian on forces back, so they know the demand sign. And so the advantage is labouring is that they have a sense of what the forces will buy and that is going to change as it opens wider with retirement reform. But that gives us a chance to be validated on the need signal in advance of the purchasor so that's Step 1. 

Speaker 1  (36:42)
So it's not leading within. Oh, that sounds good. We'll leave it. 

Speaker 1  (36:47)
Can we if we can't see the purchase signal clearly, can we, at least tractively you know reason that the purchase will come? That's that one step 2 is defined problem? Step 3, unfortunately as analysts are absolutely correct. 

Speaker 1  (37:02)
Where do you think their first customer actually is? Yeah, it's studying the same, so it's not an unfortunate for businessandline it's we all wish Canada sources at the financial, maybe strategic and other motivations. The lead in terms of procurement, but the reality is this one money. 

Speaker 1  (37:18)
So so we have all that lined up, it's still not enough to cause the long-standing relationships. The corporation had with existing aerospace defence and other functors, and the balance sheet was an inhibitor to traditional pieces. So it was the first perfect, and we were very lucky. 

Speaker 1  (37:40)
It was our first deal, and we ran the deals and said that shouldn't do it. Do it private that would be perfect. So we'll take that extra us. 

Speaker 1  (37:52)
So we get here and we left and the thing that was astoning active. I mean, I think personally a little bit credit, come up to the idea. Let's just go to all the investors and tell him we're going to lead around with them without and so we held a couple of phone calls, and I literally cut up the phone and say we're gone if you don't take the rest, we're now we're going to do it first, got my boss to say. 

Speaker 1  (38:13)
Yes. First, what shock me was the two major aerospace companies went, okay. We're in eight people on the call in two weeks later they're in, I think everybody was shocked. 

Speaker 1  (38:26)
So there are cases, and I know a lot of user dreamers. Look, I've been a dream or look like my history. I want I've lost. 

Speaker 1  (38:34)
I've tried some really ambitious things generally fill. Learning alarm at work. It's not just the dream of use. 

Speaker 1  (38:42)
It's got to add almost other singles. So when you go to call with us and I'm saying, no, you need this. And this, and this is most exactly I'm ever sort every one of them. 

Speaker 1  (38:51)
Yeah, but that's what she got to do here. We sound a case and just the boldness of doing that on experimental call, basically caused the whole thing to Christmas. And then the thing after that, the US customer put it in order for a whole number of units, there's something that happens when you break that like in the right cases and all this, I'm never it just changes and everything goes in the exact same thing on the second door. 

Speaker 1  (39:21)
So we'll we do something in a completely financially responsible for the years amount of we call them in a big ski on a plane. Oh, I guarantee it. But the portfolio's big enough. 

Speaker 1  (39:32)
We don't start the risk. And so at least senior management Isabel, I give her locker. I was in the mornings, I was in the investment community meetings. 

Speaker 1  (39:42)
The company was delivering a mummunition. Mudc's never done that. Not only about the defence, we're not doing rockets emissions, and to give visit credit. 

Speaker 1  (39:54)
Somebody asked Third time ensure we knew we're doing It as The Order from the Prime Minister. That's the policy don't ever ask again. So the world has changed. 

Speaker 1  (40:06)
We are where we are, the right thing to start that. But we need way more apple, we need way more purchasing reform. But I'll leave it there. 

Speaker 1  (40:13)
We will try to break the long dead with you. 

Speaker 3  (40:16)
Okay, I just need to say I was on the other side of that story appears being so modest. It was crazy story with linen zones. We had basically even chosen for billion dollar US programme, but couldn't fund the like final testi, like not testified what the final thing to get into this. 

Speaker 3  (40:35)
And so we're not even saying, we're early stage company, we have a dream. We're saying like, we have an order. We just need this little bridge and we've, you know, scrounched around and spoke to as many investors as we could. 

Speaker 3  (40:46)
And then we get an intro to BBC and as like BBC. Now I'm not good, I don't want to talk to the government crown. For bank, we're good and we want a nature of Peter and it was like December 23rd, you know, everyone closes in Canada, December 10th and says season in January. 

Speaker 3  (41:01)
And we set up doing silver, Boxing Day morning, and everything kind of Ram, but you're right, you need the problem was that we were talking to 3 or 4 company or potential investors. And everyone was sitting out the sideline, like the start of a dance, no one wants to start it, and somebody has to lead in and say, and that's what he did. And we had like a couple of large aerospace companies that also want to invest, and it wasn't until they hurt some confidence and their minds and nice single BC. 

Speaker 3  (41:31)
Is it a crown court, and so it looks like some national support. So I'm really optimistic about what this is going to do for the country because it's really you just need a catalyst, you just need one little spark and then dispoint you can get the rest of the investors in and then you can get your first contracts and then you can go from there. So it's really critical. 

Speaker 3  (41:53)
What's happening here, and I'm glad to see that it's happening. 

Speaker 2  (41:58)
That's mainly sitting girls, along with talk about finance. Let's talk about the IP you know, so and a Dias called out as well, and a lot of people are talking about an IP insominite scaling it, so what is the right selection like to Unique, that's my backpring capacity, and I pick control and fostering that you guys have done over the years to get to a point where you're saying, okay, I want to keep it here, we're building it here, and we've scaled globally in some cases, before scaling in Canada. 

Speaker 2  (42:31)
What are the consideration is, how do we manage to kind of navigate some of those conversations with potential buyers? Who's saying, hey, why are you going just you know, ready or will? Why you have kind of can you talk to maybe starting Kevin? 

Speaker 4  (42:48)
Yeah, it's really hard problem, especially for serving. A customer like the US space Force because their goal in contracting is how do I have this sovereignty button that I can press in an all scenarios? You know, I'll press a button, and I'll be able to take over and so and I wouldn't. 

Speaker 4  (43:09)
I would say it's not just in how you sell the these customers. It's also downstream and supply chain, so we have a bunch of suppliers that are subjected to US regulations. And there are these regulations. 

Speaker 4  (43:23)
Constrain all the capacity, the seller of that good is your part of the service? The US sovereignty requirements before they're able to supply friends, so it took a lot of heavy negotiation, but one thing, at least that we've learned is the USA very performance orients by No, they have the like their priority side is like. Can you read the goals and I mission objectives? 

Speaker 4  (43:48)
And then okay, the 23 other things are less relevant because I care more about a mission objectives than it or anything else. And that's kind of given a celebration, these negotiations where, you know, historically the pocacket supercarman officers are very oriented around, we want access to rip, we want the ability to redom a Sil that should we need to want to be able to hit the sovereignty button and give you a de pass reading to take your goods or your production line. But can I agree on the performance attributes of what you could deliver that they unrise cannot get themselves. 

Speaker 4  (44:22)
It really creates some right negotiation, leverage and being able to work through contracting loss, preserved sovereignty, and Not only that, but reserve by pub in the organisations leakage out towards the variety of customers since it's certainly a tricky balance. And the thing I always ate grandmothers. National international customers Vs advocating prayer, broad procurement, reforms, and making that, you know, as much as possible people to build the defence industrial base. 

Speaker 4  (44:51)
You're going to give them every opportunity to thrive. And that means not trying to claim access to their IP or putting in change a control provisions as much as that might be a hinderance to your sovereignty goals. And then the second point is, like really dealing with technology, first performance that enables you to have a leverage position in that negotiation towards what do you want to get out of it? 

Speaker 4  (45:13)
Ultimately, and I think we've seen a trend in neopra contractors that are all oriented around this concept of we'll show you we do good work first, and then you can go and buy It capability from us as opposed to traditional prime contractors are very much anchored around what are your needs? And requirement statements and then they'll deliver to that to the tea, and you'll fun this on a cost plus basis, I think that it can has probably the biggest Anker in this new wave of defence oriented companies. 

Speaker 5  (45:45)
Gathering, this is a super thin because, you know, no surprise. Last clock 18 months you've seen you're going to use as US as we building power as a consumer, and then I have this to be in our market. They're ones that are around the price. 

Speaker 5  (46:00)
So you know what some of the challenges that we have is looking at longer R and need to scale, and the US has a couple billion dollar programmes that are supported by some of our largest customers, and they don't say we are. You sat down here, we can help the reason why is there's actual desire to have our reactors in that, so keep pressure a bit like customers to be like reactors down here, they're obviously under pressure to have been domestic. In that US worth, you just seen this rose and seen as domestic? 

Speaker 5  (46:35)
That that's changed, but our saving grace now there and we made, and it's been fairly compelling, is that there's a reason that you buy 75% of your Canada. Woolman, powder is exempted under the S. MCA for a reason, because it's strategic and our technology link, so they can't. 

Speaker 5  (46:56)
We're in position where they really had scale, you know, without us at moment those words, but I go back to the, you know, you're better off having us here. Supplying you reliably with these competitive advance, we have and trying to replicate technology distributed to the US so that important, competitive advantage from far. And it's on the Canadian, and I think it's our best device. 

Speaker 2  (47:21)
So maybe this equick is going to laugh that question, and then we'll maybe we open a gift to our users for work a couple of questions before we close. So you guys were able to export first for selling. What is the export rights that you guys, you know, back on? 

Speaker 2  (47:37)
And that allowed you to scale and say, okay, you know, these buyers are ready to buy. And they monitors at the company knows that they 

Speaker 4  (47:50)
I called me. 

Speaker 2  (47:51)
Which, yeah, like the wage I could reputable met allows. You can say, you know, we use that and scale up an export and scale in exports. Before even yourself. 

Speaker 3  (48:04)
Yeah, I'm not really sure. I just like Canada is a good place to export defence goods because they're free and they're ease yourself. And I'll just make a plug 2 CC for 10 years. 

Speaker 3  (48:16)
And that's a great organisation. This is enables that fine children to buy from our country. I think when you were pucking. 

Speaker 3  (48:25)
I heard the storage so often that Canadian companies export before they start to our own country, and just because our tech is so good and because Mina said it, they do performance facts in the US they don't specify exactly how the product looks. They specify what they want to achieve, which is way better than what we do in here. 

Speaker 4  (48:43)
Yeah, really have here like an options analysis phase, followed by requirements phase, followed by an implementation phase and that average procurement type of 16 and a 1 years, 16 and a 1 years for Canada to fit buying like a meet. This is fact, so it's kind of crazy to think about. 

Speaker 3  (49:02)
Yeah, respect themselves as a Frank and sign of all the competitors specs just put together. 

Speaker 4  (49:08)
All that on the purpose of being unwilling to pick quitters, and so then I think we're seeing that reform, but the come back to what's the wedge is like we're not deadia. And so 

Speaker 2  (49:21)
Sort of so sensitive, we're setting the money Anything we do with this is 

Speaker 4  (49:27)
Totally? It's totally persistent, like totally persistent. And but it's also persistence meaning an environment right if the environments going to be like, you know, conduct with us in 16. 

Speaker 4  (49:38)
And now here's that just wont-work like I know you won't pay attention, but if there's a environment that supported with a need, you know, a commercial basis within my lifetime, then it's like it creates the ability for you to push through those boundaries and be super super persistent. 

Speaker 1  (49:58)
Just now short guide there is reform coming. So, these is all accurate of the currency of things, but there is a major project underway. And one of my practise is actually one of the key people helping to do reforms of the usement stood up to do reform of innovation and acquisition rapid, but the actual basic procurement system is also undergoing a complete. 

Speaker 1  (50:25)
I'm very absolute. What you do that. But 

Speaker 5  (50:31)
I've just meaning that mean a ski takeaway here that it will be might be this lessons, you're not deadly at that. So doing the west, I think we were lucky when he was when we released our technology show images of our powder, you're such a big problem in the straight that everybody reached up basically nazo. Gee, everybody, three weeks, how do you do that? 

Speaker 5  (50:54)
So we always have demand when they didn't realise that you can eat 10 years to do that. Oh, we know that in Grandpa, the united bully. So that's the heartburt. 

Speaker 5  (51:04)
Now, the wedges from here really is that you know, is that sustainable manager? It's a bit there, canastric strategy. He said us at the very time when leverage dressed and scarce. 

Speaker 5  (51:16)
So like definition So bad, I think more and more keeping our technology Canada is not in the field. And just leveraging oh entray clipper, stress of the first move prevention. Once we're qualified, we've been qualified for onward depression can't change our products again. 

Speaker 5  (51:35)
So our whole thing is, be first, we're not set up to be second or third break in the new will be the the Imperial and industry stampardises the scale upon sustainable. 

Speaker 1  (51:49)
That's so you all see the connection of the theme right? So follow-on this first is the key performance outcomes is the purchase defence is lumpy on purchase. Long to get there. 

Speaker 1  (52:04)
US has reformed Canada, companies can get first on because we're so good because we've spent so much money on education because of our culture. We're actually really good at research and apply. But then they can't get funding. 

Speaker 1  (52:17)
The series B is missing. The series B is what gives you the ability to have the power velocity to end up with multi markets or power law distributions. 1 to 23 winters these days, especially Yes, all the Canadians at what happens, I can't get a beat. 

Speaker 1  (52:33)
They get sold to the states, right? We got a fix, the venture cap of propers from north this year. We got the $20 million check size, we're going to get that 300 million to work. 

Speaker 1  (52:44)
And if you go back and ask her more, because we worked out we did the first 3 so fast, and so well, so that's a really we need to do and if we do it right, it's super little C***, in money and I will be looking for my next job. You can we do it smart, we're all going to win that doesn't mean everybody's going So together we got a summary. 

Speaker 2  (53:06)
Hello, we're going to be around a lot of time. Maybe 1 or 2 questions from the audience. 

Speaker 5  (53:11)
Yeah, 2, but I've started one points, but I think everybody I can't wild barrel when it comes to the productivity. 

Speaker 1  (53:24)
Networks, once the room 

Speaker 5  (53:28)
Let's put my brain injury, it's online. 

Speaker 1  (53:31)
Life maybe cut 

Speaker 5  (53:33)
Chin, oh yeah, obviously you think all that you know absolutely question. So you guys have set up and I think to finance companies like this, but annoying out of my view. You probably very productive, but there are many, many, many companies that mark as productive as as the 3 tree of you are using up the finance companies that might have product services software that could enhance their productivity, making these, but the vast majority of SMEs in the manufacturing sector are not that productive. 

Speaker 1  (54:11)
So you said where's what set up to finance the inventors of the productivity, enhancing tools? The question you ask is, actually, I was just a leadership Montreal, and we have this discussion, remember, financing was available for companies adopting digital internet technologies at the Don of the internet. So maybe it signed a finance isn't my programme, but maybe it's a great question. 

Speaker 1  (54:36)
Should we finance productivity enhancement in the SME sector and AI option? Which is one of the courses? 

Speaker 2  (54:43)
The answer is yet and then it's been worked out through the do one juice component is the traditional community. Does that already? But the strong amounts on the venture site, but the majority of the councils and beyond the finance, all the way from small loans. 
