
Speaker 1  (00:00)
Right next to the Canadian baby at rdc, the coast guard gives us a really unique advantage. When it comes to real world, testing and engagement for programs like this. And as Canada's first defense innovation secure hub, we're providing infrastructure and the expertise and the connectivity to accelerate. 

Speaker 1  (00:23)
Do we use technologies that strengthen Canada's maritime and defense capabilities? So sessions, like this more, invite only sessions, things that we don't put out to the broader community are designed to foster a more meaningful engagement between end users and innovators, and we want to do that because we want to make sure that we're working on capabilities that are not only innovative but also operational capital. As we'll start today by giving a little bit of background for those who are unfamiliar with the program itself, or what we're really working on. 

Speaker 1  (00:58)
And then we'll dive into why really came carried from the innovators that and so for the past 3 years, in partnership with Dallas, Canada and Atlantic, Canada, opportunities, agency coa has been running the naval technology innovation challenges and the program is really designed to take real world challenges, put them in front of Atlantic Canadian companies. To solve The solutions are competitively selected. They are developed, and they are derised through a structured program that we put on here at cove, and that work is then funded by Dallas, Canada and nacoa, our Partners. 

Speaker 1  (01:42)
So over this time, over the last 3 years, we have worked on problems like digitizing dock aired operations working on condition, space maintenance solutions improving air quality on ships, capturing maritime greenhouse gasses, and this year we're here to put a spotlight on 2 companies and their Partners as well. Who are tackling autonomous vesicle? Haul inspection as well as infrastructure inspection and added a manufacturing for ships. 

Speaker 2  (02:14)
I and I ended 

Speaker 1  (02:14)
So what we are trying to do here is really achieve three things accelerate. Solutions for real operational challenges strengthen Canada's domestic defense industrial pipeline and give Canadian innovators a path to defense markets and bridge the gap between innovation and capability and economic components, but well to that further. So One of the things that we recognized in this program is that this provides the art that maybe an opportunity to like a risk and investment free opportunity to build test ideas with a follow-on procurement mechanism through one of the Partners through the hs contract, and so as you're engaging today with the people who are going to be up here on stage. 

Speaker 1  (03:03)
I encourage everyone in the room to see this as more than like a tech demo but an opportunity to help shape future challenges as well. And so because we want to be real Working on problems that support new emissions. So think about your days. 

Speaker 1  (03:20)
Today's your day-to-day within this context, you know where your pain points that you think technology might help solve. And break those forward to us. So please participate, you know, ask questions as we get to the end of the presentations we are looking for that feedback. 

Speaker 1  (03:38)
Today is going to be our first-hand experience for really experiencing what can be accomplished in a matter of months with the right ideas and the right Partners. And how technology can shape the future, and so we want to make sure that we have end users in the industry working together to help solve some of these complex maritime challenges. So with that, I'm going to I'm going to stop talking very shortly I'm going to introduce the next company. 

Speaker 1  (04:06)
But again, thank you all for being here. So we'll start off with the additive manufacturing for ships challenge, and this is an interesting challenge. Because when we Post this challenge, initially we started with a bit of a dream scenario where you're deployed in the Arctic, a critical component on your shipwrecks, you go to your 3D metal printer onboard and you print out that critical component install on the ship and go about your day. 

Speaker 1  (04:36)
We quickly learned through the application of actually our winning company that there are some real barriers to making that happen. And the 3 main ones that need to be overcome are first and foremost technical, but then regulatory, and also cultural and outsolving the regulatory problem in the cultural problem, there's no sense solving that technical problem yet, because you can actually implement it. So within the scope of this program, it's sort of a more of a 6 month program, what is actually achievable within sort of the timeframe that we're working with. 

Speaker 1  (05:12)
So we ended up sort of shifting the scope of the program today is not a wrap up for this project. This will be wrapping up in equal. Sorry in May. 

Speaker 1  (05:21)
And in May and presented on a demo Bay and so we'd be able to get sort of an update of a midway point this program. But Purpose of this program now is to build a framework that we can put parts through in order to find out where these where these barriers and how do we overcome the and we have to actually put a cart through this record to make picture looking fine, and we are finding them. I will tell you, and you will hear so with that. 

Speaker 1  (05:49)
I'd like to welcome Bruce Stover president, of course, Bruce oh there he is okay, here's a tall guy in front of normally you're at the top of the room. And where is Mike Scott on a movie? Mike's got from talis and mark coffin from the partner organization, which is pronounced visitors CPI. 

Speaker 1  (06:19)
So if you guys need more than one microphone 

Speaker 2  (06:33)
Yeah, my name is Machiavelli sharks, delivery. Planning team manager per talis. I got involved with this challenge when it was first looking for thousands of employees to get involved. 

Speaker 2  (06:48)
Because I had a background with The material expediting community within thousands itself, trying to source parts. We discovered all the houthis of random ships, obsolescence happens fast and trying to open up a whole new American. For sourcing, those fires became extremely strong. 

Speaker 2  (07:12)
Exciting for me, because hopefully make my life a little easier. So we when going through that selection, we definitely lean a heavily towards precise and turnover, says they're coming with an aviation background that is definitely going to speak to the regulatory problems that we foresee with getting the hearts approved to be onboard and years of knowledge of in the industry of additive manufacturing, so the problem that like we were really looking at as I mentioned. Although the brand new party ships, there's obsolescence plays a major barrier on day one whether they're obsolete because the production line has moved on or obsolete. 

Speaker 2  (08:02)
Because it specialized parts for a specialized application, and we quickly ran through the spares, and then we had. But not equipment, sorry, significant amount of retooling for those producers. We have 6 ships under contract, so we're not buying a 100 of each item in some cases. 

Speaker 2  (08:28)
Because they're meant to be permanent. So we don't really have that buying power to convince a supplier to retool and sourcing low volume, very specialized. And with that comes regulatory from buying overseas mixed with the timeline for the 2° tool to get us where we need. 

Speaker 2  (08:52)
But and again as we have at the bottom, the amount of downtime with months, or sometimes years, that's not really acceptable in the industry. So When offered the opportunity to look at at a manufacturer to fix these problems, it seemed like no-brainer and as James alluded to, we really wanted to get to a state that yeah, we could print right onboard, and even through the application process. Yeah, that's not the place to start. 

Speaker 2  (09:24)
So very excited to work with precise and drones, to really map the room of the framework to see how do we drive this culture change? As you can see on the side, it's being very collaborative. Actually, between all the groups, trying to get the data to them, to Instead, just bringing a solution to a problem. 

Speaker 2  (09:52)
Actually really identifying a real world problem for them to help us solve. And it's been what a challenge, because under every rock has a new problem, but I believe, at this point I can pass over to you. And yeah. 

Speaker 3  (10:21)
Wein burst over with precise design and free crowd being here today, representing managing I have a great partnership with animal code, but also a part of the house coast house. And actually strengthening the relationship that we've had from over 15 years and struggles, it's been pretty process. So they mentioned a couple times now, these challenges and shifts, we're not and the goal will be able to put a military print on a ship. 

Speaker 3  (10:54)
If you get what you get between parents, but it's going to be the world, I could tell everybody that and one of the things even in the application is this is the great starting point when you need to step them out to the culture cultural shifts and figure out how we can get that culture changed that we can support the technology within the program. So with that, Mike spoke to a lot of these supply chain challenges and whatnot presents as I'm just a very brief introduction as designed built and the full-scale machine shops and experiences on a whole basis. 

Speaker 3  (11:29)
On the other side of this president Virgin work here, looking to fix problems that we have to I have to solve these appointments, but we have to make it In inventory, the inventory is huge huge issue in terms of I'm sorry I understand where I find it. So the whole culture shift here is with choosing the arts, choosing parts and trying to pick the parts for the right notifications, not everything's fitting, things more than you need for that's the solution. That's not actually what needs. 

Speaker 3  (12:16)
There's a lot of there's a lot of things that go into the computer. There was decisions, so The weight of what I get affected so with the relationship with drones and the aerospace has been the metal free. Mark Turkey gets full credit to this Indian Iowa. 

Speaker 3  (12:45)
One of the things we were trying to do with tell us, specifically was try to put a survey and say, how much the team actually uses, where On the end of the process, we're treating the plastics 3D three things. So with other applications, we received back, it told the story really quick. A lot of people who are aware of the plastics are being driven as the prototype. 

Speaker 3  (13:15)
But in the middle of noise nobody will use it. So yes, for your son and plastic with less than 10% of the metal were aware of the 3 years. We've got the 2 making decisions that aren't necessarily aware of the technology. 

Speaker 3  (13:31)
That's of We got drug back right from the vehicle. And then make sure that team teams rate from engineering design teams all working through procurement teams. So this level speaks to that in terms of the information we've come back A 60% had used 3D printing less than 10D. 

Speaker 3  (13:55)
Get used a metal metal met We're even on the plastic plastic, and then you can The other the other part is which I'll speak to. It is not It's being more really accepted on the prototyping aspect, you're not changing cultures, necessarily on a prototypeing aspect. So you can see a slide and on the breaking side. 

Speaker 3  (14:23)
But not necessarily. When that is out there That's also something that we need to It starts seeing cultural shifts that people start shifting to this work type environment, but how do we communicate to the supply chain? And I'm really talking. 

Speaker 3  (14:41)
I'm going to talk to the next slide a little bit, pass the hardship. I think that naturally in the room, how many people actually use 3 new plastic? Someone went and how many people in the room would actually use the levels for me again. 

Speaker 3  (15:07)
So it could all almost reflect the numbers on the slide actually could have. So there is a full there is a full process here that open after the day that we can kind of make meet. The parts that you're looking at, and they're looking possibly here today, this was midterm project in the relationship with precise and troubles. 

Speaker 3  (15:32)
But it also speaks to the defense industry. As much as it does As much as merely optional city, it also speaks to the prototype of the ability to move When you're not trying to change cultures and movements. The supply chains are here. 

Speaker 3  (15:50)
There Existing supply chain, so this is a defense part that was breaking out that we had to come up with an obscure shape. We needed to put in on the front of it and sorry. The aluminum fell off my hand here so as a fiddle and before kind of before the shedder, but that it'll speak to the story. 

Speaker 3  (16:13)
So very quickly, we went 24 hours with the 3D with a 3D model and design in the plastic version. We printed it overnight. Got in front of our customer and this product type go around to California and Colony. 

Speaker 3  (16:31)
They've designed it. We've printed it. We got in front of the customer. 

Speaker 3  (16:34)
The customer would love what we did. The excruciating took care of the problem behind it Combs the hunting combined fairly well, which we were imagining quite surprisingly. But the real problem here is they actually want to be able to change. 

Speaker 3  (16:49)
So we through our coffin and our community cross through the trails, and they set that wound hard up our Friday afternoon. Turned it over the weekend, so they retooled, retooled, redesigned a little bit to fit the 3D prayer and Norman, and this speaks to the Taliban at charlottes and the ability to react they printed it over the weekend. We'd hope to get it on Monday and know how to turn those. 

Speaker 3  (17:16)
We had enough of a golden marathon snowstorm on Monday and I couldn't get it until Tuesday. We did have it and arrived Tuesday. We post machine and I'm going to speak to that a little bit everyway. 

Speaker 3  (17:28)
Thanks for eating printing while we're done before being comfortable here. Please go to go and stop that sin. There's fine detail and part that we're looking at, because very fine spread that the current definition won't do that fine. 

Speaker 3  (17:45)
Forever and You start opening up bearing things and start looking at other seal surfaces, especially in the marine environment. Although there was dealing Very tight tolerance is very deep, finishes. Where the bargain framework also is very big tolerances, do not really achieve that with the Ukraine. 

Speaker 3  (18:12)
So that is a very basic basic example that we're fought threatening to be done. But what I want to talk to you today is how the culture, how the culture can be involved very quickly can go into the field where people think it exaggerate a box can be produced and actually shipped. So that ended up in California in the book at least time from start to finish now. 

Speaker 3  (18:37)
Because I was literally adopted early prototype. We had great binding, great binding a break from the customer level that was able to move very quickly. All right, what we're going into on the cultural side of it There's so many with oem, perks and engineering respects and whatnot in the field. 

Speaker 3  (19:06)
These are hard hurdles to just overcome and print something in the field and just for safety reasons. Liabilities, whatever case IP restrictions I think technology exists. It's how do we start changing cultures so that we can business and accept and process and accept the technology. 

Speaker 3  (19:28)
So with that, we can start influencing our engineering teams. Our decision makers, our buyers to start using software as we speak to them right now, through this process is a great network with Canada, banks and selecting it as a software, and it is amazing. That friend Smith and I'm going to fully get out of here. 

Speaker 3  (19:52)
Brendan has actually down the slide. So I'm going to the bus right now, where he's actually down the slide. And a lot of the work here, so credit cares do run, it'll be in the back here when we're done the devil and anybody that's got further questions on the select days and solve or what we're going to just kind of show here today is the ability very quickly to be taken an apartment, put it into a software and actually give is this. 

Speaker 3  (20:18)
If you can give me a machine, then it can be done. Fairly quickly add the manufacturers not fit, but it's great to be able to have the tools to be able to put it in front of people that don't necessarily do the process out things. So Canada makes it kind of a tool And with the select day and the software run, is we have to download that part I don't think it's The madam power Adam Keller, that's a scale of model which we just saw in the slide. 

Speaker 3  (20:51)
And that's just a 3D printed car at this point, but we're going to see a full discussion, friendly software and the software kick faculty for seconds, and scores, edit manufacturing score 70% when you take that perspective from a buyer, you take that perspective from an engineer, somebody that doesn't necessarily have to pay any parts of me, it automatically gives more people on those 70% that this is a successful, and if that squirrel is a 25%, well, it's called the California, you should achieve it fabricated, well, there, whatever case may be with this 70%, it tells you that it's not a bad fitly, at any manufacturing process, this software allows you for your materials in titanium. 

Speaker 3  (21:42)
Whatever the case may be and within seconds, your routine absolutely Hezbollah score, these are tools that are going to shape the culture going forward. And a lot of people are looking to say these very quickly But they need to be adopted these types of tools. These types of tools are industry now, so I'm holding people willing to take some of these tools and work with them to leave them in here. 

Speaker 3  (22:11)
So it actually renewal, closer walk on the right hand side of that screen that gives you the heart saving as well. So if you take a look at the cost, that's cost, people who are $480 per year, and $79. Absolutely, am cost money and It also gives the movie the cost savings on. 

Speaker 3  (22:37)
Actually, so it gives them a very quick, very quick analysis. Not only as it is 70% success rate, but you're going to save a ton of money and actually have it done Bixby set out. With that one of the concerns, especially with the audience we have here today is the idea is we can't put this in a name with the universe, have the public knowledge on whether these paradigms from my understanding and perspective of what it is. 

Speaker 3  (23:08)
I'm going to represent it this way. But I encourage people to deeply dive on this, it scrambles as hard as it scrambles the scrambles. The information where it gets up a little bit to the software. 

Speaker 3  (23:23)
Representation to give you essentially a score when you're not actually losing you're not data. So that you're actually able to use tools There you go I need running coaching in the background, so some of the tools can the mainstream represents this is another tool along here that kind of represents the network around the end. That housed all things in together representing cabinets, candidates and its network of companies. 

Speaker 3  (24:00)
It would represent companies like Toyota saw on here in the university so on here and anybody who's part of that campaign would ever make some network candidate makes. There is a key for Canada banks. By anyway, what we're going to adopt this type of technology by the title, recommend, I recommend it to you. 

Speaker 3  (24:19)
A membership between 2 of the network It is expanding, it is expanding. It is a great tool to be able to say, okay, the bad technology is not in your local area. It gives you other resources to be able to draw on very quickly. 

Speaker 3  (24:34)
In access populations, other options So when we pass some herds around it and we plastic hurts, there's a little new example. When you start coming out from supply chain, aspects and punching fire, how you're into, how do they be able to fit? There's a lot of restrictions and We had the opportunity, both of some of these winter houses that are just passing. 

Speaker 3  (25:04)
Where you even started submitting a needle against that on. Once and 51 stock, there are restrictions to the end of the manufacturing And that is also a cultural piece of the teacher teams sidewise that we do fit right now, as a print capacity story, animal school material with 10 inches or 10 inches of Cuban or 10 inches by 10 inches. And then I'm speaking to some of the tools on trumans right now. 

Speaker 3  (25:33)
So mark will be better with resented for that. You're sure with them. But smaller, smaller, complicated carbons, so we take our sizes and we pick our sides of our computers home, and we dig down to material sources of things. 

Speaker 3  (25:50)
So some of these, some of these material choices that we were talking to people as we were talking to your money. There's benefits to doing a lot of the hardware materials and from the schedule instead of machinery. So you want to make decisions also around science society's shapes, complex shapes and your material. 

Speaker 3  (26:15)
The manufacturer restraints and credit card. Would that elevate the one look at it if it can be machine? At this point, it's likely cheaper to machine machine. 

Speaker 3  (26:27)
That is, to put through the AI structure. And So with all those decisions with all those decisions Those are all the all tools that any of these teams should be looking at on shooting harness. That's So some of these some of these parts right now start looking at other reasons. 

Speaker 3  (26:55)
These were all 3 parts of the considered book deaths for this process, different lifting hopes. Some of these decisions, some of the ability to move quickly, if you've got a lithium pump, this let's say for a mandate. Juror. 

Speaker 3  (27:14)
What you've got excessive certification and restraints that you're going to want to make sure you're going to do guilty is on material testing. Somebody had asked me on some of that earlier on the treaty being friend and there's an automatic come off is really helpful and it should be qualified, so it should be qualified in the same qualified design. The pilgrim, the pilgrim down the middle. 

Speaker 3  (27:43)
It was too large, and we began, it was simple, machine, processed and projected, and we started opening manifold walk. And even though it's pants, hard cast hard, which quickly signals big, it just didn't fit too fast. And machines were a little bit predicted from quickly. 

Speaker 3  (28:03)
So we've chosen on about chosen about the neighboring. Now it's a nice option before the current project looks forward with going through some of the warehouses we've gone through the trips of this point. As anticipated for any of the steel proponent, keeping out of details, we've got ports that are on angles. 

Speaker 3  (28:24)
We've done some seal surfaces and whatnot that it would be a hiring wonderful duplicated and machine process. So we are in the process right now number one in the part of education bacteria in the next stages are freed scanning. The material analysis we're going to talk to that for a little bit. 

Speaker 3  (28:48)
You start looking at the culture on the ships as an example, instead of just going to pull them from a 3D metal printer on a ship. And if we can introduce some of this technology earlier on right now, if we can put through these standards on the ships and part like this, we can stand and get some of that detailed back to a shop that can actually duplicate it, these are baby steps to much bigger pictures. So 3D scanners, people can operate them and be trained home. 

Speaker 3  (29:22)
The other thing is okay, we need material identification. You know, it shot a shot like us. Isn't going to have that Now we're going to rely on that information being related to this at this moment. 

Speaker 3  (29:33)
So those are tools that can be introduced into culture, very easy and And starting as we see, starting losing, not the people own ship but also empty at the stories of different parents that received these constraints. So it's And I'm going to return over mark source along the overview of the Senate. So one? 

Speaker 4  (30:02)
The challenges are one of the aspects is three different industries. Especially people would have to make decisions around whether they need or can use that margins around I think where we come in and where we've done and sort of a certification pathway that we You've been put together for aerospace, and we've run this part. Here's flying in the civilian aerospace. 

Speaker 4  (30:27)
It's a classroom and critical moment because the most critical momentum is And it seems like by the faa Boeing as a partner like this. Airbuses departments in that classification perhaps would mean as a partner on that classification. So it's not 

Speaker 3  (30:53)
Apparently, using to do 

Speaker 4  (30:55)
So that process that you get to in terms of creating this AI certification process. Once you have that process, you can take care of. So it's not going to read all the slides, but the problem portions of this slide. 

Speaker 4  (31:10)
But in terms of the I am a certification. There's everything from your power to being stopped. So in order to have that certified union need to know exactly how this material is going to perform and exactly whether the repeatability of this reprinted for thousands of comp. 

Speaker 4  (31:41)
And that creates a Dallas, an ultimate So it's in this environment for D and dvd. That sort of thing we're looking at working through here and you see we're dealing with I'm the engineering, multiple materials bubble. You need to know if it is possible. 

Speaker 4  (32:01)
Anybody who actually heard what they understand the material that happened. So that's the first step, and then beyond that, it's going to continue treatment. It's the geometry. 

Speaker 4  (32:13)
Making sure that the wire is designed to beg Where this comes in around is heavily around place. The castle is so we're talking about 

Speaker 3  (32:24)
Absolute questions about evidence will be 3 castles that are there 

Speaker 4  (32:29)
In terms of vessels in that important place. 

Speaker 3  (32:35)
The captain bringing that Zoe truns and squirrel being turned and starting that campaign sense that ultimately speaking 

Speaker 4  (32:55)
Has become tremendously This part here is titanium. Do you relieve? I hope here and through that that will suspend 24000 pounds. 

Speaker 4  (33:07)
So and it won't pass it around. But using this approach and this certification of this process effects, you can take that from similar airspace and readily So the fire is very high in similar aerospace. The bar was very high in the fence. 

Speaker 4  (33:31)
It didn't change. The surface or some surface Emma classification. It changes so hard. 

Speaker 4  (33:42)
That is 

Speaker 3  (33:43)
It's pretty cool and surface facility, extremely critical. 

Speaker 4  (33:47)
So it's creating this type of like a certification framework. Being able to put together a pathway that as parents want into view that are unavailable. A lot of processing that you're welcome to come and speak to this thing. 

Speaker 4  (34:18)
Is that Um, I'm I think so. This is where we are. All finished up so end of May as our final milestone stops. 

Speaker 4  (34:29)
Which is part of the certification framework part of this education piece? 

Speaker 3  (34:33)
Uh, uh, uh um beyond that. It's empty. 

Speaker 4  (34:44)
The moments of hearts that are not available. The American national defense 

Speaker 3  (35:11)
Hopefully, I'll start. 

Speaker 1  (35:16)
That's better than nothing right now. In all every now I said this at the start of the program. But this challenge that we're about to Yeah, that promote to go through was one of the most difficult ones we've had to date to select the winner on we had 10. 

Speaker 1  (35:33)
Okay. We had 7 really good applications for this, and the top 3 were very difficult to choose between over the course of the last 6 months, I am fully confident that we made the right choice. This team has proven again and again that they are resilient and fast and can vivid quickly when things come up. 

Speaker 1  (35:52)
So I'm going to invite Gordon to marine math up and their partner boys Russ is going to represent boyas and I have your clicker here. 

Speaker 3  (36:03)
Down, explores. 

Speaker 5  (36:06)
Hopefully it. 

Speaker 1  (36:11)
Thank you so 

Speaker 6  (36:12)
In afternoon. So the first question we always get asked is here's better enough. Here we are. 

Speaker 6  (36:23)
I'm probably Canadian during those buildings, gross as 2005 recent Pi, we're employed just over 20 people. We have feudable staff, also a global dealer network of what we're selling, what we're representing what we manufacture. We are manufacturers, our defacities, but also defense contractors. 

Speaker 6  (36:44)
We hope and house facilities for Magu shop, however, quoting software teams designed teams videos on all A house within marine navalny. I mean, I also control games and ratings as well as some of the tier 2 tier 1 companies and deal with, and there's some of our other products and our control rates. We're also is online intelligence. 

Speaker 6  (37:07)
One standard Voice images can choose Russell for voice 

Speaker 7  (37:14)
Hi everyone. Thank you very much. Yes, so voyeus is a company based in founder big Waterloo. 

Speaker 7  (37:21)
We are approximately 60 employees. Fun fact, we actually built and deliver the first dynamic laser scanner ever used in subsea applications, and then we've been involved in some really cool projects, such as mapping the Titanic chipwreck. As well as earnest shackletons and during shipwreck, go over the next slide at home. 

Speaker 3  (37:41)
So 

Speaker 7  (37:46)
What are a company's goal or what our motto is? A nutshell is helping to build optical sensors that enable true underwater autonomy through underwater camera systems or laser scanners. And that just showcasing some of our capabilities, your 3D models of the Titanic shipwreck from our camera systems, and then the next slide. 

Speaker 3  (38:06)
Oh, that was a perfect 

Speaker 6  (38:11)
We did seem looking this quick. 

Speaker 3  (38:14)
These are incredible athletes 

Speaker 5  (38:20)
Thank you so much. 

Speaker 7  (38:20)
I would end up here, spurnish, apples and endurance shipwreck. 

Speaker 6  (38:26)
So the main project required for this one was design the manufacturer and rv platform to do autonomous assessment of the holes for the navy. And then maybe check for an ID. Thanks in issues, you are EV manufacturers and doing it for many years. 

Speaker 6  (38:43)
The making point was autonomous. Take the diverting, a human over loop. Sometimes, maybe we can invest in those who don't know the size of the vessel in that one50 has been a model of fantastic case. 

Speaker 6  (38:54)
So we had no starting place of start point a start point B from a known point of view. We also had to create bathroom at room type 3 model, says we're scanning the side of the hall, because in 3D in a defects in a damage, and almost deep measurements. After it's been doing the main process in the field, we then also have to produce a high quality through the molecule, so after the national scanning, we can actually do our additional twin. 

Speaker 6  (39:22)
So you've got all of the measurements, any anomalies on the whole Michigan, south As well as the poor generations or any key importance, anything else? So they keep in the pilot minimal impact on the rv system. Google is still 8 assumed in the loop. 

Speaker 6  (39:43)
Someone took oversee to stop-start or just be an exercise. The underwater technology can be autonomous to a point we still have to have a human mobility and supervisor. The main point of this was to reduce time through state church, diverse, and water means you can actually get Marvel against the water quicker as sense and conditions and act twibbling. 

Speaker 6  (40:09)
If you're right around 2 diversion, maybe days or over a week rate or diverting the rv system. Again, water, operational within 1015 minutes start assessing activity data. For the talis, it was not just looking for damage. 

Speaker 6  (40:25)
It was also just assassin continuously. The condition of the vessels as well. Let me just give this one. 

Speaker 6  (40:35)
You just said most of this So as you know, having a diver in the water, there's no risk to parson or to the equipment is a machine that's an integrated survey. Also, using autonomous introduces human error if they can the rv and the software ability model. We are not going to have mistakes by a Divergent, miss something, or The door court's second area full coverage of the hall to make sure everything is covered probes the body everything else. 

Speaker 6  (41:07)
Do you have an autonomous as well? And workflow, it seems to have been a highly skilled rally pilot opening an Irv into our conditions. So it swirls these states when I see it does take something years to get really proficient. 

Speaker 6  (41:22)
And to do it in different conditions, changing I can do some opportunities here to get Harvey in to do a piece and take but deeper to time and practice to do a fully confident, good quality argument using the software that autonomous workflow is an rv teams of that greenhouse summer is more skilled, basic knowledge to do the CV. So the main architectural that we did in this system is we use one of our marine lab virus information on this terminal. It's been accustomed to upside for this project. 

Speaker 6  (41:54)
I was tying in's extra same search for the third parties so we're using the voice. A character force we're using either software suite, which a sister company on voice as well, to help us afford to talk about. As well as if V slide, which is a life through the living room. 

Speaker 6  (42:12)
There are a few other scientists about the manufacturers to help positioning everything else. So the key things we've used fuel proven technology and architectures platform fields, and we've had a solar basis being using years. And we're designed for this job Our normal arties, my death code, and hope. 

Speaker 6  (42:37)
So this challenge is enabled us to work closer to get the economy into vehicles to go to positions start and stop them scandals. Without this. We are really closely the voice and we continue weakeningly. 

Speaker 6  (42:50)
Detaining this whole detail more. The old details were software movements of the camera. A world back-and-forth years a few partnership. 

Speaker 6  (42:58)
We have also built multiple rational desires. One thing there is version 123 physicals and a lot of different design observations to prove to our fault together. So this shows with an RD company we're focused. 

Speaker 6  (43:12)
We can make changes happen quickly by a few more 70. The main thing was without is this integration of Canadian manufacturer development. Where manufacturer, a UK built an rvs, the cameras are manufactured society made up the detail. 

Speaker 6  (43:28)
Because I'm sure there's reopening and solution. Because we do live in this design and manufacture, we can rapidly prototype. Boston was in a fair shortage store Monday. 

Speaker 6  (43:41)
We need a new party. You meant. We had to come from metal painted, ready to hold number reconstruction very quickly. 

Speaker 6  (43:52)
The previous version was traveled in pbi and DNA woman. Even downstairs in New York Muslims teams were texting it to prove the feasibility, an old patient before we came over here. Yesterday to give us some data. 

Speaker 6  (44:05)
This project we've known is library. Now to ruthma, if we have a technology, a system, the architecture of free or top void our customers and defense psychoftworth. There is a food tasting fraction tame we did. 

Speaker 6  (44:21)
In fact, we proved it, we capture 3 woodlands. We proved it could build a masset of the Ship, it should be. Professors 11, this is one of them. 

Speaker 6  (44:33)
Hunts and babe is a slightly bigger finger than the one we're seeing here. We realize it was like bigger. 2 too heavy produced waves reduced the Fleet time difference between that one coming back to our shoulder. 

Speaker 6  (44:45)
That unit was about 2 to three weeks or getting next and duration. Goal we do have. Sometimes videos is just running an air, and then there are some of its 

Speaker 6  (45:15)
So it's a truly finished product operation. Only fuel operational intact. During the key criteria of the mission. 

Speaker 6  (45:25)
So what occasions when they're used to waiting to go smaller, we also did a law for the software for a Tony, so lots of Fine-tuning for the autonomous software. Because it's different working on the air. Even there, you have your GPS degree users create an underwater. 

Speaker 6  (45:40)
There's a turbine water, there's green, cloth, king position from visuals, and all sorts of sensors can be very So we've done a lot of social work integration of sensors to give us a more accurate position of who we are in the water. Part of the important realized that if you're right in the field with a vessel, I don't do a skill survey. If you give lots of data for photographry, what you're doing with the data, if you've got no internet signal cell signal and you want to create a high quality model for what you deserve it, you can give it all the internet, so we've decided your top side to be GPU processing, so even in a remote field, you can do your survey, do your scan and process. 

Speaker 6  (46:22)
It can feel remote system and design We're trying to come back up options at worst case. Scenarios, I've been open to an Arctic with coastal art. A couple types where you're up there, you're removed. 

Speaker 6  (46:34)
There's no backups. You have talked with the tools available in the work system. What does it just don't do? 

Speaker 6  (46:52)
You can go. A quick look for diagrams and they are completely. We have all the extensions of sensors coming from any system. 

Speaker 6  (47:03)
We have acquisition software to use data from the cameras. The sensors, the sonar, your dvl the sibling of water comes all in and that says the vehicles and this location officials have some dislocation. And I'm processing all the time to the individual The challenges that autonomy is really hard to alter reason, how that produce it. 

Speaker 6  (47:27)
We've tried to work heavily using the sensor integration fusion on a software to the photo option to help data on that October later, who will show you according to position a coherent weblizing tracks and do the moral system doing that. Yesterday and every year Every hole is different originally we were seeing, it had a 3D model. We could scan the hole But one was changed sometimes built. 

Speaker 6  (47:55)
So we can open the methodology, where we can scan the whole I can just out and then get the world going from that without having any previous data, we don't know how long vessels it was 20 m or a 100 m at the start of the battery, go to the stair and still be able to three people. So if you're doing your own passage, no idea if there's a form vessel or something anticipates the check, you can decide your parameters and your limits, you also want to be regarding bigger understanding one, because we're more sensitive for it. 

Speaker 6  (48:26)
Given the data. Because we're going to pick an rv, we've increased it Lost the power to reunit cold war and stronger cumins, deeper deads, everything else. We're also using the cameras to create a deeper field. 

Speaker 6  (48:41)
So as the cameras are burning, the 3 walls and knows how far away it is from the home. And so it doesn't have any collision, even in swells, or storms are an event off that will keep us steady scanned quality data. And then just a little one, is this whole show gives me 

Speaker 6  (49:24)
And all this British years taken out a task proved on Pi, because if we're gonna do everything in-house we can test. And I just thought It's been a rumored collaboration between Thomas voice enough. Hopefully over to go next so we would continue with talis and thalas customers before the customized performance to develop up the food productive solution. 

Speaker 6  (49:45)
We're also going to be constantly updating pain loads the cabinet architecture and also the iron architecture as well, really between loft testing through the sun. Although the system is one in the moment, we can do the basic key points that are fighting improvements to be made through farther fluid. Test voices launching new cameras. 

Speaker 6  (50:06)
Smaller. Light type present allows us to make the Army smaller and more portable easier to have more portable Or an accretive human rights are dealing with it here. But the mean thing is, is, if you replay the manufacturers, it's truly a designed build, manufactured tested made in cataport even though And 

Speaker 1  (50:38)
Dave Peterson from Dallas engineering change. All right, all right, it's a long title to come up and talk about the program as a whole and help us wrap up today. And look what it is that we're truly trying to do here. 

Speaker 3  (50:51)
In fact, thanksg. 

Speaker 8  (50:54)
Let's look at afternoon. Thanks very much. I had like Mike was working with the additive manufacturing team. 

Speaker 8  (51:01)
I had the pleasure working with bringing NAFTA boys on this and in 6 months, they were able to build three different prototypes. Take it to a version 12 test it in three different provinces in one state and build some sexy promotional videos, right? That's a lot of work done. 

Speaker 8  (51:22)
So I'm with the ages program for those of you that don't know ages. Is the meaning service support program for aops and jss and tau is very proud to be the service provider for that in service report for those 2 classes of ships, that program ages is unique. It's the navy's first ever. 

Speaker 8  (51:47)
The same relationship, no performance-based program. So its performance-based, it's a shared pain, shared game model. What that means for Taliban is that we have to find solutions For keeping these ships going right? 

Speaker 8  (52:05)
And if you think about additive manufacturing, where it's a crazy world out there right now and supply chains are at risk. So developing resiliency into our supply chain will enable us to help keep these ships going. If you have an aops, that's operating way up in the Arctic tens not tens thousands of miles away, not a miles away, and suddenly heads of ground only What do you do? 

Speaker 8  (52:35)
What are the tools that the crew has to be able to assess their ship? Assess a damage and feed that information back so that we have a plan and can come up with a plan to take care of that issue. So these are the different reasons that we propose these challenges this year. 

Speaker 8  (52:58)
So such great like we had over 30 submissions between three different challenges. This year we had to pick only 2 that was tough to pick which 2 challenges and then which winners out of each challenge. But absolutely happy with the results this year and very excited about future challenges. 

Speaker 8  (53:21)
As we embark on this talis, has a through its ages contract and has a unique opportunity where we have a contracting mechanism. Where we can take new solutions and insert them directly into the program. That's really important, right in that you don't have to follow all of the traditional procurement processes to get new capabilities onto your ship. 

Speaker 8  (53:51)
So as we move forward, we're going to be looking for more ideas of how we can improve and deliver capability to the navy. And thank you all for your time this afternoon, James, do you have any last thoughts or James goke? As I'm short enough. 

Speaker 1  (54:11)
So again, just wanting that go with Dave said, thank you all so much for number one, the work that you do. But also for taking the time to come down, to go over on a Friday afternoon and listen to the report that we are trying to do to support you. So there's a few ways that you can engage with the program going forward, that there's a QR growing up on the screen. 

Speaker 1  (54:29)
And is also on the inside flap of the panphyl that you'll see around here that will take you to a survey where you can just go ahead and drop your ideas of what future challenges that will impact your work. You can put those in there as many as you like. They don't have to be world changing, they don't have to be super specific. 

Speaker 1  (54:48)
But having perspectives from all these different groups across dmde helps us to shape the future challenge program. So there's you can either participate that way, you can participate in a webinar that we're hosting able 21st, also through that QR Code, come and be a judge for some of our challenges. A select companies tell your colleagues about the work that we're trying to do, like, the more engagement we can get from you guys and girls. 

Speaker 1  (55:17)
The more that we can bring solutions forward. That are relevant to your work. So I'm going to leave it there. 

Speaker 1  (55:23)
I want to make sure that we have time for questions and interactions with the companies. Marine has going to be up here, and they're going to share some of the data that they were able to capture yesterday. Precisely is going to be over in this corner here and we're going to have a little bit of a head-to-head. 

Speaker 1  (55:37)
I guess so thank you all for your time again and enjoy your address your Friday. And we get to be here 
