
Speaker 1  (00:00)
Manufacturing sector for defen. 

Speaker 2  (00:03)
Yeah, and that's what I was going to say all of my comments will be basically from the tier 2 tier 3 segment of the industry manufacturer, basically in the defense space where over the past 50 years. So we have a lot of familiarity with this, and one of the things we've noticed in the vis is this indication that they want to have 70% Canadian content, and as advanced manufacturers. I think minister mentioned it. 

Speaker 2  (00:28)
We are very good at manufacturing. Especially in the airspace field and there is a lot of capability in the investment manufacturing sector within Canada. What's some of the struggles that I see some of the concerns that I have is and we're already feeling this couple of months ago I would have said that I was concerned about the way that this hero was going to go from a Pyramid standpoint. 

Speaker 2  (00:53)
But we've seen a significant increase in partnership activity in And it's not just noise like no matter where it associated with people. Looking to partner for the purposes of potential, there are lots of purchase on this company and lots of activity and demand and what I am noticing is within our sector there's nowhere close to our capacity to support what's required. And so that's, I think, going to be one of the main challenges. 

Speaker 1  (01:20)
I have liked to come back to that because I think that's really incredibly pulled off time, and production capacity is really a key issue here in the future. Why don't you take through now? But you know someone who is very, very happy. 

Speaker 3  (01:40)
Untapped, one of the protection Think about Canada controlled 75% of the Arctic coastline right now right now. We're using years and years, we have to have the ability to move personnel equipment down to them. If we don't have the deep water ports, we don't have the heavy ice breakers. 

Speaker 3  (01:57)
We don't even have the roads in many cases to To get up to the ring of fire for reasons extraction. And so when you start to think about what is the purpose of a defense industrial strategy, where I think they got it right is the emphasis on build before a partner and buy, I read a really good up and I think by a guy named Jason Myers earlier this week, that said you can't Amazon Prime your way to security, you've got to build capability. You can't just buy it, and I think that's and I think you're banging on Jason. 

Speaker 3  (02:26)
When you think about some of the companies in the room today, I was just talking to the Canada strategic missions corporation. Guys right over there, back left. And they're doing small, modular reactors, that's a you know, it's based off of the candy technology. 

Speaker 3  (02:40)
It's tried tested a true Canadian advanced manufacturing technology for years. And years, we haven't thought through how do you actually use what we actually have at home to catalyze the entirety of the supply chain, starting with just basic energy, up to the Arctic to protect that space? So I think they're directionally correct, and it's not again about the dollar value commitment. 

Speaker 3  (03:02)
It's about how you spend that money 

Speaker 1  (03:05)
Matthew, I think you raise a really interesting point. Let me start with you and come back this way this time. We often talk about specific technologies. 

Speaker 1  (03:14)
Specific critical products, but from everybody's perspective, what are the strategic priorities around defense? What Arctic is clearly Arctic security is clearly one, but are there others that we need to be focusing on as well. 

Speaker 3  (03:30)
Sure All right, so I'll name 21. You know, when you, if you rewind 5 to 7 years, just before COVID Canada had a definitive lead in artificial intelligence. Right? 

Speaker 3  (03:42)
All of the patents were here, or at least being built here out of labs like Google, all of the best researchers were here, you know, Canada was considered to have a comparative advantage in AI. Fast forward to today, other than coherve commercialized very little right all that IP got sucked right out of the country. I think this defense industrial strategy gives us Mulligan. 

Speaker 3  (04:08)
In the space of quantum not an AI, but in quantum where we are again in a scenario where we have the best researchers, we have the best patents, we have a definitive comparative advantage living in consumer Waterloo and amongst the clustered companies and the defense industrial strategy, rightly calls out quantum as a strategic area, where Canada can win and we can put real money behind, making sure those companies stay here in commerci. Jawa is here. 

Speaker 1  (04:32)
Right? Thanks by the Glenn. 

Speaker 4  (04:34)
And I was just going to say from a critical like capability perspective, the way that we approach, defense and investing specifically is, you know, we'll often say, we don't invest in technology. We invest in capability, and this is critically important when you're talking about a defense customer. And one of the things that we've experienced, that's very misunderstood, is how the customer integrates that capability and what's driving a military customer, and it's really at the end of the day like the delivery of an effects based outcome. 

Speaker 4  (05:06)
And you know, the military for all, its foibles is really good at planning and really good at, like creating these courses of action, where you can develop different optionality and how to deliver effects based forward deployed forces and where the technology fits is military's think in terms of force, capability, integration and force employment. Concepts and so at technology generally doesn't exist on its own. When integrating in with military customer, it's going to form part of a technology stack that stack is really important to form a capability. 

Speaker 4  (05:41)
The military then applies that to a specific mandate or mission set and it yields what they'll call in the military a ttp or a tactic technique or a procedure. And that translates to a Canadian soldier somewhere in the world, doing something to deliver a tactical effect in support of their mission. And so you know what we strive to achieve in the way that we think about things is just like we military plan. 

Speaker 4  (06:07)
We work from the effect and we work backwards and so you know, I know it's not maybe directly answering your question, but what's capability, but we try to avoid the buzzwords because we don't care like they're all going to be integrated into the delivery of a capability down range. For a military mission 

Speaker 1  (06:25)
I want to come back to that because I think there is some really good implications for that around setting up defense production capabilities here, but I gotta say, here's talking to our language. That's exactly what ngen was set up to do is integrate technologies to come up with solutions that are applicable in manufacturing, the manufacturers can actually manage here. And what we found is that some people have heard you say this before that, if a manufacturer wants, if the end goal is to go from a to B. 

Speaker 1  (07:00)
And I think they need a car technology companies come with a pair of tires that expect manufacturer to put something together, so I need that tech stack, you need the full product stack to be able to do it either that or the Ferrari manufacturer only needed to scooter and couldn't probably afford to scooter in the first place? But it really important to think about how the integration and the end, the end impact that's the solution for the system that counts. But Michael back to what are there certain areas where you're focusing on and Ben machining, that you see some really good opportunity business opportunities right now for Canada. 

Speaker 2  (07:46)
Yes, there's I mean one of the things, because the original question was about what military religion, yeah, what's strategic capability should the military have and does manufacture? I can't really talk to that right. We're here to do the first of the build partner Vine. 

Speaker 2  (08:01)
We're here to build, but to something that Glenn said about frigid air, and then pivoting to build that what we've seen through the past number of decades is the loss of capability from an advanced manufacturing standpoint. There are things that we have to do in order to do some of the manufacturing invest manufacturing that we do that we cannot obtain in Canada. The skill sets not here. 

Speaker 2  (08:24)
The technology is not here, the capabilities, not here. And that's a detriment to that whole build piece. So aside from what's the military required, we need to build some of those capabilities? 

Speaker 2  (08:36)
And that's where we're focused, like that's those are the challenges we're looking at now, instead of having to go to the US, instead of having to go to Europe, to be able to do that developing those technologies. And those manufacturing technologies again or bringing them back so that we're able to actually support it. 

Speaker 1  (08:54)
Kristen erg, you're the guy that talked about the need for a defense, a defense strategy here in the importance of Bob. What are some of the critical strategic priorities that you would say 

Speaker 5  (09:08)
I mean, so why is it calling the defense industrial and investment strategy, positive defense, procurement strategy? Because everybody in the world is trying to procure things, and we've realized the things that we want to procure either don't exist, or we can't get them on the timeline that we need. Or we don't get them with the capabilities that we need. 

Speaker 5  (09:28)
So understanding that these investments are critical to achieve the effect, because we can actually purchase these effects in the way that we want them. So what are we trying to then? What's the effect that we're trying to achieve? 

Speaker 5  (09:43)
We all talk about defense investments, but actually don't think that's the effect we're trying to achieve what we're actually doing is we're investing in deterrence, because what we're trying to do is change our adversary's mind. We are investing in not having to ever defend this country. Or our allies or our Partners? 

Speaker 5  (10:01)
And that's where Canada can have a disproportionate effect. So what does that mean investing in deterrence, right? So you're investing even in deter, hence by denial, what determines by punishments without taking us through deterrence for military folks will understand that distinction. 

Speaker 5  (10:14)
But there's lots of technology can do in those 2 spaces. So if you talk about we've heard lots about capabilities where the 2 capabilities fit, it's the definition of a thread. Right, so need intent capability and opportunity. 

Speaker 5  (10:28)
So if you don't have the capability, it means you don't actually pose a threat. So we also need to do it and demonstrate that we oppose a real threat to our adversaries, and to that effect, we need to demonstrate that we're actually taking the initiative. We're not investing in effects that allow us to react we're investing in effects that allow us as a country to take the initiative, why those 10 sovereign areas, because if we're sovereign in those capabilities that then allows us to be able to take the initiative and to use these instruments of statecraft. 

Speaker 5  (10:59)
To shape a very volatile environment that we live in, rather than simply having to be able to react to that. And figure out how to do that in an integrated fashion. I mean, most, that's When I go to these wonderful events and ask the challenges that we have is that we don't have an integrated Canadian textile that so much of it is other companies. 

Speaker 5  (11:18)
So in terms of those 10 categories in the strategy we need to think about what does the actual integrated tech stack look like, and to have that integrated tech stack we of course need to develop intellectual property. The problem is, if you can look at the initiative of some of my quebec, lawyer, friends who are intellectual intellectual property business. We write, absolutely terrible, intellectual property contracts in this country. 

Speaker 5  (11:41)
So a lot of what we end up doing at an intellectual property is effectively providing government subsidized IP that becomes free IP for the United States. For Japan and for some other allies, or if it stolen from espionage to China. So we also at the same time they need to invest in really smart IP contracts in terms of what we're doing with the actual value that we're developing, we need to invest in. 

Speaker 5  (12:05)
Really smart technology, development and deployment cycles? And we also need to make sure we invest in research security, so that both in terms of insider threats as well as the IP and the data and so forth that we're developing, we can make sure we can actually protect that, because there's no point in talking about the sovereign capabilities. If we can actually protect those capabilities, the data and the IP behind them. 

Speaker 1  (12:28)
Hello, that was a good point, Peter. It's a strategic 

Speaker 6  (12:32)
Yeah, so I was this. So what discipliitary needs? So I'm going to answer from the perspective of the B ADC platform, the largest platform in the country and has multiple components, so financial advisory, obviously growth and working and transformational capital, your local BBC advisor is well aware of the $6 billion defense platform that's been put out and all lines. 

Speaker 6  (12:52)
Of business can access a component of that. So if you have a defense component, if you've identified to the to the experience of the experience calf members here how to force apply that you've done the research, you've found the context we're here to give you and help you. If that signal is available to provide capital for you to make that transition. 

Speaker 6  (13:14)
So don't forget about the BBC bear. Talk to your local rep, specifically with strong north 300 million in the 6 billion. We're focused on the net new. 

Speaker 6  (13:23)
So the diis for our purposes is as specific as you could make it, you can't go much further because we're talking about inventing things that don't existed a so we can't drill down now to my copanelists. When you're talking about the existing industrial base frigid, air banking, machine guns, all of cd, how and all the things that went on before the Second World War. That's a different question, and they're completely correct. 

Speaker 6  (13:48)
It needs to be specific. How in exchange as Yuan etc this is what happened in the states of Canada and in England just before the Second World War they went, and they had something called AV loan, which was basically, you gotta procure the contract. And then you were immediately given government guaranteed debt to go do that, we're not at that stage right now, we're trying to invest in existing identified. 

Speaker 6  (14:10)
Need and demand in a preconflic state. So that is why the investment products are simply supplemental to your existing relationship. Strong, north. 

Speaker 6  (14:19)
However, net new venture fund do all the things. So for example, we have companies, Canadian companies all I can tell you, is this things I've heard here, I wish I was at liberty to tell you exactly what's going on. But a number of these panelists identified absolutely critical strategic gaps, and there are companies that can need entrepreneurs that I've been astounded with some of them, the leading edge, how understanding of those needs. 

Speaker 6  (14:43)
They are typically their calf or calf adjacent teams that have developed that detailed understanding, but we are alive. And well with defense innovation in this country, and we've had some incredible success stories. And the last thing I'll say is strong. 

Speaker 6  (14:59)
North has the mandate to catalyze and work with and partner with Glenn and Matt and their funds and BBC has a fund of fund strategy team that also helps them capitalize their funds. And it's all coming together. It is only a couple of months you but it is moving at absolute light speed and watch out for announcements. 

Speaker 4  (15:18)
I'll just, I'll just pile onto that. Because what Peter is saying is absolutely correct. We've gone from, it's actually like pretty remarkable. 

Speaker 4  (15:26)
The speed that Canada has pivoted. We've gone in the last 8 months from uninvestable. Moratorium, don't touch it to national priority with the corresponding top cover from government and financing and vehicles to get money into the door. 

Speaker 4  (15:42)
And that's pretty remarkable. And I just, I think it's a testament to sort of the impetus of the moment that we're all sort of collectively in. And we are now You know, growing in the same direction, for lack of better term. 

Speaker 4  (15:56)
Given the realities of the world, we're in which again just turn on your TV and a hazard. I guess keep watching because it's probably not going to get better in the next couple of days. This is this is critically needed. 

Speaker 4  (16:10)
And I just think it's we're now seeing, you know, with a platform like bdc that has the top cover from the federal government and a deployment mechanism that's given permission for institutional capital to start to look at this, and it's taking some time, but it's happening. So banks are all of a sudden, really interested in having commercial opportunities with startups. Because they want startups that are going to be the recipients in this capital, to be on their banking platform. 

Speaker 4  (16:35)
So what was unbankable? Even 4 months ago were delisted or wires, posing was a banqueting process, a defense tech company. They're now prioritizing it in almost like competitively, trying to Woo these companies onto their platform. 

Speaker 4  (16:50)
So it's kind of a remarkable complete 180 that we've seen from the country. 

Speaker 6  (16:55)
I just want to follow into the way. Think about what's required specific domain knowledge about the problem entrepreneurial, drive to Go Solve That Problem. So your funding strategy should look like this. 

Speaker 6  (17:06)
And nobody does entire investment rounds themselves. So here you have 19. You have X special forces. 

Speaker 6  (17:12)
He actually has been there done and knows what it needs, whether it's communications weapons, delivery et. Cetera so call Glenn, my mandate is to break log jams to come in with extra capital and bring him and Matt in, we're not here, we don't compete with each other, we can't close grounds without each other. And you need specific defense advice. 

Speaker 6  (17:33)
That's where you get circuit capital, stack there, and then when you need to bigger, check to help them lower the risk and make it happen. Call Us 

Speaker 2  (17:40)
You know, I'm going to say something I'm giggling in the background, because being in defense for the past 50 years, we have to pretend that we weren't in defense, right pretend we were an aerospace company, even though 95% of what we did was defense. And you know, and I apologized, but bdc was one of the players that said, we want nothing to do with that, it really has significantly been powered. 

Speaker 6  (18:03)
Can you exchange? What's changed is we have ACE O. We haven't who said that's that's done. 

Speaker 6  (18:10)
We're not doing that anymore, right? Global politics changed change. Change the context. 

Speaker 6  (18:15)
Don't be surprised if the answer changes, we all do that in our own lives. So I want month in, I could acknowledge apologies for the policies of the previous government. It's not the bank. 

Speaker 6  (18:26)
It's the government and they did the right thing in the time. Their answer was different for the time. The time changed the answer changed and I can tell you inside the bank from the CEO. 

Speaker 6  (18:36)
Don't ask me again, defense. The Di IS we're doing it should that bold about Isabel and gave us the clear signal to go ahead and want our first company's as a munitions company and the announcement's coming out. Defense is now the answer because the context changed. 

Speaker 1  (18:53)
So I want to follow-up on this specifically around investment. So what makes a good investment candidate in defense field, like what do you look like to qualify? Some of the companies that you're dealing with at. 

Speaker 1  (19:07)
Let me go to Matthew first. 

Speaker 3  (19:10)
Sure, look, it's a different go to market motion when you're looking at an old script on what Peter is talking about ammunitions company than, you know, a software company, right? My traditional sax, you can stick with the company you can do growth hacking. You can help them unlock and go to market motion basically using a template, right? 

Speaker 3  (19:28)
You can't do that in defense, right? And defense is essentially a chill point that's going to be one buyer at the start, hopefully your own government. Although plenty of examples of Canadian companies will sold abroad at the floor if they can be south Canada to this point. 

Speaker 3  (19:42)
But I know Glenn's itching on this one, because he's bringing the most defense checks out of anyone on this state. But I would just say, at a high level, go to market is just totally different. And so you've got to think about who is the customer, and do these guys understand the sales motion? 

Speaker 4  (19:57)
And it's particularly important with early stage companies where resources capacity, time and your people are scarce. So you've got to prioritize? And so we've heard a lot of discussion about dual use of what does dual use mean? 

Speaker 4  (20:10)
And how do we define it? And well, it's a company or a capability of your product that can do both markets And we were to sort of sort of just joking that it was also a way of like doing defense safely in the last 10 and 1520 years as saying, I'm really a defense company. But I'm dual use. 

Speaker 4  (20:29)
I have other customers, and it was a Safeway of playing a sector we think it's really important that early stage companies address dual use as a go to market strategy and specifically do that customer discovery. Because it's going to change the way that you set up and prioritize internally within your company. It's going to change potentially your capital stack with a different threshold of investor that it's actually okay with a single customer or a defense customer, it's going to change your sales cycles, it's going to change your business development, you're going to probably want a heavily early focus on some form of a gr campaign early in your bd aspect, if you're going after a defense, first customer, we don't think there's a wrong answer, whether you're going to go commercial first or defense. 

Speaker 4  (21:15)
First, we just like to see our founders, especially again, and it's more importantly earlier, they are really focused on that one entry point. And then have a condition based pivot, when they're ready to start exploring that adjacent market. 

Speaker 1  (21:32)
Andrew, how do you evaluate these? 

Speaker 6  (21:35)
I don't think it's exactly what Len and Matt said, I look at our fund as we have 2 masters. Master one is the diis and the defense signal of applicability and everything that Glenn was just talking about a year to focus etc and have the entry point is, number one, number two, mastery is fiducial and financial responsibility. So that in 5 years from now, they don't say, what in the heck were you thinking when you invested at the same time? 

Speaker 6  (22:04)
We're playing in the net new area of capability that doesn't exist against a customer who will only buy what works and delivers an effect. So your job is incredibly difficult to come to that solution. Ours is trying to have a crystal ball and we weigh against the 2. 

Speaker 6  (22:23)
If defense signal is obviously high, we consider that if but the finance signal has to be reasonable. At that point, we can't just throw capital out against a badly executed plant under one brings a toxic capital structure. That said the defense industry at the startup stage, this is my personal comment. 

Speaker 6  (22:43)
Looks like sunniburg hospital on Friday night in the middle of the summer with traffic accidents. It's the capital structures are broken. The balance sheets are broken. 

Speaker 6  (22:53)
Yet some of these companies are operating critical components of the Canadian defense infrastructure. We come in as a venture but we tolerate more risk than most and the size of our capital changes. What Glenn and Mac can do? 

Speaker 6  (23:09)
So he looks at the company says critical. Absolutely, we need it. We need to combat this threat from that we see on the Russian battlefield et, cetera, but there's all this toxic depth. 

Speaker 6  (23:20)
There's all these other problems, it might be maybe that we bring enough capital to see that through to get the company stood up properly. But remember, defense is cyclical, so we're only going to invest in companies that we can with enough capital partnership and expertise can see succeeding and succeeding because of due use of defense, on their own, not counting that this stack of capitalists 5 years from now, available, if peace breaks out over the world policy. Will change context will change. 

Speaker 6  (23:49)
Answer will change. You. Got to accept that in life. 

Speaker 6  (23:52)
So that's what we're trying to do. So what's a good deal? We accept that we're open and we're venture capitalists, we accept risk, we use our leadership position that's our sovereign mission to try and break the log jam in the cases we can, if all work for everybody most will have to say, no, we'll try and give you a reason. 

Speaker 6  (24:07)
But that's how we see our role 

Speaker 1  (24:09)
I'm caught all you guys are all doing is not just about the investment. It's about the support, the advice there as well. Helping make the contacts the connections that are necessary to scale up Mike. 

Speaker 1  (24:23)
I want to ask you from a point of view of a commercial successful manufacturing company, and it will do even in the sector having to transform and maybe going to new mines here to new product lines. New customers as well. What do you need to support the growth strategy going forward 

Speaker 2  (24:44)
So uh U. I'mn't working out that I know you'll probably at some point get into the sme side of context, and this maybe this is a good time to sort of get to there. And I think that our sme strategy associated with helping, because I mean, really, the question is, how do we grow, how do we build this capacity? 

Speaker 2  (25:03)
And this capability to support this massive growth that's happening in the defense sector and I kind of have a little bit of a problem with the reference to sme, because to be honest with you, I don't think it's a small and medium enterprise strategy, I think it's a small enterprise. Strategy, I think that the way that policies are set up the way that things are arranged from your ccpc. Tax structure, your shred claim structure the itb structure. 

Speaker 2  (25:30)
It all supports the small business which is great. And it's great like I really don't have a problem with that. Where I have a problem is, everybody's incentivized to stay there because there's a massive cliff, once you get past $1 from going to a small to a medium-sized, you're basically going from small to large. 

Speaker 2  (25:50)
So we have autonomous small businesses. We have a handful of large businesses. We have very few in the middle. 

Speaker 2  (25:58)
And unless you're like, we were pulled kicking and screaming, because I'll be honest for 56 years, we did not move from that small to the medium, basically because we were not incentivized to do it, it was a we would be making less money. Having more revenue is a result of the way that this structure was. So I mean, one of the things I think that's necessary, because I think there are a lot of great small businesses out there we need a better transition from small to actual medium. 

Speaker 2  (26:25)
And then from medium to large, that isn't like, I mean itb is looking right now. At a 5 year sort of we're going to give you a 5 year grace period once you kind of become a medium-sized that doesn't deal with the tax structure, it doesn't deal with shred, claims doesn't deal with all these other elements. But it's not enough. 

Speaker 2  (26:41)
It should be, you know, you got one for small one for medium one for large. So that's, I think, a big challenge in growing everything again 

Speaker 1  (26:48)
No, really good point. And it's also very applicable and lots of other areas other than defense, but as well as our ability to grow here and to incentives, incentivize rather than to disincent growth as well, Kristen I want to come back to you one thing that Stephen furyer talked about, or all these new processes and procurement. There maybe you could speak to some of the challenges that uc in the not only in defense procurement, but I mean, have met Christian because we're both on a working group together around procurement of critical health products for her face a number of the same challenges. 

Speaker 1  (27:34)
But you know, what are some of the processes that maybe need to be improved? 

Speaker 5  (27:39)
I mean the way some of the suckers that are basically for the last 25 years, California has not wanted to assume political financial or reputational risks. When it came to defense and I think you heard this year from the panel, so we shifted all the risk onto the Keynesian. Armed forces. 

Speaker 5  (27:52)
And in addition to that, we piled massive accountability on on the premise that the accountability, because there wasn't really a will to spend on defense. So the way you basically shrink the organization is through multiple levels of accountability, which then makes sure you can't spend as you heard from the minister and the money that you actually have allocated. And so part of the challenge, I think for industrial Partners is making sure that we can mitigate some of the significant risks that the government administer currently facing and also taking some of these accountability measures off the government's hands to be able to demonstrate that as an industry as people are investing, we're actually accountable. 

Speaker 5  (28:29)
For the money and we're actually accountable for what we are actually delivering with that money and we're doing our best to mitigate the risk, but I also combine that with the kroller, there's significant opportunity for me to talk about that. And off that, second a sense when we have these great transactional conversations. If we play a couple steps ahead, there's an opportunity for resilience. 

Speaker 5  (28:50)
And what do I mean by that, from a Canadian perspective, we have a 3 key comparative advantage points. The first is that the ability to provide defense in depth. So we talked about the Arctic in the north. 

Speaker 5  (29:04)
Why are investments in Arctic defense? So important, because ultimately, it's very difficult to hit this country. So if there's conflict or war elsewhere, where are people going to look to the ability to manufacture and to scale that going to look to Canada? 

Speaker 5  (29:17)
But, of course, we need to be able to protect those capabilities in the event of conflict, and in the event of war, we also have the advantage of and before you talk about supply chains. We can provide key supply chain security, not just to our own enterprises to be able to deliver in the event that we need to scale. But also to our allies and Partners, what are the investments that we need to make? 

Speaker 5  (29:38)
For instance, greens, in order to be able to secure shipping and sea lands both through the Atlantic and through the Pacific for defense purposes. For supply agriculture and so forth purposes. I mean, if there's conflict in the Indo-Pacific people in Japan and Korea will go hungry within about a week. 

Speaker 5  (29:55)
So understanding what so, you know, being a little bit less naval gazing in Canada and a little bit more worried towards what is it that we can? And we must do? And that I think will turn incentivize, also foreign capital and other companies to come and partner with us when they see and they realize those opportunities. 

Speaker 5  (30:12)
But the challenge is exactly, I think, what you just pointed out, and I think the strategy doesn't really get at this strategy that talks lots about. So if the small and medium enterprises, the problem is that as I see it, those are very difficult to scale rapidly in the event of conflict. So how do we position those key hinges in the text back and in the supply chain in a way that you can actually scale them rapidly in the event that you need? 

Speaker 5  (30:40)
To be able to do that, and you can do it in a way to deliver not just for us, but to deliver for allies and Partners and to think about this broader ecosystem that we're trying to develop, that is well beyond Canada. 

Speaker 4  (30:52)
I think Christian just hit on a really important point for this audience of manufacturing, and that is a couple of key themes that are changing in warfare right now. The first is sort of this concept of a tradable mass, and we're seeing a massive asymmetry between these legacy exquisite systems that cost multi 100 millions of dollars able to be defeated asymmetrically with a really inexpensive technology. And that is rapidly, we're seeing it, play out through the use of uas encounter uas or drone warfare, or you know, to turn on your TV and you'll see myriad examples of what that's happening. 

Speaker 4  (31:32)
But it's not a sustainable model for a government to fund going forward. The Americans lost an awax aircraft in Saudi Arabia a couple of days ago from, you know, probably a 25 or a $50000 system being fired from Iran. That's not sustainable. 

Speaker 4  (31:47)
And so the change in the pivot that has to happen in the manufa, a true sector is exactly what Christian just said in speed, agility and a delivery of a cost-effective system, where you can just pump out this attributable mass to counter some of those exquisite systems, it's challenging for a government because you need both. We need manned submarines that cost 24 billion. But we should also have a Fleet of 300 unmanned submarines patrolling our Arctic sort of coastline. 

Speaker 4  (32:16)
So we need like this mix and that's a really tough sort of balance to reconcile in a military environment where we are collectively steeped in culture and like we know what works. And there's all kinds of internal politics that's going to be difficult to change that. But it's coming sort of quickly, the other thing I would suggest and really think about from a manufacturing audience, is think about decentralized and forward deployed manufacturing, if you're going to be building in support of the military customer, so we're seeing 40 foot seat can self contain, and you know, manufacturing. 

Speaker 4  (32:55)
The factories essentially that are, you know, sea 130 air transportable, and then a forward operating base, where a military soldier can actually do the manufacturer and so manufacturing as a service and forward, deploying it is critical that's equally critical in harsh environments, like the Arctic, where it's really expensive to ship and build so we're starting to see a massive trend of forward, deployed onto a frontier manufacturing capability. And there's a huge opportunity in streamlining the process, whether it's additive or immaterials or you know, powders that can, you know, forward deploy and not be expensive, like Kevin and the team in atmospheres have built some really, really compelling technologies to advance and forward deployment manufacturing. 

Speaker 2  (33:44)
If I could just sorry, then I'd jump in, but one of the things I would point out is that Canada is actually very good at some of this right, you know, one of the pillars that Canada and one of the sovereign capabilities is eoir systems and electroopical inference systems. It's one of the most effective tools being used in the Ukraine to countergrown attacks that you can tell whether a drone is carrying munitions or not, which is one of the strategies that's been used in order to do drone warfare. 

Speaker 2  (34:13)
So there's a lot of that capability. That's actually being developed and not just developed, but leading in Canada. So sometimes we look at ourselves and think we're not as good as we actually are, we really do have a lot of great capabilities here. 

Speaker 1  (34:27)
Absolutely, mathematic. 

Speaker 3  (34:28)
The reference of the gigipost set or a capability development here, as well as, you know, what we're seeing in the news in terms of modern conflict and a tradable mass. It's actually quite shocking to me that the Americans controlled the timing and the tempo of this conflict with Iran, right? They selected the launch date so on and so forth. 

Speaker 3  (34:49)
And yet, still six weeks in they're having to go to the Ukrainians and say we need your counterdone experts and in fact, we need your cheaper counter drone system. So you know, the Americans sat, they watched this war in Ukraine. For problems in weighing 3 years now, almost 4 years and still when they when they chose a new conflict timing, they were not ready for what the Iranians would throw out them in terms of the drone warfarin harassment. 

Speaker 3  (35:15)
Now you sit back and you think, well, if the Americans aren't ready for it, how would we be ready for it? I think is clearly the lesson here is necessity. Is the mother of innovation right? 

Speaker 3  (35:26)
The problem is 5 years ago. We actually had our wake up call this called COVID, and we very quickly learned Canada, can't produce masks. Canada can't produce ventilators, Canada can't produce back. 

Speaker 3  (35:37)
Scenes are running around begging other countries for things that we weren't able to build right. And so we've actually already had this wake up call right. It wasn't in the form of a kinetic conflict, it was certainly an emergency. 

Speaker 1  (35:50)
Exactly. Well, let me just kind of riff off that, because going back to COVID times there were 2 ventilators that the government purchased, one ventilator was actually already being used in the field as a Canadian ventilator used for military purposes. And that was a ventilator that a number of the number of manufacturers jumped onto said, well, we can help produce that we can help scale, that up. 

Speaker 1  (36:14)
The problem was it contained 1400 components and majority of which were coming from China, so it was a little bit more difficult to build than it did. Ah, then a lot of people thought the other ventilator that actually came into production within 3 months was a Canadian a Canadian device built by a doctor in whinipeg that has been used for sleep disorders, was an analog device who was already being used in China in Wuhan, as ventilator there, and it was one of our projects that we worked with starfish medical to take that digitize, it, redesign it re-engineer, it sell all of the components we're Canadian and build up a supply chain of probably, I think 10 suppliers and 2 manufacturers to do the final product, and it turned out actually to be brought on onto the market in a production. 

Speaker 1  (37:17)
I don't think very many units are actually produced, but it was faster to do that to reenj I near it, and it was to procure all of these components from offshore, but we don't, I think it shows the capability that we have to build kind of an integrated vertically integrated system. The product like that across the supply chain. But let's go. 

Speaker 1  (37:44)
Let's talk for a minute about production systems here. Because my first take at the her. Look at the fence strategy was that there's a lot here about technology and technological capability. 

Speaker 1  (37:58)
But A little about that building that stack that the overall capability, there's a lot about technology. And there wasn't very much about how do we produce this stuff, how do we manufacture this stuff? How do we go from maybe tens or hundreds of units to literally thousands that we would need on a regular basis? 

Speaker 1  (38:19)
And how do we match that surge capacity? In the more the maintenance and the operational repair, that would be necessary to maintain maintain the field force. So Let me just ask a general question. 

Speaker 1  (38:35)
And I think we've touched on many of this, that, how quite are some of the new business models that you see in the opportunities to do that, to build that integrated integrated production system. 

Speaker 4  (38:50)
I'll start because one of the other macro changes that's happening in the national security sector is that government doesn't have the monopoly that it used to have. And so, you know, whether you're in a military or an intelligence community or other government, intelligent, 3 letter agencies that can do really interesting things they used to hold monopoly on that piece of capability to deliver the effect that I was talking about earlier, that for a large part has changed significantly, so we're starting to see like as a service start to be an increasing new model, whether it's manufacturing as a service data as a service intelligence surveillance or reconnaissance, as a service sensor fusion as a service, the private sector are these venture back companies that are well-capitalized can move with a speed that government can't and so we don't need to rely on the government to deliver that capability anymore, you know, the best example, you know, I did 7 deployments in Afghanistan and in he 

Speaker 4  (39:48)
wanted some, you know, 30 cm imagery of a target compound. We were going to go on to we had to call back task. An a** said it would go and do its thing, it would collect the image, and it would send it to us that image that same image is now commercially available on the open source because of what's happened, with sort of this democratization and proliferation of private sector space assets, or if it doesn't exist. 

Speaker 4  (40:11)
Like Peter said, we just find the company, we fund it, we go build it, we just do it ourselves. So that monopoly is changing, and one of the really interesting business models is as a service concept as it pertains to national security and defense. 

Speaker 1  (40:27)
That's great. I'm like. 

Speaker 2  (40:28)
Sure. So I'll explain from my perspective. What I've been seeing on the manufacturing side, advanced manufacturing side, and it's been pretty much focused around partnerships and again, it's going away from this idea that the government is driving things. 

Speaker 2  (40:45)
There are sort of these partnerships that are forming and create and happening in the background, amongst all the tiers, putting solutions together from a defense perspective. So and we're to your point about how do we actually move the production capability up? There's discussions happening in advance, which never used to happen. 

Speaker 2  (41:07)
It used to be okay. We've got this program now. You need to move forward with the program. 

Speaker 2  (41:11)
Here's the requirement how much and we're moving now into something being significantly more proactive. Listen, we're going to go to the government and tell them this is the solution we think that should be provided with an Arctic capability or something like that. We don't know, you know, one of the things that we need the government to do is to recognize is that there may be things outside of the boxes of the regulations as to how we're going to structure those kinds of solutions. 

Speaker 2  (41:37)
But right now, what I'm seeing one of the most effective ways to kind of move things forward is this partnering that's happening with the private sector across all different tiers, in order to kind of meet what we think is going to be happening. 

Speaker 1  (41:50)
A lot of these partnerships are already coming together there to better. 

Speaker 6  (41:54)
Hi. I think the comments there point to exactly some panelists have said the DIS is not specific enough. And in certain areas they're correct, it's also true and can be true that the general nature is allowing self-organization of capital and resources and skill and talent, to propose solutions that didn't exist as a venture capitalist in love what I just heard, because it basically just hurt the, you know, our Defense Base is turning into vcs themselves to innovate solutions to propose and what the government is doing needs to do and knew more of is stand up. 

Speaker 6  (42:35)
The excuse me, the defense innovation agency is stood up to help with that. And there are the DND is undertaking procurement reform, and the general trends already been spoken about. I think Glenn talked about it earlier. 

Speaker 6  (42:50)
It's more about looking at what industry can do. What can you do for me? And then adap acting on a fast cycle and not publishing specs, because we know, because they don't, if we don't as venture capitalists know what the technology is capable of we have to wait for you entrepreneurs to organize then the role of the dis is to cause enough information to cause. 

Speaker 6  (43:11)
Self-organization of the real creators, which are you guys, so I think it's working, and the money, is there. It still takes time both funding and procurement, but we're in a wholly different world than I understand it. And having been in defense tangential, venture for at least the last dozen years, mostly servicing the US military. 

Speaker 1  (43:32)
Wherever you're in the Line of Duty 

Speaker 6  (43:35)
So just run guys, the signal has changed. It's R$, at least for the next 7 years. You have a massive increase in defense spending coming and you know what's going to continue till 2032. 

Speaker 6  (43:47)
Yes, you've got to do the self-organizing work in many cases, but the door is open. 

Speaker 1  (43:52)
Matthew, you're doing a lot of work to enable some of these collaborations as well. 

Speaker 3  (43:58)
I think one of the things that's smaller. Canadian companies are learning from this signal. Is that it cascades down, right? 

Speaker 3  (44:04)
So when you take a company like, you know, just by way of illustrative example, recallion, right kalion stood up, they've now, you know, pledged a $100 million. They're calling me Italian ventrics. That is specifically designed to create those new business model pathways for smbs, to get into the system. 

Speaker 3  (44:22)
And in a system that they've traditionally found it for lots of regulatory reasons and rfp related reasons. Just very difficult to access right? And so even the big traditional, what might call calium and almost grime are taking that signal from the government around bill partner by, and they're saying, well, where can we partner within the Canadian supply chain? 

Speaker 3  (44:43)
So you know, those new business models are developing in real-time, right before us. 

Speaker 1  (44:49)
It's been in Christian today, as I said you've been working on a number of initiatives and one of them was around critical healthcare products too. Where these collaborative ventures had been formed and And then kind of disappeared as the as the priority lessened around COVID. But what do you see in terms of some of the how long-lasting? 

Speaker 1  (45:12)
Well this opportunity? B 

Speaker 5  (45:16)
Well, it's, of course, we need a long-term commitment. I think just for people to have their capital, the investments that they're making pay off and being able to deliver for the government. And that's something a tradition defense is not done well in this country. 

Speaker 5  (45:27)
So are we actually willing to 
