
Speaker 1  (00:02)
Hello, are you smashing the house university? How are you pets C? And from a community, so nice to see you guys, I hope to see you guys over here a little bit busy. 

Speaker 1  (00:18)
I mean, Jordan told me that apparently he's Exactly, so I talked with them, super super nice guys that I was happy to talk to you guys more about that. Because right now I'm from the house university and as we know the supply chain is a very, very big issue these days, I'm from the electric car engineer department. But I'm also working somehow, in mechanical departments, Dr. 

Speaker 1  (00:46)
Bishop from health university, so I'm trying to work on a solution solution for the supply chain and how additive manufacturing can be product. So throughout this phase, I talk with different kind of industries. I mean, for avoiding gas, the tier ones tier 2, you name it, and I really would like to know, is that additive manufacturing can have a place where there are values. 

Speaker 1  (01:12)
Recently, I was in an event and the tallest people, and people from the defense was also there, and they saw their potential about how we can use the electric manufacturing there. But at the meantime, I targeted some industries from the guy is that actually working with manufacturing see powder actually manufacture. But we still have a long, long way to use that to manufacture, because the thing that defense wants is that they would like to install the separate printers on-site. 

Speaker 1  (01:39)
So how is your dealing? I mean, how have you dealt with those guys? I mean, have they seen this song? 

Speaker 2  (01:46)
Yeah, we've done I mean, we've put plastic punching on boards from as a trial for needy for us. It's gone through the design of A The legacy component is no longer available, so observations will be the aggregate. Which is the map? 

Speaker 2  (02:07)
We're waiting to go ahead too much to build the first one. Of the most important concepts, which 

Speaker 1  (02:24)
To prove that. 

Speaker 2  (02:27)
So definitely see opportunity. That was The obvious gymnastics problem is we're already running into absolute Listen, Tommy helps fight some operations because we're getting so 5 years in huge abstract decision. Exactly. 

Speaker 2  (02:46)
It's only going in one direction. 

Speaker 2  (03:00)
On the private sector side, it's a lot less. I think we've just told us that unprecedented backbone of this thing is right. I had lots of cameras. 

Speaker 2  (03:20)
So we've been pushing against the war for a long time. We're now only just really putting robots in place. Freedom. 

Speaker 2  (03:39)
But so we're, you know, we're at that point, and we're seeing a lot of invasion. But we're not at this point, seeing I'll just say losses remain pretty perfect prototype in the contemplative, will, in the transitions of design for benefits and But we want to be at a bank part of it, so it's all if you're pulling together. We are in Australia, have a specific view. 

Speaker 2  (04:06)
During this central excellent stuff. 

Speaker 1  (04:12)
That's fantastic, because I don't even shoot that I was talking to different kind of industries like gas and other investors who have taken the We handled those victim. 

Speaker 2  (04:24)
So all this chapter, you've seen the 6 magazine of their chatter, David earlier on because he's got. Wow, there's a company in the UK called Greek deep dot And that bill, that they felt half a dozen, massive wireless cells just outside the rest of the world. And they've been through a small family Which is a massive so now that's been done by so we're not opening up in the great classroom. 

Speaker 2  (05:02)
So, you know, he's got a treatment brought to a pillow. 

Speaker 1  (05:09)
So I think that will progress fantastic. And also, you guys Excel That there's another company you'll come out. That is Facility are working on Santa parameto, not specifically on marine side, but there are just that recertified from some kind of voyage administration, actually, as I was talking with void guys a few days ago. 

Speaker 1  (05:34)
And I told me that after 2 years they got the research pod location for the metal clause and so that sort of special manufacturing for the probably I'm not very sure about an entail loss. 

Speaker 2  (05:48)
Conversation. 

Speaker 1  (05:48)
Uh, it was super water from the Hui grate. Thank you very much. I was talking with a potler with next year, Adam sachsy So, it's what's travel bottle. 

Speaker 1  (06:01)
I mean, because yeah, I have no different name, and there was another one I cannot remember that. But there were three people that I had to take So there was a guy that was from the name side, and there was Better. Something that gets our kind of university, but yeah, I mean, because right now my idea is some kind of is just like a startup is more commodity platform. 

Speaker 1  (06:27)
A platform that can connect different kind of entities the end user, the freedom printing facilities. Some kind of the oems throughout the system to be connected together and find a good solution to how they can use it really printers. For the end users, because I talk with different kind of names in song for some kind of Bitcoin or actually some kind of different people, we do have some problems about some problems, not very massive problems, some problems about their warehousing, because the currency cannot have all the hard site and also when we are talking about the offshore. 

Speaker 1  (07:02)
Locations, it's 500 km out of onshore. If something is broken so it could be small, they have to shut down the whole operation, an asset, massive money is just going away. And yeah, this other opportunity for that, for green, new printers, but they don't have the trust. 

Speaker 1  (07:19)
They don't have the education, and most importantly, they don't have the sun level. They see that okay, if I can have the 3 printer on-site, we're going to certify that 

Speaker 2  (07:30)
Certification path, there's an even inspiration. 

Speaker 1  (07:33)
The risk is exactly what cash 

Speaker 2  (07:36)
We'll be there for support. And also, and that's the role that 

Speaker 1  (07:39)
Okay. 

Speaker 2  (07:40)
That's very much a power 

Speaker 1  (07:42)
I'm worried about this. I'm going to lie about this liable someone else. 

Speaker 2  (07:53)
Anybody else? 

Speaker 3  (07:56)
I mean you're talking about building a supply chain, so as a supplier you're going to have to take responsibility. That's obviously great. So until somebody goes down well, they've got all their homework and all the testing and all the x-rays, and all did in jail 

Speaker 1  (08:15)
Because this is a very fascinating question. Every time I bring up my idea, someone said, okay, who's liable? Think about it because it is a very big problem right? 

Speaker 1  (08:24)
I mean, you can guarantee at this point, but anyways, that was a fantastic dog for sure. We want to be touched, and thank you so much. 

Speaker 3  (08:33)
Are you doing a project on this? Actually, on developing it as a thesis. 

Speaker 1  (08:40)
My thesis explores something different about MBA. Dai, but this kind of project that I'm working with Memorial University that I haven't heard about the laptop market. The program, I think, that's 

Speaker 2  (08:53)
I've mentored a bunch of 

Speaker 1  (08:54)
Oh, really okay, the tantastic. So you know the deal. I mean, I have to interview with lots of people, 7080 people. 

Speaker 3  (09:07)
Have you not a fellow named mark Kirby? 

Speaker 1  (09:11)
Yes, a little bit negative about this, some kind of progress I have to say or is conservative. 

Speaker 3  (09:19)
He's dealt with the problems. Yeah, right? The market fall apart. 

Speaker 1  (09:23)
Yeah, my talk is, park off, man, that people are at the event, so I talk to Parker me online park mark off in person, but, yeah, I mean again they see the opportunity, what they're working on aerospace. So but they're using the aerospace sector into defense, that's why they are out, especially from the last defendant hope. And we have to see, we have to see the future. 

Speaker 1  (09:44)
Because obviously about the obstacle, since you're talking about some kind of picture last submarines that you have a huge problem with them, they don't have the audience. They don't have the more effective 80 90s, so we have to have to do the software. Yeah, exactly. 

Speaker 1  (09:59)
That's fantastic. That's good to know. Okay, so thank you, gentlemen, that was good. 

Speaker 1  (10:02)
One. 
