
Speaker 1  (00:03)
How are you? How many time 

Speaker 2  (00:08)
So I was just talking about people over here, and they introduced you to guys to me that how you can some kind of implement the AI into 

Speaker 1  (00:24)
Yeah, so we're a services company. We used to work in private Silicon Valley style, Starbucks. Until AI kind of became a thing, and it became very apparent, really quick that AI has nothing to do with products that has nothing to do with technology and everything to do with humans. 

Speaker 1  (00:40)
So we left me and my business partner, kind of left that, you know, traditional startup, world and technology, world. And we created a product diagnostic training organization, so we then partnered with excellence in manufacturing consortium. In Canada, 1500 manufacturers across the country, we had developed a boot camp. 

Speaker 1  (01:01)
That was just designed again frontline workers, people that had managed spreadsheets. I know your problems and feel your pain and get them from 0 to 1 with AI. So we, in doing so we really embraced open source technologies. 

Speaker 1  (01:15)
A lot of people would come to our root camps and they wouldn't have access to AI. No their company had bought it yet. And didn't want to spend a 30 bucks a month. 

Speaker 1  (01:24)
We learned how to set up a server in Canada, install free and open source tools and then hit private AI endpoints. So that we can create an entirely understood chain of custody of your company data so that we can get away from company policies that say, hey, we bought everyone Chad GPT. But don't use company data. 

Speaker 1  (01:44)
All right, because we think if you do that, you're missing the point of AI. Right, because unlocking your company data is literally the point. So we've really morphed into, like an enablement company where we can train your staff, we can help you develop a North Star. 

Speaker 1  (01:58)
So like you're strategic direction with AI so training, we call it strategic intelligence, that's what people who work on the business workforce, intelligence is people that work in the business. And then data intelligence, that's telling you, unlock everything is really kind of setting up your database appropriately. So that's in the training side over here, how do we do this? 

Speaker 1  (02:19)
In a way that you know isn't compounding costs. So how are we not just buying software from vendors? And that's where we look at we've partnered with infrastructure providers in Canada that have sovereign servers. 

Speaker 1  (02:33)
So not a us controlled like a Microsoft server. It's like from ovh cloud. Who's a French company from France? 

Speaker 1  (02:40)
In a revolutionaries, they're sovereign from the start we work with a couple other former crypto companies that are repurposing more hardware to do AI hosting now and we help you set up something that looks on your balance sheet. So this is an asset that's your company. It's an instance that only you own, and then again, we kind of keep that going and we teach you how to find 2 models to get business results that's dealt. 

Speaker 2  (03:02)
Assembly resources you talk about the sovereignty has obviously influenced all so on. Yeah, they would like to find a review. The defense but they don't trust activity and other kind of thing they cannot just kind of Egypt all of those Datasets without necessarily. 

Speaker 2  (03:15)
Hey do something for the studio. 

Speaker 1  (03:17)
Exactly. 

Speaker 2  (03:17)
I will sell your data. Just give it to me right? So that's pretty fascinating. 

Speaker 2  (03:22)
I mean, it's 

Speaker 1  (03:24)
Yeah, so we are we're part of a consortium that's putting together a thing for project borialis, we're from London Ontario. So that's where they do a majority of Canada's drone testing. So uav testing and test pilot training, they need sovereign infrastructure, so we're starting to lay the groundwork for that. 

Speaker 1  (03:42)
That's something that's happening locally. In terms of defense, it's still more the work we train a ton of defense companies. And we train hundreds of manufacturers in the past 2 years, so I work with a lot of defense companies who are still kind of stuck with controlled goods data like things that have ig in it, you know, from their suppliers or their vendors and things that they just can't share. 

Speaker 1  (04:04)
Obviously this is the answer. But everyone's so busy, and I think like we're still there's a small there's only about 1% of manufacturers that I've experienced in Canada that have a clearly articulated goal for the business with AI. Like, here's what we're going to unlock. 

Speaker 1  (04:19)
Here's why our lives are going to be better. Here's how we're going to here's an abundance mindset, and what our business will be in the future. Most defense people are like they kind of have analysis paralysis right now, there's great minds that are telling them they need to do these things. 

Speaker 1  (04:34)
But they also, when they call their trusted advisor that trusted advisor tries to sell the Microsoft, which is, you know, what I mean, like. So like there's just not enough, you know, we're not marketers like we kind of you know, we do a lot of work at EMC. And they've built a great platform for us, but I think defense needs What does that guy say from Siemens? 

Speaker 1  (04:55)
This morning, their leadership that really knows how to understand the AI and really say, here's how we're going to satisfy our Department of Defense data requirements and here's how we're going to implement AI. But again, most of the leaders I've worked with from the defense industry are like buy ChatGPT for everyone. Check all the boxes, don't use company data. 

Speaker 1  (05:16)
So that your staff is just limited to emails, and that single player productivity, that'll never trickle up. 

Speaker 2  (05:29)
I don't know 30 miles per hour break. The record is something I mean, that's so fascinating that I'm doing my PhD right now. And I'm super engineers, but in some kind of engineering, especially electrical engineering. 

Speaker 2  (05:46)
Most of the time use classic control books, the controllers they're okay. They're still working fine, but then you're talking about these days, which are then you have all of those renewable energies. And everything is getting connected. 

Speaker 2  (05:59)
You cannot do it at meeting normal controller or in a normal human so you need the AI to be side by side. So I'm trying to work on that, but one of the issue puts out only by some kind of use case I'm using it for my own use. I mean I'm just using chat to speak again. 

Speaker 2  (06:13)
All of that, there are just some kind of llms are trying to get more moving the agents using some kind of an open clothing. I really want to discover open close fascinating and also try to use that maybe in other sectors, using it in actual industry, like using it beside adequate, manufacturing advanced manufacturing in use cases is a lot every time I wake up, I said this is a new opportunity we have to do that. But education, it's about that. 

Speaker 2  (06:42)
I mean, people, I mean, are really appreciative to let you go talk to industries, so that this is a guy. This is, you can use it is more than ChatGPT. Actually, guys, you don't have to have your plan to Mexico. 

Speaker 2  (06:54)
You think ChatGPT use it for another? So passionate about this kind 

Speaker 1  (06:59)
Thank you. Let me show you a partner, meet and poultry Ontario. So meat and poultry Ontario, you can imagine an operator at a meat processing plant to make it sausages big yellow gloves on. 

Speaker 1  (07:13)
But you can also feel good as a Canadian that we've got federal regulations as to how that person can actually do that job, they have to take temperatures every so often they have to do nitrate checks. They have to cook it for so long. And all these days, so the meat and poultry Ontario came to us and said one recall like if somebody doesn't write down a critical control point during their meat, making process like it just costs 30 bucks or $30000 to open the door that recall will probably be a $100000. 

Speaker 1  (07:42)
But it's like minimum 30 grand so the second thing is the workforce. It's hard to train people on how to make this so like. Can we find tune a model that does two things guide somebody through the process? 

Speaker 1  (07:57)
And it also passively just saves the data into an SQL database. So we spun them up a server. So here, let me get the right one here. 

Speaker 1  (08:07)
So we spun them off a server and we installed an open source so that this looks and feels like ChatGPT. This is open source this we own this. Yeah, this is not our server. 

Speaker 1  (08:18)
We don't pay for this yet. Yeah, open web UI. So if you've ever worked with Obama, this is the Obama friend, so they separated out the project so that open webui is its own thing. 

Speaker 1  (08:29)
Now this is this what's that? Oh, so we pointed at so we point this at where things can be true. So we pointed out all kinds of open source models, so we have like Queen and here So, DeepSeek GPT, open source. 

Speaker 1  (08:50)
It depends on your model. That's how fast 

Speaker 2  (08:54)
So we are talking about the 7 billion parameters are huge. 

Speaker 1  (08:58)
A 120 billion parameters for free, right? So it's 

Speaker 2  (09:02)
You have to have a device that actually can handle that right? So how do you 

Speaker 1  (09:07)
So first of all, we use ovh and ovh provides AI endpoints for free. So ovh cloud, we just plug in the ap 

Speaker 2  (09:14)
I think what's happening 

Speaker 1  (09:20)
Your virtual private machine. So we're spinning up computers, it's just there in the clou. So you're just putting security onto the file wisdom, the same way you put security onto like your firewalls, because it's the same, but the difference is. 

Speaker 1  (09:40)
If you're using chatgp, so this is a computer application that hits AAPI endpoints. ChatGPT is a computer application that hits API endpoints. So there's a black box still there and ChatGPT. 

Speaker 1  (09:51)
I've done an experiment I've taken Oprah web UI ChatGPT and I've pointed open web UI at GPT API. I say, tell me about lean manufacturing. This gives me a very deliberate answer. 

Speaker 1  (10:03)
I go to ChatGPT, say, tell me about lean, manufacturing, same prompt and it's like, oh John, what a brilliant question. Like pumps, my tires and stuff. So yeah, all of these are underpinning models. 

Speaker 1  (10:17)
So again, there's no tokens, no token limits. No use no token limits. So there's in context there is, but like it's not monthly. 

Speaker 1  (10:24)
Nobody throttles us. We just pay for the access to the API. Right, and it's unlimited usage. 

Speaker 1  (10:30)
So an operator just comes in and says new batch. So this is connected. Directly to an SQL database. 

Speaker 1  (10:36)
So then the AI actually should go away here, cursing the demo I might have to read, just refresh my page here quick. Can I turn the Hotspot off? That was the problem. 

Speaker 1  (10:50)
Okay, let's get the hotspot going. Whoa, it was really 

Speaker 2  (11:03)
Other things are not 

Speaker 1  (11:10)
Some things. Go back to So gradu. So I come in here and I say new batch. 

Speaker 1  (11:24)
He has an operator it goes over to the database, says, what products do we have to make so I could be an operator off the street. I want to make number five, so that's summer sausage that we're gonna make. And that's like, how much raw material do you have in the meat? 

Speaker 1  (11:38)
So I'm going to say 12.6 kg. And then so it's going to go back to the database. It's going to create me a unique code of the batch I'm working on. 

Speaker 1  (11:49)
It's going to mark it as in progress. It's going to grab the 1 kg recipe for this batch. And it's going to scale all my ingredients to be enough. 

Speaker 1  (11:57)
So now is the operator it's just like, hey, go weight. Your ingredients and tell me when you're ready. So I just say yes. 

Speaker 1  (12:04)
Hey, I'm ready to go, and I was going to say, okay, Step 1 Where do you meet? Okay, go done? So now it's done those two things. 

Speaker 1  (12:15)
It's guiding the operator through the process of actually making the me. Okay, grinding the meat done soon. We're gonna start to get into the government regulation. 

Speaker 1  (12:25)
Where, okay, so it's gonna tell me what I have a critical control point. So, remember what step it is today. Because maybe step 5 or 6 okay, well, I got a load of the sauce. 

Speaker 1  (12:42)
In the plastic, moon also are involved in reflection programs for the univer. Okay, all this to say when I get done. When I get done, making the process and going through, we just spit out like automatically spit out this automated report. 

Speaker 1  (12:59)
Here's what I made the product. It's completed here was the ingredients that I used. Here's all my critical control points. 

Speaker 1  (13:07)
Here's the instruments that I used for those critical control points. When they were calibrated, did I have to take any corrective actions? Here's how we cooled the meat and all the operator had to do was go through the process. 

Speaker 1  (13:20)
They just had a text message with AI. And this was all created an at the same time. We can see like in our database. 

Speaker 1  (13:32)
Just give me a second change. My sword order here. Look at 12.6 in progress. 

Speaker 1  (13:40)
That was the one you and I just made, so it's saving all this data. As it goes along so when we think about like when Brock and I talk to people about AI and everyone's like, yeah wait. I rate my emails and this stuff and we're like, dude, data, data collection, data management process management and data analysis. 

Speaker 1  (13:59)
That's the unlock of AI. There's a future in a couple of years, when you come into work, I believe this wholeheartedly this is the interface of the future when we come to work, no more logging into the CRM. And then this and chat and this it'll just be we talk to AI. 

Speaker 1  (14:16)
We talk to humans and we talk to documents period that'll be the future. 

Speaker 2  (14:22)
It's open source. I 

Speaker 1  (14:24)
Yeah, we own this too, like we own it. The only thing that we're like is the we pay for our server. Obviously, and then we pay for our access to the API endpoints. 

Speaker 1  (14:34)
Right? But you've got to pay for that. Anyway, we could spin up our own server for and start doing stall Ava. 

Speaker 1  (14:41)
Maybe download some models from hugging piece and bring them over. That's the next step. But right now, ovh makes it so easy, like they've got these infinitely scalable endpoints. 

Speaker 1  (14:51)
So we could have a 1000 users. We could have one user, and just all this one. Cloud is my friend. 

Speaker 1  (14:59)
They are Ovh cloud so ovh cloud, so these are This is the infrastructure provider, so they have a data center in Montreal. They have in Cambridge. They have 40 data centers around the world. 

Speaker 1  (15:15)
It's just these guys are French revolutionaries, man, they're in France. They've been doing this for 20 years and they saw where Silicon Valley was going hyperscalers, and then government overreach, and then like the 2018 cloud act that says it doesn't matter where your data is stored. If the US government controls like if it's a us company and the government wants the data, they get it, it could be in a Microsoft server in France, but that doesn't matter the US. 

Speaker 1  (15:40)
Government gets that data, so these guys are all about. Sovereignty, it's built into the core of their business. So this is where we get our servers, our dedicated servers. 

Speaker 1  (15:49)
But we also get our AI endpoints. So resources from these guys, these guys are the best. Yeah 

Speaker 2  (15:56)
For gas equality, I'm also looking for a crowd for myself to deploy that open quarter things 

Speaker 1  (16:02)
Yeah, yeah, yeah, so I'll show you what I do. So when I spit up a server so you gotta go in here and create either probably on their public cloud, create an instance. And then I go and I'll show you 15 new development like, do you know? 

Speaker 1  (16:16)
Oh, no I guess he's clothed so when I get a server spun off. I install easy panel, so this is one command line. When you get it. 

Speaker 1  (16:32)
So this is one command line that you'll gotta do like a password protector so I install this one open source program called easy panel. Okay, that's all I install on my server. And then I can put in open web UI. 

Speaker 1  (16:51)
I have a bunch of different databases or watch this So if I want to install a new piece of software, for example. I'm sure all the different open source. So I can just point and click and install it. 

Speaker 1  (17:07)
So these are all the open source packages. Once you say open claw. 

Speaker 2  (17:11)
We have 

Speaker 1  (17:12)
I like them, that's open web UI. That's what we use. So I can click it and install it right now. 

Speaker 1  (17:17)
And then just figure out a plug it into your AI. Somehow, and we're good to go Yeah, it's 0, it's free, you know, if it's horse, easy panel itself. 

Speaker 2  (17:28)
I don't know anything. 

Speaker 1  (17:29)
I'm like, yeah, dude, easy panels, open source, and it's a container management software that these are all open source. Softwares, so like our slack and our company, this is open source. This is matter most. 

Speaker 1  (17:43)
It's better than slack. Like in a lot of ways where we own it, we control it, it's on our server and we don't pay a cent for it. Our CRM, open source, buddy. 

Speaker 1  (17:52)
The future is open source out and everything. But when a guy like me, who can do this stuff? I just use clothes to help me cloud. 

Speaker 1  (17:59)
How do I do this? And it's like, you know, log in here, right? This command line and then installed this and I was like it's over, I'll never buy something. 

Speaker 2  (18:07)
I've got this guy. You're just sorry. You're both pieces of pen, right? 

Speaker 2  (18:12)
So then you have the API probably comes from both the ov and everything is free. This last probably just correct some kind of the Chatbot, or the Telegram or WhatsApp, or anything you do some kind of communication with that. Yeah, that's fantastic scalp. 

Speaker 1  (18:29)
So now everything's free again you have to pay for your server. Yeah, so by your like for your server. And your API endpoints, 70 bucks a point Max, and you can deploy There's so much of any sense if you want to design, like actual repetitive agents and so on, it ends powerful workflow, automation like go to Google every morning, look at my emails like it's etc. 

Speaker 2  (19:02)
Fascinating, because I like me, I don't I don't ADHD and sometimes marking concentrate, that's where I'm working different kind of ais. And recently, I've resumed local, killing this fascinating driving PDF every morning. I just listened to podcasts and said, okay, I know what's the thing that every time people come to this work. 

Speaker 2  (19:25)
Where is your feelings now in electrical engineer? But you know, I'm superhero, but yeah, it was fascinating. That was very fantastic. 

Speaker 1  (19:42)
Boarding is holding it higher So listening to it 
