
Speaker 1  (01:58)
Hello 

Speaker 2  (01:59)
Hi, good morning. 

Speaker 1  (02:02)
How are you? 

Speaker 2  (02:03)
What are you do? 

Speaker 3  (02:04)
Go again, not So how you are handfacked, right? 

Speaker 1  (02:09)
That's exactly. I'm a holex, yeah. 

Speaker 3  (02:12)
Um, and I don't know how to prone athlete in mind me. Oh 

Speaker 1  (02:17)
Oh, mine it oh, it's Hood, yeah, I mean, I mean it's a little bit hard to pronounce because of the AND between. So that's okay. I mean, I don't know what are you lucky. 

Speaker 3  (02:25)
It's weight, can you try it? 

Speaker 1  (02:27)
Um, so I guess I real. 

Speaker 2  (02:30)
Yeah, no, I'm quietly in O 

Speaker 3  (02:32)
Okay. 

Speaker 2  (02:33)
I've been basically Halifax, wasn't here for a project, so it's been one year and a 1 doesn't here for a project. So once you're basically based in Halifax, we consider ourselve Halifax, based company 

Speaker 3  (02:47)
Worried, yeah, I'm just curious. That's because me exactly. Tell me Mat I think there's like you are locating in different place right now. 

Speaker 3  (02:56)
So I want to make sure I deliver messages, you know, maybe I can start with introduction a little bit about universal Scotia, so how familiar you are, but the quick overview we are a crown operation promotion crown operation. So with a target to support business, another based business to look support economic growth. So 3 parts of the job one is the staff sky, like which I am like on the staff we have grants and accumate investment funds to fund investment incubitors to support our staff. 

Speaker 3  (03:43)
The other part is to follow more. Establish business momentual business, so we have a group to support their expart to increase their productivity. Such steps and the other like the third part is business attraction and for those large uncorporate. 

Speaker 3  (04:07)
If they want to relocate it and open a branch office very scructure. So that's a business traction, investment traction. So basically 33 things. 

Speaker 3  (04:19)
So all about next supporting local economic growth. For my team is winter capital, so I'm on the winter capital team. We provide act investment to local, like early stage, deptech of companies with high potential to grow quickly. 

Speaker 3  (04:44)
Basically, AI companies Soldiers, yeah, have our audit sector not only AIC T but also like labsence can intag oceans space myself is, I believe food, a groupful, industrial bio agricultural agricultural, like this kind of basically area like all the sectors that can be beneficial to the province. So I think I made my home. II want water, I'm likes and the IP session. 

Speaker 3  (05:14)
Yeah, we do work very closely with all the other ecosystem like all the other Partners, no Scottish is small, yeah, so I'd like to yeah, I'm glad I send a message to curious to know more about what you are working. 

Speaker 1  (05:30)
Yeah, for sure. Definitely. I mean, probably. 

Speaker 1  (05:32)
I mean, I let me have a little bit introduction from my side. I mean, my name is manhood. Yes, sir. 

Speaker 1  (05:38)
I'm doing my PH adul Hause university, and around 2 years ago. Aliza, I mean, is in this company alone tech company we came up with an idea about how we can help the supply chain management to become more efficient, so related to that we try to focus on how we can use additive manufacturing and 3-D printer on this side, so related to that, because algorizza is also working with The company that is focused on 3D printers that they can sometimes obviously he will talk more about it. By the way, we made a presentation for you. 

Speaker 1  (06:14)
You have time for the some kind of maybe you're 15 minutes of 

Speaker 3  (06:18)
If you if we want to go through this quickly, yeah, all we can start as what you'll ask like if I can help if I need to go through the yeah. 

Speaker 1  (06:28)
Okay, that's fantastic. So it will be better to skip just to add a result and talk about it more in detail allowed with fantastic. Yeah. 

Speaker 3  (06:34)
I think you'll make very good on the email like you, how you'll address the problem. You are working on the solutions and current stage this basically all the information I need, I want to know like, what kind of problem you are working on. And what's the product you have? 

Speaker 3  (06:51)
And yeah, you would talk to your customers, and that's good. Yeah, and so um, I think we can. We can just start with questions like Example um yeah, but maybe when you've finished the introduction if you want. 

Speaker 1  (07:10)
Areas what you want to move forward. 

Speaker 2  (07:13)
Yes, sure, so my name is Ali. I did my PhD at dal housing university and 3 years of post draw floorci at dalas university. My focus has been always on addity, manufacturing and metal twideprinting and lloit mah mentioned, so we are trying to help Different industries to facilitate the adoption of this technology to the printing to help resolve some of their issues with supply chain management. 

Speaker 2  (07:43)
So we have a software. We have developed the software. It's in a minimum viable product stage right now that can help them manage the supply chain by benefiting from addive manufacturing. 

Speaker 2  (07:59)
Or metal to the drinking. So Being able to secure some funds so far to get some internship for matmood and another intern, and also your successful in getting accepted to the lab market programme being done by Mahmood. So at this point that we had a lot of customer discovery interviews Uh, find out a lot of morning about the actual Needs of the customer and adjusted our methodologies and hypotheses. 

Speaker 2  (08:34)
And And meaning, revival, products based on their feedbacks and insights that we got through these intensive customer discovery process. And at this point in time, we are hoping to be able to primarily Higher matton and Hopefully, another inter to turn this minimum viable product to a commercial product. Uh. 

Speaker 2  (09:06)
So we want to waste all the time. And energy that we spent so far and these product, because from technical perspective, my who is the lead on this project because he's an expert in AI and software development and stuff like that, I have industry, knowledge. And I know the customers and what they would need, actually, with man who is the one who is actually doing the work on AI and suffer development. 

Speaker 2  (09:33)
So this is a stage that you are at But if you want, I can provide you like fighting. I mean it's partpoint presentation for you. 

Speaker 3  (09:42)
Yeah, sure. It's yeah, of course. Yeah, because I feel kind of so your background is working on as a consulting company to help industry adopt the 3 printing but the product of the service, the solution you want to talk about Brexit company wants to talk about today is it's different. 

Speaker 3  (10:04)
It's soft nowhere. It's a platform to sold them. 

Speaker 2  (10:10)
And this suffer will essentially is doing the job. It is facilitating the adoption of this technology because they would need a suffer death, we believe it's an ecosystem that connects open entities that needs to come together. So that actual 3, the printing can help resolve the issue because by only buying it 3 deprinter, you're not adopting the technology because there are different entities that needs to be interconnected so that the workflow can go forward. 

Speaker 2  (10:45)
Right? So I'm going to share with screen up. I think you are the one who set up this meeting but I don't have access to share my speaking. 

Speaker 3  (10:53)
Yeah, yeah. 

Speaker 1  (10:55)
Well, actually, in Geo is yeah 

Speaker 2  (10:57)
It's not okay, okay. 

Speaker 3  (11:02)
Okay. Thank you. Both kam hasn't if you want to share here? 

Speaker 2  (11:17)
I'm going to share my second scheme. I guess you can see it now. I'm going to turn it to a presentation mode. 

Speaker 2  (11:23)
Uh, I just keep you a second. It's all good now, so you can see my screen right now, right? That you have my laser pointer here, maybe it can help a little bit so okay. 

Speaker 2  (11:34)
So we are all of tech and like I mentioned we are a company that is helping industries to adopt through the printing technologies to help them manage their supply chain. So this is our team, the founders, including me, the PhD, and manufacturing from dollhouse. And my all the PhD and IT manufacturing from dollhouse, so the advisors we have technical advisors, Dr Alina, Siri, from the mechanical engineering department with the focus on added manufacturing. 

Speaker 2  (12:08)
We also have doctor harmed Ali, who is an assistant professor in the department of electric computer engineering. We have 2 in termsmood and Mathe, they're both in electrical engineering department. They're housing. 

Speaker 2  (12:22)
And we have some support network with some mentors to our previous customer discovery process. So what is the problem that you're focusing on? We believe generating all industries and especially rmote industries. 

Speaker 2  (12:38)
They have issues with their supply chain, mostly it's remote industries, they have they have limited access to their physical inventories. Just as an example, just imagine an offshore oil and gas platform. So If apart fails during the operation, then they need to they need to ship a new part to be replaced. 

Speaker 2  (13:01)
So they have 2 main options. They have chopper or drones or helicopters, which are fast, but they're costly and they can carry only light looks and they also have supply vessels which are cheaper and they can carry heavier loads with their various low. And this is where the issue comes from lead time. 

Speaker 2  (13:18)
So, just imagine if the part is critical, then it may result in process shut down, and they will end up costly down times and also safety concerns. So we have some customer discoveries. So for example, G oil and gas is that there is up to $88 million downtime, costs and money? 

Speaker 2  (13:40)
An also equinor is mentioning that in order to reduce these downtime costs, they build large physical inventories in order to keep the parts in the physical inventory in case they need it. So it's just in case philosophy, but $4.5 billion is unused. $4.5 million of these physical inventory is unusious 80% of their inventory, so there is a big cost involved for having these physical inventory. 

Speaker 2  (14:13)
So what our suggestion or our solution is to shift from just in case philosophy to just on time philosophy, which means that if you equip yourself with metal tree, the printers and a digital inventory, then whenever apart fails. You can just print it Time just finished where you need departing instead of buying them and assorting them in physical warehouses. So if we'll reduce the lead time, it will downsize your warehouse so that your inventory cost will reduce significantly so you have flexibility in your design. 

Speaker 2  (14:54)
So the parts there are parts that their design changes over time and they become absolute. So this is not going to happen anymore. You can Now, replacement of your parts using this technology instead of replacement of 100% of the worn or damaged part. 

Speaker 2  (15:12)
And also, you will reduce the carbon footprint by reducing the transportation significantly. So What is the legacy supply chain? What is the competitor or the solution that people are using right now is buying these part through original equipment manufacturers and we have started them. 

Speaker 2  (15:33)
They're very strong. They have very established business cases with their customers. They have long and lasting relationship. 

Speaker 2  (15:41)
Let's also and most important one is that they already have all the certification stamps so that the end users trust them easily and buy the parts from them. However, there are some weaknesses, so longly turns no desire flexibility, high carbon footprints, so based on our understanding and the results of our studies and research on the market, it's very difficult almost impossible to compete. And remove the original equipment manufacturers from the market. 

Speaker 2  (16:13)
So that's why in our ecosystem, we make it possible to bring them to the business and make them new general revenue generation avenues so that they can join us and we can work all together. So we will bring New avenues for them to make money so they are platform or our ecosystem works. It will connect all the entities needed to be connected so that an apart end, user can actually print and use a part whenever they really need that part the way it works. 

Speaker 2  (16:55)
Is this digital inventory software will connect the part and users to the oems to the 3D printing centres and to the certification authorities? So how we deal with that competitors and bringing them to the table to work with us is that we offer them. Okay, you guys right now are selling your physical parts. 

Speaker 2  (17:19)
This is good, just keep doing it, but we are going to bring up new windows for you. Now using these ecosystem, you can also sell digital parts as well. So it's a new revenue for you. 

Speaker 2  (17:31)
So how it works in order to protect their IP of the design of the parts so we will ask them to put the cat files of the parts on our digital inventory. But it is safe and secure. No one has access to So the part end users whenever they want to print apart. 

Speaker 2  (17:52)
They will send a notification purchase. Order request to the oem, the money will be transferred to the OEM and then they then when it happens. The digital inventory suffer will release the cat file only one time. 

Speaker 2  (18:08)
So it's going to be only one time use from that cat file. So there's 2 options. Now either the parts and users has the trendy printer on-site so that they can print, or we can connect them to 3, the printing centres that are closed to them. 

Speaker 2  (18:26)
So let's say there is different 3 printing centres closed like in Atlantic region. So we will identify a lot of them. We'll join them all together to this platform. 

Speaker 2  (18:36)
And whenever a part comes off and when the design has been purchased from the ON by the part and user, the part and user can use the printing centres to print that part, but the certification authority is also connected to this ecosystem. So there would be some certification processes monitored and controlled by the certification authorities. So everyone needs to give a green light so that the part can actually be printed by the part and user, and it includes the oem certification authorities to the printing centre and us as the code. 

Speaker 2  (19:14)
And then the part user can print the part whenever it's needed. So this is what we actually Affair, so and also I'm going to show this very short video Give me a second. Ensures how metal food printing or added manufacturing actually works it assorts with a cat file and then it is a slides to very thin layer. 

Speaker 2  (19:44)
And then these cat file will be transferred to emmatal through the printer like I mentioned either the part and user can add the technology or it can be connected to our platform to the Tilly printing centres and then laser will A melt? A bit of powder layer by layer According to the cat 5 and then print the parts. So in these technology, we just print whatever we need in a set of starting with a block of material and then machineing of what we don't need. 

Speaker 2  (20:17)
So this is how it works. So there is many advantages to the technology itself regarding material consumption. But if efficiency and stuff like that, I'm not going to go through all those details, but this is the hardware side, which is not our products or already in the market. 

Speaker 2  (20:39)
We are making this ecosystem to get everyone connected so that the part and user can actually use it. So this is what our product is ah, so I hope 

Speaker 3  (20:53)
Worry I appreciate yeah, I appreciate you. You share those guys. You did make it clear, like clarify all my questions, and I'm telling some notes where you are talking. 

Speaker 3  (21:03)
And then you're later, you'll answer my question. So yeah, I think this is great. This works better so for the time, we only have 10 minutes left. 

Speaker 3  (21:14)
I just have another car had town service so I want to say this for like I do have some questions so on the email sent to me like I think the company name is different. Oh, there might be some I misunderstood. 

Speaker 1  (21:31)
No, actually, the company is almetech and the products or the platform that we named is at Manu chain. Yeah. 

Speaker 3  (21:39)
That really? I want to make sure we are talking. Yeah, I think of course great, yeah. 

Speaker 3  (21:46)
So for the whole team. There's like a lot of people on the team, are they like what's the no scotchia footprint looking like? Are they all here or half here? 

Speaker 3  (21:56)
Yeah. 

Speaker 2  (21:58)
Yeah, so I go back to my first. Slide, these guys are all in Halifax, right now, I'm personally in Ottawa. The company is a federal company. 

Speaker 2  (22:11)
So that we can work everywhere, including northia. Budget, but it's not registered in no Scotia right now. Because we just didn't need that, because it just adds some cost to us like animal cost, but at the end of the day, it's something easy that we can do and we believe having the right to work everywhere, right? 

Speaker 2  (22:35)
So what I'm trying to say is that all the RNE work all the RND work is done at their healthy 

Speaker 3  (22:43)
And that's why 

Speaker 2  (22:44)
Consider ourselves yeah, no skus. 

Speaker 3  (22:48)
I can see the quality of the presentation. It did actually outcome from the left to market. And as a programme, I do like their programme Adele, and we work very closely. 

Speaker 3  (23:01)
Actually, Y. 

Speaker 1  (23:02)
I almost wanted that. Sorry to drop. Do you just want to add big because the validation of this problem? 

Speaker 1  (23:09)
That areas are just mentioned actually went, it was validated by 2 lab 2 markets, there slides that you can see right now. Others are just did it back there and I do also have more than 7 interviews that they also admit this fact, the numbers other, as I mentioned 4 to 5 billions. It just got 10 times more so again, you have to scale up and scale up the number that you're talking. 

Speaker 1  (23:34)
I just want to mention that. 

Speaker 3  (23:35)
Hmm, where's I? 

Speaker 2  (23:36)
Yeah, just a climate for I personally joined lab market programme and bevered the second coherts that's happened in Canada, so yeah, it goes back to 2020 or 2021. Yeah, so I attended lap tomorrow, but lap to market at that time. At that time I was a peached student. 

Speaker 2  (23:56)
So we never looked this idea, validated this idea, and these 2 beautiful people, they were my support network at that luck to market programme, and then and then we were pursuing this idea and then by having mamood as our intern since last 2 years, we started on developing the actual NV. 

Speaker 3  (24:20)
Yeah, this grey. Yeah, I like I ask a lot about social footprint. It just because there are promotion cooperation, so all our programmes like all our funding are from like taxpayers. 

Speaker 3  (24:32)
You know, scructure so as a public fund, accommodation support, no scotshire based to businesses and we do require business to reduce 10, no scholshire. So there's something keeping mind if it's term, but that's it's not a big problem. So what's the ask today? 

Speaker 3  (24:53)
What can I help you? Yeah? 

Speaker 2  (24:56)
So how you can help YouTube, yeah 

Speaker 3  (25:00)
We are looking for any yeah, yeah, you know 

Speaker 2  (25:06)
PM job, you're also good if you go 

Speaker 3  (25:10)
In the first yeah, I'm not sure so our programme team. We used to do kind of preditation. I like to market. 

Speaker 3  (25:17)
I'm not sure like your co. Parts you have ever heard about that, but we do have accelerate programme. I can see like at current stage. 

Speaker 3  (25:26)
You help customer validation, not validation now. Yeah, they have a trial part this October, right, so you have customer discovery. And next step to vanidate the market purda market market so that I don't know where you can get the prof from, but after that, because this is kind of ict project, so I'm working with more like deeptech redicted projects. 

Speaker 3  (25:58)
Um, so full I'll share this with my BVC I came member who seems this sector but we do request to have Ah, revenue, I mean, like for the ict companies, AI companies, because, you know, it's highly grows. It grows so fast this morning. This industry is totally different companies who require 3 fires, 10 years per that development regulatory approval process, but for this is, I feel like, I think Before move forward to our like either equity investment or grants or supporting ict companies, we do want to say this product is validated. 

Speaker 3  (26:50)
There's marketing need, it's a clear need from the industry. And you have revenue, you have paid project. The upcoming, as I said, there's a programme called accelerate programmes. 

Speaker 3  (27:05)
No scottia, I can send you the link after like it's to support. We have something this year like separate it, just because of the nature of high course company back yours and the other detect companies. So there's growth growth stream to support Ic company to expand the revenue right quickly. 

Speaker 3  (27:35)
So I think that's a good project to think of like, we just Uh, discover, it will be reopening the summer. Yeah, yeah, I haven't seen a bad day for this year, but normally yeah, it's twice a year. The programme I can connect you with a programme manager. 

Speaker 3  (27:57)
It's kind of web. Have you talked to her? I'll know her so okay. 

Speaker 3  (28:01)
I say she work with that to mark that in a way I do have closely before, like because it kind of good, have no resource for our programme, but like I can make connection after that. Yeah, you are there is a graduate from accelerary programme. The programme is designed to help company get in westnight ready so normally after graduation, the participant Start fundraising in 6 traumas, and that's a town. 

Speaker 3  (28:34)
They will refer to our team like winter capital team. We'll start looking at if this is a good opportunity for equity investment but we do sit on the review panel. So we got our eyes, on the projects too, yeah. 

Speaker 2  (28:50)
Also, thank you very much. That's very helpful information, not that I want to add, is that AI has a big portion of this platform. So these platform cannot work without AR ok. 

Speaker 2  (29:04)
And that's why we actually need maphol. Yeah, just keep this in mind and then if you want, I can send this presentation to you and I guess based on based on what I understood our next step is to join the accelerate programme and get our product. And company ready for investment like fundraising in stockment. 

Speaker 3  (29:25)
During encouraged, that app, like, as a certain stage when you are right to investment equity, I mean, yeah, if we want to go quicker accepting investment, I'm sorry, yeah, sorry, if you tend, it really depends on company all the founder of the employer. It's kissback it's because they just want to. It's like last time project. 

Speaker 3  (29:48)
It's more businesses we don't want to go global. We only want to start working with some companies here like some companies. They are now winter opportunity, so it's not necessarily for them to accept equity, but for this project. 

Speaker 3  (30:03)
I do see, you have potential to grow global, like to go to some multi-billion dollar market, and they have together. For revenue revenue, I'm quickly in 5 years. So there's something 

Speaker 1  (30:15)
Yeah, sarghio I just want to ask you something because we only have maybe 1 or 2 minutes I already talk with Walta. I mean I still have an applied for them because for this project we need to have the incubat here for ourselves, either. It should be in health in the housing. 

Speaker 1  (30:30)
The idea hub or it should be voter, so we thought that vote would be a better option. So I just want to know that there won't be any conflict between these programmes. If you have the Volta, and after that we applied for you, I think you're 

Speaker 3  (30:43)
Yeah, just yeah, I it's on my commerce. I'm a suggestion that he should talk to what time yeah, yeah, I'm going to talk about, yeah, the forecast of his AI company for last 2 year. Yeah, sure for sure. 

Speaker 3  (30:56)
Yeah, and also like propel, but you already being through electronically, so there may be some overlap with propel the peers. Computers is, you may find some customers there. 

Speaker 1  (31:14)
Oh, I was talking about the PRCO so okay, I mean, I didn't talk it like that that we would like do some kind of use their services yet. But I know some of them, but yeah, I mean, we are an active talk again as I as I mentioned, because we have to gather some kind of the capital fundings especially, we are talking about the nvp the nvp is ready as once as one, therefore level, but if you want to move forward. We need some kind of myself because already working on other parts, but I have to put my focus most mainly over. 

Speaker 1  (31:47)
Yeah 

Speaker 3  (31:48)
Past here, I think, how about a regional? Do you have APDA from investmental scottia? Like Hector Frazer, have we talked to he? 

Speaker 1  (31:57)
No, no you're the first person in that was like she knows 

Speaker 3  (32:00)
Yeah, I'm go on to please send me Habe. The regional he's a business development advisor based in HR M so yeah, he can help you a lot. 

Speaker 1  (32:10)
Yeah, we're sure F. L. 

Speaker 3  (32:13)
Hello, after this meeting, I'll message you, I'll conneccut for the accelerate programme and also Hector policy. He also managed several program. ETP is to support company if you want to travel to discovery, customers or talk to customer or talk to anything, if you want to hire consultant, to make a better business plan or some good market strategy. 

Speaker 3  (32:40)
That's a programme 

Speaker 1  (32:42)
Excellent, perfect. Thank you very much. Thank you very much for your time. 

Speaker 1  (32:44)
Really 

Speaker 3  (32:45)
Yeah, okay? Great, thank you, yeah. 
