
Speaker 1  (00:04)
And the brother. 

Speaker 2  (00:26)
Silver bridge, Greek in the stark American task September. The convention here 

Speaker 2  (00:51)
Good afternoon, everyone. Welcome I'm practise senna represent the CA misses sagas economic development team capacitor that's we over there Thursday when an year older. But before we get started, I went to level set right away, right? 

Speaker 2  (01:07)
This is not a ceremonial session. I mean, it's not a lecture, it's not a panel for the sake of a panel and not another warm, we're a good idea is going to die on the sholt. This is about deal flow. 

Speaker 2  (01:17)
The European innovation and turning crossord interest into projects that actually should Natural George. If you don't know, miss a sauga by name, you know, my experience, it's a city that has the airport. 

Speaker 1  (01:29)
Most of you were 

Speaker 2  (01:31)
Problem. And this section over here, person airport is Canada's largest and busiest airport moving 50 million passengers annually that matters. Because connectivity is the competitive advantage, talent moves faster supply chains, compressed and executive time stops getting wasted in aerospace. 

Speaker 2  (01:49)
We're the largest subsector in Canada by both employment and number of worlds. Companies operating here, support global programmes might names view already know airbus, Sapra Leonardo en rolls, Roys a lot of site Canadian leaders like MHI and bombardio. Now let's talk about Parliament rentals. 

Speaker 2  (02:08)
The real reason why we're all in this room 50 billion, that's how much can saug. This manufacturing sector contributes to bacteria's GDP annually sits at the centre of Canada's advanced manufacturing universe, with over 2400 device manufacturing businesses. 91000 plus skilled workers, 73% of which have a full secondary education. 

Speaker 2  (02:32)
On the tact side, we're building an ecosystem. We are on with over 940 plus tech businesses and 44000 tech employees. This includes globally recognised brands such as scennings, wash Schneider, electric and Harrison companies that don't choose locations likely columnus alcohol Low over the past 5 years misses sauga, software sector employment improved by 138%. 

Speaker 2  (02:57)
The basis in the GT a so what does that mean an investor terms? It means density. It means customers nearby. 

Speaker 2  (03:04)
It means colleges don't stay pilots, they scale. And the capital capital signals are already here. Over the last year, investment saga has supported 116 investment projects, creating more than 9000 new direct jobs in adding 3.3 billion 2 our economy in 20 global sources of investment impact, specifically, the city has attracted nearly a billion in foreign domestic investment over the past 5 years, creating more than 2300 jobs, recent investments like astrozetica, Roche, Erikson and semens a line supply chains reinforced that momentum. 

Speaker 2  (03:39)
That's our darity, matrics, the proof that capital can land here and scale here. So why smart? 

Speaker 1  (03:47)
Let's ask that direct way. 

Speaker 2  (03:49)
Lovertage billion of potential arts, 140 organisations, 21, Europe, adventures, smart eurocas, the bridge between global purpose and private execution. Moving from talk, the public collaboration and commercial results, and we're not doing this alone through engine network. You're plugged into 45 plus more than 10000 SM. 

Speaker 2  (04:11)
Yes. With over 8.2 billion in industry sales, that means partnerships don't start from 0. It starts with the network that already exists. 

Speaker 2  (04:19)
But the bottom line is that missagus, where global access to industrial capability and investment momentum intersite. Nicora, I had this over. Let me hand let me leave you with one clear thought. 

Speaker 2  (04:31)
This is not about learning another programme, it's about deciding to use it with sasocho. Already has the industrial base, the customer and capital momentum, the smart Erika, is the mechanism that let us move faster across borders across clusters and into real projects. So if you're looking for Partners who can actually execute under North American platform that scales and funding that D risks collaboration instead of slowing down that this is the room. 

Speaker 2  (04:57)
And this is the moment As he listen to what comes next, think less about is this interesting and more about who do I want to build with? Because the goal today isn't about awareness, it's alignment in action. And with that offendable order to our colleagues. 

Speaker 2  (05:15)
This bargain Rica, my friend britisha The director of sway Erika EU and Peter international advisor at Ira Q 

Speaker 1  (05:33)
Thanks for the pubs. 

Speaker 3  (05:56)
Okay, thank you very much. But I hope you enjoy this Christmas. Assume we are going to go together. 

Speaker 1  (06:05)
All right, thanks. Thank you. Thank you for moving a lovely introduction from this misses. 

Speaker 1  (06:09)
Saga. My name is Peter bandas and I work for NRC I rap NRC I rap is an organisation that is the funding agency for European Canada and that's iro, you're supporting my friend Patricia from a lot of civilistian, Spain. 

Speaker 3  (06:27)
Yeah, God from surveys. Yeah, which is on the North Coast of Spain, mark 3% here, the mart ericaster, which is a class, an international plus there is not only European, it's international with more than 47 countries involved in the eurica Nevers and will spend to you later and I represent the claster on advance manufacturing, focusing on advanced manufacturing companies and technologies, trying to promote rnd at the international level and rnd, which is an industry driven close to the market. So what we believe you have some information conservatives, a young day, director of this is smart But let's start. 

Speaker 3  (07:12)
I am always explain before what you decise. And then we will go deeply into the smartplaster, which is focusing on advancement as I said. And then we will give you some information here on how an allian companies can be founded by my Ida. 

Speaker 1  (07:35)
And we would like to ask you to ask as many questions as possible. So you get clarity on how this can actually work in reality. Because this is not really a presentation. 

Speaker 1  (07:45)
This is mainly a workshop, so both the foreign companies and the Canadian companies can leave this room with understanding. How would their international coinnovation, using to reach a smart or and how can they make it happen in their own case? 

Speaker 3  (08:04)
Okay, so let's start with eurica. Eurica is an international network in which accessibility for a more 45 countries are involved 44 or I think it's 47. 

Speaker 1  (08:16)
I think it's focusing. Yeah, we are global. 

Speaker 3  (08:21)
Maybe you can see the next slide in the picture of the Andrews which are involved. I think the last countries we were joining the network. Chilly joined Chile, congrasville, South Africa. 

Speaker 1  (08:38)
Yeah, yeah, goes well. 

Speaker 3  (08:40)
So it's not only Europe but many countries around the world trying to accommodate in international army projects. And what we do is to promote combination in our activities. That's the key issue, but there are some rules, and there are some instruments which what is what we are going to try to spend. 

Speaker 3  (09:00)
Now A as I said, there are several initiatives within the eurica network one is the clusters. The clusters are instrument. Our technology called focused issues in which we become promot projects. 

Speaker 3  (09:19)
The network projects. There are the eurostarts goals, global Stars, and some activities within other to promote starts and a new establishing combination. 

Speaker 1  (09:31)
Not sure, Canada supports your stars network and all of the 5 clusters. We are sometimes involved in global stars. That depends on the specific geography, but basically NRC R at 3 Erika supports through our funding. 

Speaker 1  (09:49)
All of these programmes, the programmes are different, and we can get into that later and we are here mostly to talk about one of the clusters, a specific to advanced manufacturing sector which is smarter. 

Speaker 3  (10:04)
Yes, I'm before my enthusmack, I will just tell you the names of the 5 clusters that will have one is related to a sofare innovation and digital transition, which is idea. Another one is related to sustainability, which is erosure. Another one is related to electronic components on system, which is X CCS telle pic, is relatively to next generation communication systems and a smart, of course, what is the one related to manufacturing? 

Speaker 3  (10:34)
We are cooperating all the time we're having many meetings together. The clusters sometimes there are proads in which we can have technologies from different clusters, and we cooperate among ourselves. So the issue is not to decide whether I want my mother or my father which projects I have among us. 

Speaker 3  (10:53)
We can decide where the parade can figure 

Speaker 1  (10:57)
And basically you can look at this as a preset plumbing that has been in place for 40 years, that is very oiled machine for making calls and funding the projects across all this huge network of 47 countries. 

Speaker 3  (11:15)
Okay, so I'm going to so the euricaps the briets. They have to be industry agreement, as I said before, the Tr L between 6 and 9, it's not Bradley, man more or less. And they have 2 years, of course, often to global cooperation, proposals, market-oriented, as I said, it will we go to have their full value chain involved in the project proposals in terms of the consultium and what it wants to promote most is to make S VS a more competitive and trying to promote or so. 

Speaker 3  (11:59)
The screen up of the companies 

Speaker 1  (12:02)
I would add that the project triple market, so this doesn't mean that at the end of the project, the market entry has to happen right at that moment, but we would like to see that the project goes to market within 2 years of the completion of the project that might take 23 years. 

Speaker 3  (12:23)
Okay, so let's go now to smart. And well, it's smart, as I said, it goes through from the to 6 to 8 and what we want is to boost competitiveness in the advance manufacturing sector and there's a big difference in the clasterism. Idea, for instance, which is related to ICT technologies in the city technologies that are big players in the smart and then advancement of factory sector there are not so many big players, but we have lots of SMS that need to cooperate among themselves in order to be more combinated, and does there reason. 

Speaker 3  (13:00)
Why is Mat is if you're trying to promote this kind of cooperation? I would invite you to load to our website in our website. We have a lot of information explaining, but one of the things that we have, however, is our technology don't mark A. 

Speaker 3  (13:17)
The technology, Roma is not, it's just an audientation document. It doesn't mean that everything that end that is equipment has to be done or your project has to feel exactly on the world map. It's just an organisation of what we understand in smart manufacturing is so in the technology called drama, which will review last year at the end of the last year, we have declined some technological domains and we also define which have been keyn application areas of large technologies. 

Speaker 3  (13:54)
In fact, in the review that we defluestly and end of next year we included the BO sector the health sector food sector but as far as manufacturing is involved, we are not taking into this smart plus their projects on alary or health. We are taking projects in which there are manufacturing challenges in the health sector or in the video sector we have to wait manufacturing. That's the key issue in our way to participate in this kinds of operates. 

Speaker 3  (14:29)
And also a insmat. Not all in the class of projects, not all there for the 7 countries are involved or for the 7 countries do not support deployers in this course every year in smart will lounge one call per year, and every time that we lounge a car we ask each of the 47 countries if they will support the call. So this is also a violence is not exactly, but this are more or less. 

Speaker 3  (15:07)
They're supporting countries that we have for the moment supporting projects in the asthmasty. But the most important thing in is magica. Project is to talk with the nation and hunting agency to talk to Twitter and then to talk to the Peters in the other countries, that's the key issue, because then to brighter would propose or we can do it, or we now have to do it, but the key issue to talk to the right people in each company in Norman, to see if that country this year, is going to support this kind of permits that's the case. 

Speaker 3  (15:49)
Okay, why? Adjusting some information of water, typical smokies, taken into consideration work in the manufacturing sectories, usually in a smart project. We'll have 3 or 5 countries in world. 

Speaker 3  (16:07)
2 is the minimum. As far as we have 2 companies. We can accept deployers, but usually we have 3 to 5 pounds. 

Speaker 3  (16:16)
That's more, right. Usefully, progress are foreigners, and there are no 6 years for his 3 years. It can be 2 years, but mostly is 3 years. 

Speaker 3  (16:28)
Usually we used to have 32 participants. And a useful budget, average budget of the projects are between 15 million €, not in $, north canalian $, but a million Euros. The medium value of the project situationalators sometimes a while we used to have projects of €700000 and now in an event. 

Speaker 3  (17:00)
So now we just will have 1.5 or even 2 m Euros for 3 years, which is not so much. 

Speaker 1  (17:09)
So the overall project size, of course, depends on the number of the farces, because generally most countries and this differ from country to country. There's a limit of one partner can get in terms of funding in Canada. We generally Fun about 50% of the budget of the project of the Canadian participant up to about 4 to 500000 Canadian. 

Speaker 1  (17:37)
Of course. If you have 5 Partners that the budget for the project gets much much higher. And you get, of course, more IP average through that, through funding from the other countries. 

Speaker 3  (17:50)
Okay. I just said before in smart we launch one call per here we are little office and we have resources to launch more. And I think it's quite efficient to have. 

Speaker 3  (18:01)
Yes, well, just for in our sector there are some of my other launch, even 2 courses per year. But in our cases, one called by year Which are the eligibility that we use college proposals? What we are looking for the project has to be a market-oriented, and at the same time it has to be no, it has to be we are talking about R and deploying, so the innovation is an issue that has to be in the Korean proposal, and we are we've had always been saying that has to be civil purposed, but there is a discussion now, of course, with the 2 are used technologies and with a defence. 

Speaker 3  (18:41)
So I think Peter is going to talk about a little bit about it. 

Speaker 1  (18:45)
Right, I would like to address that because I actually sit as a Canadian representative on that Europe committee that is discussing to do use. And all the rules around it. So currently from this issue of potentially working on the future of military defence technologies defained by prominent, but when we apply or when the companies apply for current eurica private checks, it needs to be primarily stable, which means that the current Partners and the current end use of the technology is civilian, which doesn't mean that in the future, the same technology could not find home in the defence centre, in fact, that is preferred that it would happen. 

Speaker 1  (19:35)
But we need to currently use the criteria of eligibility for any Europe approach. So it cannot be a relationship between an Agen company and a defence contractory in Germany that would not work right, so the distinction is the interest can goes project. Is there but the project is being proposed, doesn't just clear civilian and result? 

Speaker 1  (20:04)
After that insolition, 2 years later, it can proceed further. 

Speaker 3  (20:11)
Okay, of course, this are discussion always now. 

Speaker 1  (20:14)
Point right, I mean, we were really involved in discussions, what will be the rules and what will be the filters and how we will actually manage when this mandate gets enlargeed, but that's currently not in place. And so it's no part of the eligibility criteria for labelling approach. 

Speaker 3  (20:30)
Okay, in this war ahead in smart, I said we'll have one corporate here, but this have 2 faces called we have the PO phase, and the FPB face. The PO face is a kind of advisory face so you so me submit a kind of kind of proposal. It's not a complete one. 

Speaker 3  (20:51)
We evaluate with external evaluators. The proposal and we give you advice on how to improve your proposal for the final advice. So it's not that go, no go is an advice for a place in which because we want to have good proposals at the end of the proceedure. 

Speaker 3  (21:08)
So is that kind of advice for your face? In which, by the end of this phase, we say, okay, we've proposed the project to go to the end or we can't recommend you not to go ahead, but you have to give it just a numbers in the coal line. We are in the cornline. 

Speaker 3  (21:25)
Now we close the PO phase in January. And 36 out of 38 proposals were proposed to go ahead and 2 of them will have this kind of difficulties. And to this process, we give them advice, we say, exactly what they have to improve in the proposal. 

Speaker 3  (21:47)
And then we have the final phase, which is the FB phase. And in that's the final one. That's what you prevent the complaint proposion and there we say we evaluated with 3SM evaluators, and then is where we say yes, the proposal come beloved or none or kind of beloved. 

Speaker 3  (22:06)
At this stage. It's not only is mark office who evaluate the proposal, but it's also the counties involved. Whoever way to proposal so if there is a proportional in which is a cooperating with company from the UK for instance, the representatives of the Canada and the representatives of the UK participate if they want in the valuation process, so we are sharing for both an information can be valid or not all together working together. 

Speaker 1  (22:41)
Here, I would my games some westerns learn. So first one is timing each one of these cycles. We'll have a clear deadline. 

Speaker 1  (22:50)
And you will know the deadline for our list normal months ahead of deadline and misunderstand that you know you might be used to other treatment of that lions elsewhere, but generally with you Europe, the deadline is final, it has time 8 and minutes and watch out the timing is usually in central European time, so if it's noon at 6 AM in eastern Canada and whether the deadline closes the portal closes and exception of input after that moment in time is not acceptable. The other thing is that it is really good practise, although it's not a requirement of the submission process to discount contact your funding agency. 

Speaker 1  (23:41)
So Ira in Canada, in case of Canadian entries and discuss the project with that organisation, because you want to get a clear understanding on eligibility of the company in the project and of course, you can get suggestions of how to improve your application. If you give somebody a chance to review it. And give you feedback now, if that happens after the submission, there is not much that can be done in that round. 

Speaker 1  (24:08)
You know, possibly you can have a better like next year. But it's something that I would suggest that every company does and takes advantage of our assistance that can be provided in that process. 

Speaker 3  (24:22)
I'm going to give you some ideas on the dates on the timing that we have. For instance, as I said, we are in the line to call now, the pure face close I needed a discount of January. We indicate those 36, you know proposed us from the 22nd of February and then the deadline for the final credit proposal. 

Speaker 3  (24:48)
Fensis on the press of paper that's more or less. Well, these are defining that we are a managing for the ninth call and then for the 10th call. We are already now working on the deadline sport for the time being, we only have one date, but in the next 2 months we will define the whole dates public year 2027, but we are already working on that. 

Speaker 3  (25:13)
I'm what one thing that we do, and I think is quite interesting, is that we organise how day once per year. And that's the data. If you have over there from the 10th core, what's up your a pure. 

Speaker 3  (25:30)
They is meeting in person in which companies can come present the great ideas. They can have vitable meetings and they can look for Partners in order to define alcohead. Next PO meeting will take place in October to seventh. 

Speaker 3  (25:49)
Sorry, October the eighth in biana, so you are all invited to participate in this PO. D. 

Speaker 1  (25:58)
And it's really good if the Canadian companies can come to whatever placing new Europe that here is the E o's, it's very useful networking opportunity to meet some of the Partners in person and create a relationship, and it's not computer because, of course coming from Canada gets a little bit expensive and involved in an amount of in the amount of time that you have to spend. So it is also possible to simply not create a relationships remotely and submit the EO by the peo deadline that's also possible. 

Speaker 3  (26:36)
Yeah, when web paper was going to say later, but they say now you know what webpage in smart Erika webpage we'll have information of blowers looking for Partners, and we also have information of past proot of properties we are running now so that you have information on what kind of players. We are dealing with kind of companies or even what countries that usually participated in this kind of project proposals. And then we want to instax on this like which is important and class task. 

Speaker 3  (27:07)
If the lass is a sentist, a Peter term yesterday and I like it castas give the Larry, but the national countries give the money. So this is important because we give the level. Yes, of course, this are procedure. 

Speaker 3  (27:21)
You have to present a good proposal. There is have to, what do you have to accomplish with our rules? But who give the money is the countries. 

Speaker 3  (27:28)
So before starting any brilliant, the key issue is 2 talk 2 your country and 2 try to guess if the companies that you are choosing are in the right country for this kind of instruments. 

Speaker 1  (27:43)
Right? So basically you need two things to run a successful project. You need a cluster to abolate. 

Speaker 1  (27:52)
The project to give it a label that makes it a project without success through that process, the project would not go anywhere but you also need approval of all the participating national funding organisations from each country involved to be happy with the project and the support and the RND and the impact of the project and that's why it's really useful modal, compulsory to contact those as soon as possible within the process of applying before actually final application is submitted. So that you get the feedback from from the national funding organisations on eligibility and on the processing cons of the project because that that way you maximise your chances of your project, actually winning both of those stands meaning. 

Speaker 1  (28:50)
The label San and the funding stand and you need both for the project to move on. 

Speaker 3  (28:57)
Yes, this is a case because most of the projects die or from don't go ahead because of this. So this is the most important issue. In fact, I can give you an example, did UK the UK in the last I think for years they used to have the regited by it to smart. 

Speaker 3  (29:13)
They have final pounds a year for smart so last year they had 0. So you have to contact us to check if UK is going to have money the year or next year. Para year because they don't have 2 years ago and not now and I'm saying, change it's very, very quickly. 

Speaker 3  (29:34)
So let's take with the company's first of all. 

Speaker 1  (29:37)
And at the recent angle, it is also possible that some of the Partners will be self funding, so especially if it's larger organisation, they might not, they might be essential for the approach. And it might be very interested in the project but because they have sufficient financial resources they, do not require their national funding nevertheless. They should spell contact the national funding organisation. 

Speaker 1  (30:02)
Because the national funding our organisation has to approve the participation of that country. So there will be involved, and in that case if they don't need the money. Now, that part of the process can be really simply because they can simply declare themselves to be subfunding and most of the other checks and balance going to be performed and the project can go ahead regards. 

Speaker 1  (30:27)
So that sounds 

Speaker 3  (30:30)
Yeah, I'm not what I view for Richard on the process. We have it in our workplace but yesterday. You know that there are something place in order to present the great proposal that you have to play. 

Speaker 3  (30:41)
And there are some data, and intricity to the webpage and so on, but all this information, if you believe and you want to present app parade proposalities can't go across an in the website, we'll have on that information. The only thing I'd have to add is that in office we are financed because we get on 5 attention of the parade. And that's how we are financing. 

Speaker 3  (31:05)
That's how we pay the eternal evaluator which is the biggest feet that we have to pay for and as I said before, yes, for your information in our work in our webpage, we have projects looking for Partners so you can detect, but also if you will have a project idea, you can send it to us. We have a template and we can put it into our workpage in order to create to find Partners, and if you kind of come to be enough on here or anytime to appeal, they condus this code in order to check if you can find arners, or you can your parade idea. 

Speaker 1  (31:47)
So I haven't do a platform explore it's extremely useful for companies that are further aware that cannot physically show up at these events because it's an online tool that gives you opportunity either to plug it into an existing project that somebody has proposed, or you can post their own idea and see others. That will come from all over Europe or the associated countries and find you as a partner for our project that it would be interested in. So I stroll, encouraged to have a look at that tool and potentially use that tool in order to create these circulations, relationships, or basically get them started. 

Speaker 1  (32:28)
Right. It's like a dating process, so somehow the 2 parties have to get together, and then more parties come 

Speaker 3  (32:37)
They also technology that in our workplace will have information of running, which were a big place in the past, indicating that the development program they up starting in the company and all this information that might be running one for you. In order to check the kind of prayers or you went to my partner? If you are interested in a certain technology you can check here who was doing what and perhaps it gives your clue on a 9 year who was incorporate with And then I guess factors for success with first of all take with your countries, which is we are always staying the same. 

Speaker 3  (33:21)
We have to mean to in relationship with the Partners typical recommendations for our employer proposes to go I think that the most important answer to take the consumption because they are key. We'll always see it in the same. Please contact your companies and this is the team I don't have Let's take a whole point. 

Speaker 3  (33:49)
That's the team that we're in most of you jamic. No arrive is the restaurant who is dealing with the date today? Activities, and then we have some shorts from technical environment from the marketing department. 

Speaker 3  (34:02)
And we also have here with us, the Christian smart, which is haireness for is sitting over there is the president of the smart. That's probably how canabia can another sorry? Can support 

Speaker 1  (34:18)
Okay, so now we will get into some of the technologies of what we do. So in Canada, all your programmes are supported by additional funding organisation, which is in this case, NRC Iran and in Canada. NRC R rep is a mandate to support smiss, which is 4 profit incorporated organisations that saw less than 500 employees. 

Speaker 1  (34:50)
Here are some of the basic Canadian estemary requirements, and you're going to have to take a picture of this or capitious. Okay, I'm not talking you please do, but all of the canny. All of the calls international calls that Canada participates and will be always listed on NRC irabs of international opportunity stage. 

Speaker 1  (35:14)
So I strongly suggest that you you look up that page. We go Google and you can subscribe to announcement on technique. So basically refund that it changes the system sends you an email message. 

Speaker 1  (35:27)
That's something new has been posted, and in those announcements. We always list all of the requirements for the Canadian participants, but basically it's a question of having a company that is maturing enough that has developed a product that has revenue and is capable of starting and also finishing in international project that we have in mind, right? So that's where all of the requirements come from, that there is a reasonable chance of success. 

Speaker 1  (36:08)
I would say so really small startups that have just couple of employees and don't have any track record are too early for those perfect, more reasons. Okay? And if you have any questions again in any announcement of these calls, you will always find a contact information. 

Speaker 1  (36:34)
So in this case, I am the programme lead for smart plus so you can apply my name there and you can contact me if you have any more requests. I was suggest that you always do that earlier in the process, when you and our applient your well get in touch with me and we might have a session and go through the project proposal or the idea and give you some feedback so you have a better chance of success when it comes down to actually applying 

Speaker 3  (37:12)
Okay, and this is what we wanted to present, we have some information here that they brought, so you can take some russias and it's some information on our contacts or so if you write and now if you have Christians, now Christians on yeah 

Speaker 4  (37:28)
Just just thank you very much. My own condefinence of a bit of a refresher. How does equipka advising Europe hit together or not? 

Speaker 4  (37:39)
The context? There are being I haven't trying to just apply to horizon, Europe or 2 consortium, but they'd be very eligible for this as you well, so many differentiate, and it might also applies money. 

Speaker 1  (37:54)
Okay, I can take that alright. So alright in Europe and Yuki don't have anything in common other than that. They both involved the European Union okay in Canada, all every programming grows through INR CI Arab and the supporting organisation for her rights and Europe isset. 

Speaker 4  (38:17)
So when with the ice it and then so I'm near the horizon. Europe that agnifies performing, they're probably psychoanalyste they had similarities. Um, but one is not free empty. 

Speaker 4  (38:30)
In other words, microne could 

Speaker 1  (38:33)
That's correct. And that there is no correlation between the 2 and no limitations. Now, their potentially could be a limitation. 

Speaker 1  (38:42)
Because we generally don't like multiple international projects to proceed in parallel unless the organisation is so large that they have not only the financial, but the IP or the development side of things has so much Uber and so much leverage, they have so many people that they can actually execute at the same time. The same time in terms of funding there, wouldn't be an issue and, I would also say that Europe, programming and horizon, Europe programming is not exactly for the same audience. So horizon, Europe is generally, for much larger projects of the announced of due diligence. 

Speaker 1  (39:31)
And the amount of paperwork needs to be provided in order to apply is completely on a different level. And also on the other side there is completely a different level of probability of success. Because the refund projects are the cluster projects are smaller. 

Speaker 1  (39:51)
There are smaller number of applicants, and it's much easier to cross the minimum requirement to get the label and therefore, for you know, for those of you and the audience that come from the world horizon, Europe is good for the Canadian companies, only where there is a really strong partner. Larger partner, probably from the European Union, with lot of experience of how to do that if you're learning how to do that. Well, maybe you should have an alternative for companies that have never done international, or they have done something very small. 

Speaker 1  (40:33)
Eurica is the first entry point to learn and also to get to be known with the European Union system. So I would suggest that those who ultimately want to use horizon Europe for further involvement should start with eurica. Create a context and create a track record of being able to complete a project. 

Speaker 1  (40:58)
And then eventually they congratuate to these big projects under horizon Europe. 

Speaker 4  (41:03)
Okay, so I'm not contrained about this company. Authorising Europe. That's good to know that Europe is for the earlier stage. 

Speaker 4  (41:13)
Is there a revenue threshold area that can take? 

Speaker 1  (41:18)
Revenue threshold China doesn't pose and elements. No 

Speaker 4  (41:22)
What is the role of the role of the ITA 

Speaker 1  (41:26)
Okay, I should correct revenue threshold at the top. Doesn't the revenue at the top? There is no limit? 

Speaker 1  (41:37)
However, we as part of our requirements, we're looking at companies that make at least half a million dollars a year as a starting right, you know, that won't be a problem as far as in Europe, because if you have any problems in Europe is really out for you. 

Speaker 4  (41:55)
So the divids are they proactive and assisting the S? M? Yes? 

Speaker 4  (42:02)
I'm so okay. I'll find a practise meeting work Q&A's with Europe. 

Speaker 1  (42:07)
Okay, so we at Ira don't have to band with to actually facilitate the connections. The smart pluster is much better at it. An organisations like engine are the ones that do this connection. 

Speaker 1  (42:23)
So, you know, if you if you want to follow my detail analogy, there are the leading coaches and they are organising the dances where the parties can meet we. At RF don't do that although it's sometimes happens because we haven't gonna know. However, the league IT as are hands-on and help the companies in terms of talking to people like me. 

Speaker 1  (42:47)
Now, getting them aligned with how it's done and getting them in touch with information that would help them succeed, but not in actual making the connections with the Partners. I would such as to connect with the Partners. The companies in their field of expertise, they should attend European trade shows and conferences and get visibility and also get the opportunity to meet face-to-face potential Partners and discuss it, and the tools place more has on their website is the beginning of it right. 

Speaker 1  (43:24)
You don't really want to travel to Europe and go. Blind or tracho, like an oversa with tens of thousands of exhibitors, you're probably going to get lost, and you're not going to come home with much, but if you prior to that end up setting up some meetings because there is a common interest, then that is much closer to getting subtraction. 

Speaker 4  (43:51)
And then 112 questions I'm amazing. Is there a minimum financial commitment required? The Obviously at the congres. 

Speaker 4  (43:58)
Uh, Tim worst about it. 

Speaker 1  (44:01)
So an IR and we found them out of it so basically, if you're if a Canadian some is thinking about this, they have to be able to fund halfway whether from their revenue or whether from private funding, but it cannot be public funding, because the psychology rules limit other public sector funding to fund that particle. Programme. Right? 

Speaker 1  (44:30)
Okay, all assistance. 

Speaker 5  (44:35)
I just wanted to add a comment. So I wouldn't NGN Canada, I think the bridge go in and so I travelled to the, you know, session with the POD in Dublin last year. It was fantastic and that loads of organisations from across Europe and one of the organisations is here with us today from the university of Technological University of Dublin that I met at the pedo day, and also it's not just about the funding, but it's the opportunities that you create like connecting with. 

Speaker 5  (45:04)
These organisations in the process of applying with the funding money and the phenomenal network can support that are throughout Europe and through Canada to our Partners like Iran. 

Speaker 3  (45:16)
Now, I would say that an important issue of the glasters, because we are building a community and ecosystem of internationally. A company's around manufacturing, and it's we made it. We have a members and we organise several activities among ourselves. 

Speaker 3  (45:37)
We have the clinical committee that we meet each other. We have a war, so it's an opportunity to start getting interest with different products. In the world around manufacturing, so it's not just an a tool to promote or certain industries for funding our we are trying to do is to bring the community and will it takes time slowly we organised a pure, they easier in a different countries so that we get to know the ecosystem. 

Speaker 3  (46:08)
So we are working on completely that community 

Speaker 1  (46:13)
And I want to thank triser, and the smart cluster team, because this is the first time an eurica cluster has come and done a BDA into Canada to connect with our ecosystem and thanks through Richard for organising this because engine has done a great job to facilitate this wonderful connection of the ecosystems that are in real need to connect Thank you. 

Speaker 6  (46:48)
Yeah, I'm sorry from a ministry and immunovation. And interview from a collection that evolvation point, Peter, because we all know money talks, do you have the budget for the next course for the Canadians engineers? We already have an unlocked. 

Speaker 1  (47:03)
So we do so our funding, of course comes from federal government and the funding is no directed to specific programme, but I cannot disclose how we have broken up the budget for each of the calls, but when I say that be support of the clusters that means we have a budget for all of them, and it really depends. On how much interest and how many good proposals they are, because in the end, that might determine that the budget, the way it's fluid within our hands will move to where more this projects are. 

Speaker 1  (47:42)
So it's a question of equality of the submission. It's not that just there is so much money for smartphosure, and the money must be spent. It are there really good projects that appear again? 

Speaker 1  (47:56)
This on my question. I want to go to work 

Speaker 4  (48:00)
Yeah, yeah. 

Speaker 1  (48:01)
Professional centre's mentioned that. Yeah, Mexico company leverages more monster. You cannot apply a control for them. 

Speaker 3  (48:13)
Nobody like oh spirit. 

Speaker 1  (48:17)
No, because generally, with almost the programming, is the contribution agreement you agree to some programmes just as we were all expected programmes. 
