
Speaker 1  (00:00)
The work part means you have to do some workshop. I hope you're ready to do a little bit worse. It will be beneficial for you today. 

Speaker 1  (00:20)
Where let's get the garden so my name is able to get on the advice president to the industrial, and I practise at my HD P. So today, I'll be running this workshop on AI manufacturing and industrial operations in general. The goal is to help you first see some real practical use cases I'll show you some of the 200 projects Maya delivered or solutions, but it may as the room from an industrial AI perspective. 

Speaker 1  (00:48)
And hopefully it helps you build and prioritise a roadback right? Where you would apply your some sort of great AI tech you would like to deploy and your environment in the right place, you know, with the right tools. And the right people around so the idea is often most people have heard about many use cases. 

Speaker 1  (01:14)
So you've probably seen heard lots of use cases you might have a sense of what might work in your manufacturing plan or you may not right but the idea today is to give you an exhaustive list of things that did work and things that did work so that you can then prioritise the ones are left at our align with your lauseer visit. So that's the goal today, old, and in a search that's me, you can read my camera. Maya just a quick note there. 

Speaker 1  (01:48)
So we've been in business 40 years, so we're not a startup in the AI Space we've been dealing with manufacturing and engineering for the last 40 years. We've developed lots of solutions with 250 people are headquarters are in much job, but we have offices and have been ramping in terms of on their own and torono area in China. So we really spread, you know, across Canada and my team out of the tone and 50 people. 

Speaker 1  (02:19)
About 30 or so people that are dedicated on the industrial AI slide of good business. So that's where we leverage your dirty data, whether it's elementary and all your systems collect whether it's images or x-rays or different things that you know, that you can use as data inputs and not just that right we've seen and shown a lot of agent tech in GenAI and Chatbot and assistants today. Yes, it's one of the many use cases that you could deploy in your environment, but it's not the only one that I'm going to be focusing on today. 

Speaker 1  (02:58)
Okay, so that's really our pedig green as a company. When do we look at this workshop? It's very important to move from the left of the screen to the right and not start from the right and things that we can apply amazing AI tech to solve something the mim, you know, be worth solving. 

Speaker 1  (03:21)
So first the first step in the 3 step process that we'll go together today is to start from that left handside to start from the business issues, business challenges that are, you know, a problems with you if it's not a problem, I'll try and fix it with AI pack right. I mean, I'm not trying to fix it anyway, because not a problem, but and certainly not greater. But in terms of the use cases, mias has come up with a framework, and we call epic him. 

Speaker 1  (03:56)
It's very simple, kind of 5 letters to remember of themes in industrial space, where typical manufacturers and industrial operators would see value in applying AI tech towards first eat anything related to energy when we say energy, it can be energy forecasting? It can be energy switching in terms of source per cost. It can be various things on the energy front, reducing overall, the energy used to produce your product right at the end of the day. 

Speaker 1  (04:32)
That's what this element is. And believe me. It's a lot more complicated than it happens. 

Speaker 1  (04:39)
Why? Because energy is consume at different levels across the plane, different kinds of the data different at different costs of energy, so AI and machine learning deep learning here and I will interret use a term AI deep learning machine learning. As a one, um umbrella, AI, those are all sub elements. 

Speaker 1  (05:03)
Of what we call AI today. Okay, basic machine learning. You know, technically speaking in a linear regression is AI I wouldn't consider that necessarily event AI, but it is machine learning. 

Speaker 1  (05:16)
So we'll encompass it there, but it's not necessarily what we're talking about here in terms of certainly the projects that we've deployed productivity productivity is not just tracking oi, right tracking or E is a metric that you can monitor it's influencing that metric with different right now, which actions, you have hundreds if not thousands of galimatary points and maybe 4020 control points that you can tweak at any given time to get to a better productivity. Now which one you turn on and which time that's where AI can help you independent machine learning. 

Speaker 1  (05:53)
So that's where it's important to drive. Now, he is still a great measure to track right for the effect in this of your line or your plan, but don't pull yourself the metric itself is on a standalum basis is not enough. Why? 

Speaker 1  (06:11)
Because oh, you will track essentially, the overall effectiveness online right? Or at the point level, it's going to aggregate those numbers. So let's say you have 8 lines, a manufacturing, like it rolls up to that one way for the plan, right? 

Speaker 1  (06:26)
But if lying 12 and 3, right, I've producing the most profitable product and then 400 and 506 and 7 are the least profit that you get on the third one basis for the product your boy could go off right. You could be losing money so oh eat great metric, but if not tied to business and profits on that line. If you have just one line that's scientists or one most people have learned in oneline 4 Bidens of metrics, implement them to track yourself But make sure you do it from a business sentiment, a business value as well. 

Speaker 1  (07:13)
I inventory supply chain input raw materials, get stuff in time we've seen with proven other disruptions, it's sometimes more challenging, right? So the reliability of the inputs and outputs of our company can you know forecast it much better by deep learning and open Asians that go and scrape some demand and forecast for quality anything related to yes, machine vision, or the product quality inspection on committed inspection? So those are the quality parameters where AI based machine vision can help a lot and the last but not based. 

Speaker 1  (07:52)
And the reason it's last recently, the one that finally, we can achieve successfully of low cost predictive maintenance for years, people come to me in our company at managed to great domains. Well, if you look at their historical records, it may have one unplanned long time, which cost them guess millions blocks, right? But for 10 years, there was minor elements and minor degradation, so to do predictive maintenance, you actually need degradation data, right? 

Speaker 1  (08:28)
You need degragreation of the climatery, or the process with something to inform AI model, that something is going wrong. Well, companies and for some, you know, preventive reason would replace the filter's way too many times to replace. You are replace whatever on the much more regular basis than needed to avoid issues. 

Speaker 1  (08:51)
Right? That means the data then speak, you know, I didn't be great any kind. So we couldn't really reliably do pretty good convenients. 

Speaker 1  (09:02)
Now we talk about Transformers for natural natural language processing and large language models of the same technology algorithm now be used to learn from your decades of beautiful, operational health, beautiful. They're needing us still, but operationally, normal data you can ingest and those become your operational signals and anything that starts creating from it in a very high dimension, in a 1 thousands of points now better and if come a very near combinations of climatery start acting up, it will raise the flight. 

Speaker 1  (09:44)
I first time it raises the flag. It will simply say, something abnormal, is going on. I don't know what it is something I've normally going on. 

Speaker 1  (09:52)
Now. A human being will look at it, say, oh yeah, this is what happened. The whatever filter got blocked because of whatever XY is that reason so we changed a filter and good. 

Speaker 1  (10:06)
Now we fed the information we give a label right? We classify what that weird thing is, and next time it happens. It will say this filter number 22 is being clocked. 

Speaker 1  (10:17)
Go and replace it right if you don't want an issue. So, but we will take feedback loops that you incorporate. But at least now you can reliably, you know, run and trust predictive maintenance models. 

Speaker 1  (10:32)
And the past. I'm sorry they were There, but they were not very good, but the new algorithms now. Good. 

Speaker 1  (10:40)
So those are the 5 kind of key office now. I'm just going to a very rapid-fire, go through some examples where I have deployed AI tech in different youth for you know, some of these usepasses just to give you ideas. Now think as I go through examples, think of your plan, your amount of your national operation, your shop floor right? 

Speaker 1  (11:02)
The character I'm going to have just take a maybe your cell phone or favour if you has just do list right? The top ideas here use cases that you see that you might apply to your environment. That's part of the portion. 

Speaker 1  (11:20)
So first one that those are simple, you know, if you have a treasure trove of the occuments right? That are technical documents about your operation often. Your intellectual property is part of your documents so you don't want to feed that to a club, but our solutions now, the LM are smaller enough. 

Speaker 1  (11:40)
That you can run them locally. This one can run my laptop okay, slow. But it runs on my laptop. 

Speaker 1  (11:46)
So it doesn't call home somewhere in a cloud right? And you can see the documents that are locally embedded, and it's not just the document that I research in those information. It's also the images it's called multimodal. 

Speaker 1  (12:00)
So from an engineering and technical viewpoint, these assistant now can go and fish, not just a text in your document and point back to their source very important that mission ask a question. He gets the list of the documents and the pages and clicks on it and gets to the right page. So these are just technical documents that we apply. 

Speaker 1  (12:23)
Another one is 1 of the design sets. I'll skip it because you can design components now and get feedback from a design perspective, but you're in manufacturing, so I'll skip the actually this one. I'll just keep just that's the latest one. 

Speaker 1  (12:39)
The one that freak me out the most. That's about three weeks ago and we start throwing about agent an agent existence and turfacing with that system. So to build this cylinder 100% of it is done by the agent. 

Speaker 1  (12:55)
There is no engineered designer actually touching any of the buttons in the semens and next environment here it's all done through chat. So we're interacting from a vocal perspective, and we're telling it to just build, you know, a cylinder that would sustain a certain pressure for us at microolic system and go and heaven design, and we just wanted to test up half our technology is this is more of a demonstrator an engineer here got into the body, but it's actually you'll see it towards the M. It actually created a full My ironics are it. 

Speaker 1  (13:39)
We redeline, everything always done with the manager. So many cases, those are the components on the agent pick side that you can start looking at. Do some small you know an experiment right? 

Speaker 1  (13:55)
Don't get a bit car keys or your bank account numbers and share the login because it will go and spend your money and sell your house so be here for how we use it. But in the end, there are very powerful technologies. Now back to the more practical components here with ego hydraulics, great company, build these garbage drug and other, like big hydraulic arms, right? 

Speaker 1  (14:23)
The smallest ones are literally, you know, about 37 years long. The bigger ones are 5 m long, maybe weight. Literally, they wanted to bring their manufacturing from China, back to the dark montrio, in order to do so all the manual labour and all the costing labour of us manually done in China had to be oddly. 

Speaker 1  (14:48)
So we took about a year and a 1 to fully automate all the main manual videos processes out of the way so that in the new plant brand new production plant that broken up last year, it's operational. Now the manufactured, those is mostly all automate with course a few humans in the loop, but at minimal level for the production. This here was a quoting system. 

Speaker 1  (15:20)
So thanking MS data from the manufacturing environment so all the delementary from past hydrawolic systems that they had manufactured to take the real data of how much it costs, how much time, how much raw material and all this. So all that was in the MS. And the PLM system, so from those with new hydraolic systems, right for new clients that you have never manufactured before. 

Speaker 1  (15:47)
We automatically not just create a quote, but all that 3 and 2 drawing in the back so that the engineers in Europe invalidates that process in that group. That saved your appointment from about 46 hours down to 32 or 3 hours per quote, and we're dying in other they want a second project where they want to go from the 3 hours to about 5 minutes sort of processor developing a scope of that this year was more to limitary base for the sweet manufacturing for litten batteries for electric cars. Lithium is very, very finicky, almost as much of this screen. 

Speaker 1  (16:36)
If you manufactured those batteries, and that was above 5 years, 6 years ago, just before COVID, that we did that project. And the variance between the best batteries that came out to the worst battery that came out the same process, same stage, manufacturing, same people, same everything, 300% different difference between the 2 right. The reason is the material definition and the temperature and humidity highly influence. 

Speaker 1  (17:05)
That performance for the batteryback as they're building, so a couple of things we did. We tried, we reduce that variance quite a bit by almost effective 3. It was still, you know, above, I think 92% variance with even to me. 

Speaker 1  (17:22)
That's huge, human Elizabeth to them. That was like night and day 3X to 1X. Like, okay, well, if we can live with 1X3X was definitely after sale problems, and most importantly, the last one. 

Speaker 1  (17:36)
They're they had an internal data science, scientist theme, which was great, because then we can pass on to the thons so they can go and do more internally, but they were looking at the data in the wrongway they were looking at the stars as a function of demonstras, a function of time everything as a function of time to build out the forecast model. Okay, so let's do that deficits itself as a function of temperature, not behind indirectly, yes through Vine. But the direct relationship that the model needed to learn is that this charge is a function of temperature as a function of pine. 

Speaker 1  (18:14)
So it's a curve as a function of climate makes someone learn to process Work in AI algorithm across So in this case, we simply made a very minor change in the data ingestion pipeline and train a model. I went from 64% accuracy to a big 92% accuracy overnight so now they were able to stave 10 hours of manufacturing Parliament at the end of the day, because otherwise we would have to wait 24 hours before they could ship and make sure to discharge no matches there. Supply demand anyway. 

Speaker 1  (18:52)
That's an interesting use case and I'll go very quickly. This one was a machine vision for quality inspection. So even though it's a robotic arm, sometimes the resin is too running and shares a bit too high, or the tape is a bit attention is a bit too high or too low or twisted, so there's various things that happen even if it's wrong here, robotics did that position. 

Speaker 1  (19:20)
And in order to avoid having engineering team competition and co, there's a fun. What do we do? It's been 60 layers now. 

Speaker 1  (19:30)
So it's been building up so automatically it pauses the automation system so that the technician can go locally make the repair the local repair needed and then it proceeds to that way they don't need to waste a lot of reward time. Back to Eagle, one of the automation was a wealth. Very simple. 

Speaker 1  (19:52)
Things look at wilds depending on the welfis of course, there are different algorithms that are needed. In this case, it was a last validation and external inspection of all the wealths for their system. And we built a nice little machine vision that is held on the tip of a robot arm, and it inspects 100% of all their Wales as before it was spot checks right oftentimes people will resort to spot check quality inspection because they can't spare the time to inspect every car with AI it kind of flips along to the problem. 

Speaker 1  (20:31)
Now you can typically look at every part and only pause, right? And give the people that human being a few things that need to be looked at further niceer, but also inspecting 100% of your cards. These predicted amendments as I expired before similar scenario, critical pump electrical panels, various pop machine element, another machine vision, this line for higher resolution camera, combined with ultra Violet cameras. 

Speaker 1  (21:03)
So you can think of machine vision as more than just your pictures, videos. You can look at ultra-violent x-rays, various it's some matrix of numbers at the end of the day, right? So we have very sophisticated machine vision algorithm. 

Speaker 1  (21:20)
Now deep learning algorithms that can be deployed this one to resort exploration. So when they go out for looking for little scottimen, a essentially big carrots of core sampling of Earth and they see the inspected and see if there's enough for one thing a extraction on the mining site. Problem is, these things are far, typically far at north, right? 

Speaker 1  (21:51)
But they don't have a lap up north, so they need to shift some of the samples right to make sure that they can validate how much lithium was in the course sample. Instead of doing that, we brought the lab with 2 simple cameras, an ultra fillet, camera, eye definition, camera, locally, and it could scan all those 4 sampling and give them the result right away. And it actually built a 3D geological survey as they were bigger so they could take a different places. 

Speaker 1  (22:23)
And see, you know, if they were getting better results over That's abust 9 time-saving, but it's also a cost saving, because they didn't have to shift the core samples acting a lot very far away. Here's a reinforcement learning. You think of AI and Dimitry, a lot of control engineers understand engineering for the room. 

Speaker 1  (22:50)
Excellent, so a lot of you guidd controllers are extremely rugged and reliable, right? That's why we relying on them for So many years and everything we do pretty much is somewhere in the piatic control, or somewhere the challenge was loops. Is they are so good so reliable? 

Speaker 1  (23:09)
That's why we relied on them. So no entry, you know, engineer would allow me to put an AI model and replace there via controller. And so instead, what we said, okay, fine, you don't want me to remove your loop, we'll keep it as the fail-safe, right? 

Speaker 1  (23:26)
And inside your logic, we will say, if else right if you're within certain parameter that we have trained a model. And we know reinforcement, reinforcement learning is very good at. Well, we'll flip to the reinforcement learning agent to control your system. 

Speaker 1  (23:47)
Why? Because it controls a lot better, right. You can see it when we turned it on. 

Speaker 1  (23:53)
I mean all the noise goes away. Now you can visually see how much less mechanical movement is also in this part of this did two things. The process was way more efficient way better control. 

Speaker 1  (24:08)
But the side effect, the side benefit, which nobody really expected that was actually for me. Return investment way better is the fact that there was 32% less fatigue on all the mechanical components of that part. And because of that, we're thanks to that, there was 60 months without failures, whereas before they were about 7 failures per year. 

Speaker 1  (24:35)
Think about 7 times a year. I'm planned down time, you go back change the thing after 7 times a year, and then you go and then 16 months Not a single maintenance required. No one turns outline, so in those cases, it's not just the process that we improve. 

Speaker 1  (24:54)
It's other things that maybe sometimes we have not thought about that great improvement. It's an example on mixing process. I spoke about the maintenance before. 

Speaker 1  (25:07)
We try very hard in the past, before we got these new algorithms to simulate onset of failure modes right to create data. So we can learn from fake failure modes that we did that synthetic that generated it kind of work, but then it gave us the idea of using simulation data or multiple things. This one work really well, which was they had some mixing issues for specific process of the Carbonation process in the dissolution of some components in their liquids, and you know, we would only figure that these issues at filling because they have a storage thing so there was some missing and other things, so they only did the quality inspection there, but based on the delimentary. 

Speaker 1  (25:58)
We knew exactly when they do would actually create a bad place, and so based on that, we were able to feedback early on in the process to correct the problem. So think of it as in the term digital twin, but it's kind of a digital planning, real-time of what should be versus. What is and if it started viviating yourself correct, right? 

Speaker 1  (26:23)
So it's kind of that feedback loop that you're using with simulation, perfect data that you have. So I hope I've given you enough like of the catalogue of examples right on epicham. Now I will give you 2 minutes just to write down on yourself on or an piece of paper. 

Speaker 1  (26:43)
Maybe the top 345. Business challenges half today, where you think AI tech could be used. Either I don't think further than that. 

Speaker 1  (26:58)
Just think of those use business use cases where maybe I could help you. Just go out path here. Under on it's some people are During the work shop Problems are just listening it to me, but hopefully, you'll see the night slide you miss out if you don't have that place. 

Speaker 1  (27:30)
While I'm doing this, anybody who's not running down their cup 5, then whatever use cases any questions so far in the content. Yes. 

Speaker 2  (27:40)
Okay, thank you very much for your presentation. I probably have lots of questions about that. Well, let me just up on Mike one question. 

Speaker 2  (27:47)
While others are writing, by the way, I just wrote 6 or 7 use cases from that one. So I've been to Aia lot. So from last point you mentioned that about using the AI as some sort of Site guy forward, because obviously energy sectors won't apply for that say that from the electrical side, it costs a lot of money. 

Speaker 2  (28:07)
We don't trust it another kind of things. So when you use the RL in your work and you found out that it's going to be better than the normal P. I. 

Speaker 2  (28:17)
D. How did you do that because there isn't? I'm asking that is one of the main issues about AI is that is hallucinate a lot. 

Speaker 2  (28:25)
And it just cares about the final answer. It says, okay, I would like to reach the accuracy of 98%. But Sometimes it would happen that AI break the rules, the rules in electrical engineering, write them basic physics, or in any kind of industry. 

Speaker 2  (28:41)
It's important, I won't like you to reach to this accuracy while breaking all of the rules. So how did you handle that? 

Speaker 1  (28:47)
So first there's something so reinforcement learning the way it's strand it's a probabilistic model, right? So it does not elucinate, because it's not like a natural language model. So that's my thing. 

Speaker 1  (29:01)
There's no allocinations often, so it's not always going to be right. And that is why we put an if else, if let's say temperature and pressure and humidity and whatever you know, critical parameters you're tracking are within a certain range of parameter you allow the system to run and be controlled by the reinforcement learning agent. As soon as anything levate starts deviating from those constraints, it defaults back to the piannika group that brings us back and check. 

Speaker 1  (29:38)
And then the reinforcement learning takes again, so there is no way that the reinforcement learning can break this. 

Speaker 2  (29:46)
So it's not the main guy, it's a side one. 

Speaker 1  (29:50)
It's essentially guardrailed by the PID control And you know anything that kind of spins in there stays in there as long as it stays in there, and in the control parameter that you give it in the outcome that you want. Then, you keep using the reinforcement move, if not, then you use PID control to look until it's back, and I think we gave it like a 15% time lag, right? So that once it's back is really back, and then the controller look, he falls back to the reinforcement. 

Speaker 1  (30:21)
There's a little bit of logic around rightguard for the IX. So that's that's one of the reason now, more holisically, we're generally speaking at my sgt thing we are grounded in physics, right engineers. We understand physics that's our value. 

Speaker 1  (30:38)
Proposition is to say we've safeguarded systems right in 200 projects so far. So we know What Recipe's work. We know what recipes don't work right and we'll talk a little bit about that later. 

Speaker 1  (30:51)
But that's really the key is to safeguard and ground. Those safeguards in physics bases. Good. 

Speaker 1  (31:03)
So we all have our little list and then that the first step really once we have that list brilliant ideas where we want to buy AI techn we want to kind of just do a quick, quick, sweeten, right? To eliminate the bad ideas, okay, so the way we do this is very simple. Small, medium, large and just within the list if you have 10 right? 

Speaker 1  (31:33)
Think of but once the business value, if I was to solve this use, I solve it pretty good. So is it a small business value, medium or high And then, you know, from time to implementation economy requirements, your a partner, a trusted partner in many AI. For manufacturing in Canada, by the way, lots of companies like ours. 

Speaker 1  (32:00)
So distress me, but just exploiting the system, they can say, find, implement a small memo or large Ann based on this anything that's kind of big find things since that just forgot that. Okay, that's the first aspect, all medium large, very gross categorization, right to remove the bad ideas from your list. Whatever is left, that's in my case, I have 9 components right? 

Speaker 1  (32:29)
9 potential places where I could apply to solve my business problem, I'm going to go to step 2 now, at the end of this presentation. You can't remember if we're going to the little bit, then these way, if you want the slides come and see me. And I'll give you The same, there's a QR Code. 

Speaker 1  (32:51)
You can email me at the end of this night. Enough, I'll send it a slide here, what we're going to do is for each project, we're going to go into a little bit more detail. Now that there might be worthin right? 

Speaker 1  (33:03)
We might be words considering as a good place to quit AI. Tech, well, we're going to go okay business value. We did it bloomum, large time criticality, right? 

Speaker 1  (33:15)
If I don't solve it within the next 23 months. What's it's the team order? My competitor is coming in my market. 

Speaker 1  (33:23)
I'm done. I'm suppose, right. There's a point exaggerating here, but that's the time critical data accessibility. 

Speaker 1  (33:32)
You have 52 different spreadsheets and Truly RP systems and you know what I'm playing with? This data is not easily accessible so low, medium-high again on the data accessibility data quantity, right? You have a week to 3 months a year, 10 years, right in your head. 

Speaker 1  (33:58)
Anything above a year should be big. Maybe 3 months of 12 months, average, < 3 months, low amount of data. Okay? 

Speaker 1  (34:09)
Data quality? Again, is it manual inputs with a classification without data governance on them? Like loose text inputs that anybody Joe wrote there the other one faster, the other one said Pat, okay, so we have 3 words and met the same thing. 

Speaker 1  (34:31)
But that's not, you know, enter the same way. So how good is your date? We can help you that obviously these of data generation. 

Speaker 1  (34:42)
So if you've needed to wait for 2 or three weeks or a month, right? Could you generate more data to solve the problem? Is it easy to generate more data, or is it difficult and other way in manufacturing? 

Speaker 1  (34:59)
There's a curse running around? It's called and braceer cells, you know, continues improvement. Everyone doesn't predict the right reasons every time I hope Generous improvement means typically Very little variance in your data. 

Speaker 1  (35:24)
Over time, yes, what AI models technologies learn from variance, if you have very little balance in your data models will not want anything, by the way, if you put it in, if you train a model, and it looks like 99%, you know, accurate. Don't be boy, there's something gone no AI models that 99.9% in the first shot right. If you deploy it, I guaranteed mark my word, it's going to look 62% accurate in production. 

Speaker 1  (36:00)
As the dealta between when you don't have any variance and you put it in an environment, and you expect it to react, when there's no variance, it goes down about 62% accuracy, all lesson a lot of failure that okay, the difficulties in the same way. Then engineering effort, AI modelling. Effort, implementation effort changed management. 

Speaker 1  (36:19)
You know, talk to your people, right with they accept to be guided by an AI assistant or not. Is a now that's not for me. Change management issues studio, so make sure you take these things in and then I will give you a global assess. 

Speaker 1  (36:39)
I'll give you that formula and you know, just make sure you go through these projects. Step 3. Now you take the 1 203 to the top 3 projects that will come out of that second step. 

Speaker 1  (36:52)
Now, you can, you know, push a little bit more efforts with its word actually going down that route. Right now, you have enough evidence that this project will solve solve a real problem. You probably have all the checkbox with most of the checkbox of data related change management. 

Speaker 1  (37:13)
The way that people related process related stuff covered by that little matrix, right and Just ensureful, you get sort of little handout here. Don't over promised because then the board will expect it comment mistake just under under shoots and then overshoot. The results were AI's always good. 

Speaker 1  (37:40)
So once you have those 3 projects, right when you have to be in mind, and we'll go through a process here. Very rapidly, it's called working backwards. So we're going to work from defining our challenge and numbers, right? 

Speaker 1  (37:56)
So that we can track the right metric to see how well we are going to be doing once we deploy it in the real production for And I really strongly encourage you to do this. So the problem is defining what the problem is, right based on your environment. And we believe AI can help because okay, we'll provide measurable evidence either through group will be increased. 

Speaker 1  (38:24)
Utilisation rates will go up. Waste numbers will go down something with a specific number. We know data exist, or can be collective model. 

Speaker 1  (38:34)
It involves critically, high frequency, repetitive patterns of decision process. So these are the ideal challenge, right? This is the bulllpaper and a physical earlier today. 

Speaker 1  (38:50)
But there were 600 parameters, 20 quality parameters, and 40 controls that production. A lot of it was manual points. So, humans still in the loop. 

Speaker 1  (39:05)
So even if I do millise, second inference on my AI model, guess what doesn't matter because the gymen will not act. In norvey, second 5 programme, so in these cases, historically what they were doing is they were clipping a little piece of paper feeding it to the lab, and then from the lab results they would go to the control room, the control room would send the adjustments and the technicians would go on to shop, or you. Move the stuff. 

Speaker 1  (39:34)
There was a lag of 30 to 47 minutes, depending on on The WHO is doing it that day. Um, to act, we brought it down to okay. What if an AI model just sends to the definitions directly every 5 minutes? 

Speaker 1  (39:53)
A few minor trades do you know, stay within the 20 quality products? So again, when you pick up the implementations, this is not an ideal scenario, right? Because ideally you would want to potentially automate putting new systems in place, but the capital investment in this would be just far exceeding the returns. 

Speaker 1  (40:13)
We don't do it right, but Okay, what we did as simply in the little It's a miniminterface on the shortboard that the technicians had access to already. We just added these like errors. Increased temperature decrease the speed whatever so that they can go and change the behaviour and stay inspect. 

Speaker 1  (40:40)
And thanks to that, the awarded huge breakage behaviour rules, they reduce their waste. That's part of time. They increased the productivity and big bonus. 

Speaker 1  (40:56)
Encoders, the only specific people could actually be on the shuttle. And instead of historically, it was going older people that knew exactly because they have been doing for 4 years, these people could not be on the shop floor for obvious reasons during that year. So the youngsters were able to go on and the actually beat the older people which they were very proud to their union. 

Speaker 1  (41:22)
So it generated some interesting dynamic. Other feed people in the new resources, maybe, but both in the end, where I can't get back as well. So the example was, and this is just an example how you define your business, challenge and again, numbers are important here, not because they're going to be accurate. 

Speaker 1  (41:46)
Well, because it has to describe your real business problem today. And what you intend to change it for and what's the value of it right. So in this case, we said the problem is, you know, on average, 28 minutes with raw material waste that startup time, and they have a hard time keeping the 20 quality parameters we can spec at all time. 

Speaker 1  (42:10)
They have, you know, poor quality productions, sometimes to time, which drives more lower margin products. Obviously can produce. And then, you know, we believe AI could be optimised, we have a low 86% from material efficiency. 

Speaker 1  (42:30)
So 14% wasted so okay reduce that say by half right. Just put some numbers targets at this stage. So this is the example that came up. 

Speaker 1  (42:42)
So what they did is then if we work backwards, right based on those numbers, make your board announcement, right? And 16 months from now from what I just describe as the problem right. Where do I want to end up? 

Speaker 1  (43:01)
And then announcement is has a pitle of the situation today which I just described the AI impact right? Where we're going to be with AI in 18 months now and how AI made the sponsible. So the example here is we went from 86% Material utilisation, efficiency, and we have achieved a 53% reduction right? 

Speaker 1  (43:30)
If I reduce by 50% of 53%. By the way, is one of you. Now I would have put 50% as target before we started project. 

Speaker 1  (43:41)
And it translated into 420k of raw material costs saved per year. So what? Stress error and Robin terros, so this is what you want to target with if you can as precise numbers as possible and yes, yeah, they're targets. 

Speaker 1  (44:04)
But at least 9 In part of the mind and a starting point Now the rest is defining your strategy. There's a couple of things that you want to look at just, and this is just my experience giving you some tips and tricks here. What data does AI need and I will recommend, right? 

Speaker 1  (44:28)
I know 2 school of thoughts. It just throw all the data in and over the bed, right I'll tell you why this is potentially a bad idea and potentially a good idea. If you have really high quality data, that's a really good idea. 

Speaker 1  (44:49)
Most of you deny, and I'm sure you'll say, not, and you really have Christine, beautiful day and it's noisy, but it's really good there and I got it. Pretty sure 8% of your sensors are flatbrid, or not working Just, let's start with that. Okay. 

Speaker 1  (45:10)
So here it's a bad idea to throw all the data in if you have a lot of thoughts and sensors that are stuck in weird position or offsets or engineering mentor and not working why? Because at some point a human being, we'll see it and we'll go in fix it. But your eye is not trained, it's trained on the flot. 

Speaker 1  (45:32)
It's not trained on the actual real data. So you want to make sure that the data you feed and minimally is actually good data. Not, you know, pristine, beautiful, like it can be very noisy data, but you can data aligned with their real process, and that's something that's not mind or stuck in the wrong, but there's lots of issues. 

Speaker 1  (45:58)
There's We need what do we need here? What the currently code collect or have? If you're needing to forecast a vibration on the motor and you don't have a vibration sensor well That is a little bit of a problem right, so if you need sensors to depict a problem. 

Speaker 1  (46:25)
You'd better put it in place verse before you start your approke, right? So it doesn't mean that you need to reinvest and change the work here, but if the inputs cannot, you know, solve your business across solve that first. So let's solve the input what you need to actuate data. 

Speaker 1  (46:45)
This negative decision, based on the data. You can have. Missing, and how do I add it? 

Speaker 1  (46:52)
So your experts typically should know, and it probably have a lotry list of things they would like to add, right. It's in there Thing that's a improved climb, they're continuous improvement, but laundry list of things. I'm sure he's done there somewhere that they wanted to add a pressure sensor or a ph sensor or something else sensor to get more data to be better at controlling the system. 

Speaker 1  (47:22)
So if it's missing, maybe it's the right time to make a small adjustment here. The sensor side data quality frequency issues, frequency issues simply quit, so if you know, measure or probe your sensor on a periodic basis on a second on a minute basis. On whatever basis, make sure that that frequency is the maximum possible that captures the patterns. 

Speaker 1  (47:52)
The reason ISIS, you know, if you collect temperature on a Millie, second scale. Well, you're collecting a lot of data appointment, nut. It's physically. 

Speaker 1  (48:03)
The temperature will not change on them to the second here, right? So you're wasting your data storage, you're wasting all the throughput and everything else that goes along with it. So be smart in the frequency. 

Speaker 1  (48:14)
You can go a little bit more frequent than the physical world. This fine not too much. Areas levels again as I said, continuous improvement. 

Speaker 1  (48:25)
That's the biggest error to people make it just learn from really not very preparing components. And that's a big issue. And the final one is data Axis again. 

Speaker 1  (48:36)
You store everything in spreadsheets today and there's 500 people accessing those spreadsheets today. Quite an innovation place with a little small layer, it doesn't cost much. There's a little bit source coupons you don't want to buy, you know, working software just dig yourself to favour, but move it works about switching. 

Speaker 1  (49:00)
Um, okay, stakeholders, very breeve. Uh, design, oh, so I'm here. Who needs to champion this? 

Speaker 1  (49:09)
And champion is really 2 levels. There's the executive sponsor right? That will want to pay for various components and it's not an a current budget right unless you have now budget this year for the united But we need someone higher up. 

Speaker 1  (49:28)
That is onboard with adding some fuel to the deck separately. Equality, important, you need a champion that will be actually operating change on the shopf. Right? 

Speaker 1  (49:44)
If the changes do not trickle down to where the decisions are made or where the control points are you wasted all that and that money? We might resist and why and you might be surprised. It might not be a people that you think, but make sure you engage with that understand why they're so far. 

Speaker 1  (50:05)
By the way, in all the AI project. That's what the I projects over. 812 years now. 

Speaker 1  (50:13)
There's always been high hires. Because we're augmenting the people value by increasing profit and revenue perhead CFO's typically Don't care as much to cut cost, right? They might still do that. 

Speaker 1  (50:30)
They are on, but it's not going to be because of the app project. The AI project should increase the value. All the people in that external Partners need right. 

Speaker 1  (50:39)
And sometimes or others make sure, you know, engaged them early, right? And the process system integration Again, talking about putting in place database or data historian or aggrega of data. If you're dealing with the limitary, your images or videos or x-rays, make sure you have the system integrator in place that is a software system. 

Speaker 1  (51:09)
Not Person pushing a button if it's a someone pushing a button. There's going to be limited value. On the other aspect, is what are the controlable variables which will change the outcome? 

Speaker 1  (51:27)
And this may sound like a very simple thing to write down here, but a lot of people forget, right? They have inputs, they have outputs, and they build a model right from the inputs to the output and that model be beautiful, but once you have that beautiful model, right of the behaviour. Which points on input? 

Speaker 1  (51:51)
Can you vary? What on our real control of all things? Can you increase the temperature and you increase the floor are you stuck on the building as long you want to be the one you order with this? 

Speaker 1  (52:08)
What are the things that you can act on? Very important to label off front because you're going to have to face special attention, because if you don't have enough control on these variables, right or if by using these variables, you cannot change the outcome enough to make it valuable. But don't start Great You may have a lot of control AI models, but if they don't change the outcome. 

Speaker 1  (52:41)
The don't start. We're missing variables somewhere you're missing control. So checking the control variables vary important infrastructure. 

Speaker 1  (52:49)
Most people now understand maybe some infrastructure is dated risk assessment. I will skip the list budget technical risk, organisational risk. Freedom to operate is the biggest one that people forget in AI freedom to operate means right from an intellectual property perspective. 

Speaker 1  (53:12)
You're going to be creating something unique that's learning from your data in most cases, legally speaking, this is yours it we know within your firewalls, your fine If you do predictive maintenance for a Fleet of your product that goes out, and you embed the I model in it. You're not this true, distributing this outside of your walls. Do you still have freedom to operate there? 

Speaker 1  (53:44)
Or is there a patent that prevent you from using an AI model on your vehicle? It happens Okay, so I'm just listening it here so that you don't start in this beautiful old journey without checking these few race successor it doesn't take much time, but it does if you from a lot of hard headache down the road, so hopefully you've learned a lot today. If you Have more questions. 

Speaker 1  (54:15)
Of course. All these were based on the 200 plus projects naturally how projects we've delivery. If my speaker so kiarko, you're thick your AI reading this survey and just book a call. 

Speaker 1  (54:29)
So these are the 3 QR codes for follow-ups. They don't hesitate. I'll be here rest of a day and tomorrow. 

Speaker 1  (54:37)
Just stop me and come to our booth upstairs to chat. And it thinks a village often to deploy AI solution. So we're very good at partnering with a you know, consultancy, you already have or members you already play with? 

Speaker 1  (54:56)
Um, we understand there's a atroctive begain, either we go in there and so collaboration is key. And sincerely as Canadians, I think we're going to ourselves to collaborate more and bring a last year I've expanded my team. We're headquartered my chill. 

Speaker 1  (55:18)
I'm expending my team in sharono and Regina. I'm looking forward to expand more. So hope you do the same with your team's infrastructure. 
