
Speaker 1  (00:00)
Focusing some attention now on one of the most powerful drivers of future competitiveness. And that is industrial AI. Unlike sort of those general AI tools, GenAI, we see in consumer apps or sort of everyday software, industrial AI is built specifically for the factory floor it's taking working hand in hand with physical systems. 

Speaker 1  (00:26)
Robotics sensors, digital twins, real taking real-time production data and tackling tough manufacturing challenges like optimizing processes, reducing downtime, improving quality and driving real productivity gains. So to me, that's the kind of AI that really delivers concrete economic results. It makes us all more competitive and helps us win more businesses, something that we at linmar are certainly widely adopting across our organization. 

Speaker 1  (01:00)
And I would like to say I was actually just mentioning to the minister that last year, 2025, we won more new business for our Canadian automotive plants than we've won in the last 3 years. So pretty exciting times for our comedian operations, a little bit to the point we were talking about earlier about finding opportunity and challenging time. So pretty exciting about that and Jen has made supporting the adoption of industrial AI at top priority for sure. 

Speaker 1  (01:32)
I mean, that's obvious through our AI for manufacturing challenge and other programs, Eng has been able to bridge the gap between promising technologies and the reality of the shop floor so that's fantastic. In fact, collaborative projects that allow manufacturers to test to integrate and then scale these solutions and we're already seeing outcomes from that. So now it gives me very great pleasure to welcome the honorable, Evan Solomon minister of artificial intelligence and digital innovation and minister responsible for the federal economic development agency for southern nterio to speak about the government's vision for AI. 

Speaker 1  (02:17)
And to make an important announcement on angel funded projects that are going to further accelerate industrial AI adoption across-the-board in advancing. Actually, so please join me in welcoming, Mr. Sullivan. 

Speaker 2  (02:34)
Thank you. Linda, first of all, let me thank Linda linda's going to run off total powerhouse. Okay? 

Speaker 2  (02:43)
One of the great Canadian companies that we hear a lot about the headwinds that we're all facing right now, there are real headwinds. But lenomar has been one of the most important things Continues to build attracts investment here in Canada, best Canadian workers. I just want to thank you for your leadership, your whole family and the team, your leadership, your courage, your perseverance, your toughness, the ruggedness, let's hear Linda Hanford, also work at NJ factor. 

Speaker 2  (03:16)
I also want to say I don't know where jf, Jason and Robbie. As Robbie, you can wave there Robbie and the team at nget. This is an awesome conference. 

Speaker 2  (03:27)
And it happens because of what Jason and Robbie and the team at ngen are doing Lyndon, of course, part of that, so can we just give the folks at ngen a huge hand for putting us all together what we think I also want to give a quick show here by the time. I finish this speech and all we just thank you, but it's kind of important. One of my great colleagues is here, and I don't see her, but genocides. 

Speaker 2  (03:55)
This year, I want to give a shout out to Jenna, who's been a real leader in our tech caucus. She's fantastic Charles suesa from miss saga uc Charles here, the former Finance Minister. But now, a colleague here, Carlos letao has been here at Carlos, a japoscoe they had to leave, but they're all representing regions of innovation and tech across the country and here in southern Ontario okay. 

Speaker 2  (04:22)
These are my favorite routes. A room, a huge room full of builders risk. Takers people who are betting on themselves betting on Canada. 

Speaker 2  (04:33)
We just finished a very short turn. I think I'll do another tour, but we were just with my aunt and Tony's team who I've met with before, I think they're at the back who are revolutionizing what's happening in smart textiles, which will revolutionize healthcare delivery, literally textiles that can sense your body. Fantastic word made in Canada, IP in Canada, will revolutionize healthcare around the world. 

Speaker 2  (05:00)
Fantastic work to me exebo, we were just with Johanne. They're just around the corner there, doing fantastic robotics. Look, these 2 companies and all of you are here is exactly what ngen is all about manufacturers, engineers, entrepreneurs. 

Speaker 2  (05:18)
Researchers, people who don't just imagine our future together. But people who are literally building it. Sir, IP, your imagination and the capital I do a lot of these events across the country, so I was at calibria platform. 

Speaker 2  (05:34)
An incredible incubator for AI companies in Waterloo Vancouver, and every single time I'm in the room with builders, it's not just hope. It's confidence. There's a rugged confidence that we can build here in Canada. 

Speaker 2  (05:51)
This is not Colliana, stop, this is roll up your sleeves kind of practical. Innovation and builders, the kind of people who have been told know a lie, the kind of people who say I don't care about the word. No, I'm gonna build someone anyway. 

Speaker 2  (06:11)
That's why I love this place. Is she San de LA squaretero Calgary? Guadalupe a Vancouver batters, other builders. 

Speaker 2  (06:24)
I started my life as an entrepreneur. My partner and I built a company who worked hard. We sold it eventually I can tell you being an entrepreneur was the best thing I did. 

Speaker 2  (06:36)
And the hardest thing I did maybe being a parent. I've got 2 kids as well, but as an entrepreneur. You gotta decide you're going to solve a problem, but everyone else doesn't see that problem. 

Speaker 2  (06:49)
You've got to find a group of people that work with you and bend on you, you've got to find money and you've got to search for capital. You've got to find customers, you're the janitor you're the CEO at the same time. Sometimes you have to hire your best friend. 

Speaker 2  (07:05)
And sometimes you gotta fire your best friend. Sometimes your family says to you. What are you doing? 

Speaker 2  (07:11)
Go get a job and find some security but it's 3 in the morning and you're thinking about the bills you gotta pay, because it's your company. You're wondering if this is going to work And often the world tells you, no, it's not give up for me that is team. No team know is team no is popular. 

Speaker 2  (07:34)
The team knows the status quo. Know you'll never do it in Canada. No, you can't compete no, we can't give you money. 

Speaker 2  (07:41)
No. I'm not going to work for you. No, you can't have that team. 

Speaker 2  (07:45)
Note is popular. The world is full of team know. But when we were in a room like this, I got from a family of entrepreneurs, but brothers and entrepreneurs. 

Speaker 2  (07:57)
It's team, yes, these are the people that say, yeah, we're going to do it anyway. Yes, is much harder. Yes, is much lonelier. 

Speaker 2  (08:06)
Yes, the risks are higher. Yes, the failure rate can be greater. But yes, on a TBS, the rewards are much bigger, not just for the people in this room. 

Speaker 2  (08:16)
But for our country My job as the minister of AI in the minister of federal economic development is to facilitate and grow team. Yes, this group. We have to make this an army and a mission to say yes to our country. 

Speaker 2  (08:33)
Yes, to our builders, yes to our IP, yes to our innovation. And yes to building here in Canada and then selling around the world, we've got to get out of the way when we need to and we've got to give a boost when we have to that's the job, that's what we do at federal economic development, that's what we do. At engine, that's what we will do when we launch our AI national strategy. 

Speaker 2  (08:56)
Very soon, and so just let me give you the context of the world. We're in This conference is taking place at this is not another year. 2026 is Is It what the Prime Minister calls a hinge moment? 

Speaker 2  (09:14)
We are seeing the biggest political realignment. In history since the Second World War, our grandparents and our great-grandparents at the same time as a technological revolution. And we have not seen even when I started my company in the 90s in the digital, this is transformative what's happening in AI. 

Speaker 2  (09:36)
And when you get these two things happening together, this political realignment and this technological revolution, it is transforming our alliances, our trading relationships, our supply chains, our education system, and we need to seize this opportunity or as the Prime Minister says, if you're not right now. At the table you were on the menu. These 2 forces are colliding and how do we take advantage of that. 

Speaker 2  (10:04)
Now there's 2 kind of ways that people see this, what I like to call the pomp palms and the pitchforks they're going to get a whole bunch of people that are going to say AI is going to save the world. AI is fantastic. AI is got great benefits. 

Speaker 2  (10:16)
The pom pom crowd and then you got the pitchfork crab AI is going to destroy it, it's going to take my job. Both sides have real concerns. Our job. 

Speaker 2  (10:26)
My job is not to be with the pomp plums or the pitchforks, but to work with you, real entrepreneurs to craft a rugged pragmatic, middle path where we're open to the opportunities of AI. We are open to innovation. We welcome it, we encourage it. 

Speaker 2  (10:43)
We bet on it, but we are candid about the concerns. We are candid about the concerns if you're an entrepreneur. If you're a manufacturer, the pragmatic middle is where you have to be. 

Speaker 2  (10:57)
And Jen has always done that. And today's announcement is about forging that path. Now, why manufacturing? 

Speaker 2  (11:04)
Why this sector why is this a place that we're planting our flag today. Because our manufacturing sector is the most important, most strategically, critical. And maybe the most underappreciated part of our country, the heroes when I walk when I have traveled southern Ontario. 

Speaker 2  (11:23)
And we look at our advanced manufacturing industries. They are the most remarkable companies innovation entrepreneurs. But Canadians don't even know about them, they don't know how great we're doing here, but we're talking about 1.7 million Canadian jobs. 

Speaker 2  (11:40)
We're talking about the communities in siusa, St. Marie and Halifax, at Edmonton, we're talking about the industrial backbone of the country. And in a world that's Undergoing a realignment Where other countries are saying who could you trust Who can actually build things efficiently? 

Speaker 2  (12:00)
Where's the most educated workforce? Who has the sovereign industrial base to be a partner who has the energy The minerals, the workforce and the trusted relationships. The answer is Canada, Canada, Canada. 

Speaker 2  (12:17)
The world wants what Canada has, but it is a competitive landscape. Everybody is racing to integrate AI into their manufacturing operations. As Linda said, industrial AI is the race. 

Speaker 2  (12:32)
German South Koreans, the Japanese, the Americans not 5 years right now. The question for Canada is not, is this transformation coming? We know everyone in this room knows. 

Speaker 2  (12:43)
It's already here. Are we going to lead it or follow it? Are we going to fall behind it? 

Speaker 2  (12:51)
Or are we going to leave? We're going to leave because we ask mgen. Our global innovation cluster for advanced manufacturing to use advanced manufacturing in tech to help drive digital transformation. 

Speaker 2  (13:04)
And from day one, Jason and the nge team have created new opportunities for Canada's advanced manufacturing sector. Through the AI for manufacturing challenge, which is awesome engine, is supporting the PAN. Canadian AI strategy, in a very concrete pragmatic way. 

Speaker 2  (13:21)
That's why today I am very pleased to announce that the cluster is announcing another 20 projects under the AI. For manufacturing stream, AI for M The total investment is $79 million. That includes $29 million from engj match, with 50 million from industry Partners. 

Speaker 2  (13:47)
These 20 initiatives, by the way, that was pretty good. I thought it was good enough. These 20 initiatives will support manufacturers across sectors like automotive defense security, home, home, building life, science, food production, advanced materials like we just talked about. 

Speaker 2  (14:08)
And they're laying the foundation for our national AI strategy, and I'll say a few words about that. That strategy is built for rooms like this. But for all Canadians across manufacturers, researchers, workers, it's a strategy for TVS that keep the vedaso. 

Speaker 2  (14:28)
The strategy is led by our North Star. Our foundational principle, which is AI for all that means no matter where you are in the country. No matter what community you live nor Southeast west, AI will work for you. 

Speaker 2  (14:43)
An industrial AI will be part of increasing your productivity. We've heard from Canadians. We consulted with over 11000 Canadians in our national survey, they want AI built Here in Canada, 4 Canadian jobs. 

Speaker 2  (14:59)
They want sovereign AI, but they want to trade with the world. But they want our data, secure, they want our children to be protected. They want our jobs to be protected. 

Speaker 2  (15:09)
And they want to empower services to Canadian in our healthcare, in our manufacturing, in our transportation. Engine with 13000 Partners in its network spending the full chain of Canadian manufacturing connected to large companies, SMEs connecting research at the shop floor capital and ideas that network is exactly what the kind of thing. We would use to accelerate AI at the speed. 

Speaker 2  (15:39)
And scale that it demands now, when I talk to manufacturers, probably, all of you share this. Everyone wants five things and they want a plan that will support the 3 c's and the 2 t's they want access to capital, they want compute. They want customers. 

Speaker 2  (15:57)
They want talent and they want trust. On Capitol accessing access to financing for AI companies right across the stack series. A series B right up to mid cap and on is critical. 

Speaker 2  (16:14)
But companies who want to use AI and adopt AI are facing barriers on finance We're working to change that through direct investment, through derisking mechanisms that we love launched like our Public compute access fund that we launched Patient capital that understands manufacturing cycles and not just the spikes, and you will see a big chunk about it in our strategy on compute. You can't run serious AI without serious compute, and that's why we're investing in our sovereign compute. Infrastructure not necessarily just to compete with hyperscalers, but to make sure that Canadian manufacturers, Canadian researchers, Canadian startups have the capacity they need importantly at a price that does not Force them to take their workloads and their data offshore. 

Speaker 2  (17:05)
And that's why our public compute fund is up or called our compute access fund 300 million, that will be expanding. We've rolling that out as we speak and on customers. Most of you would rather a contract than a grant. 

Speaker 2  (17:20)
The government has a role in the demand side. We need to use and we will use our procurement power, faster and smarter to give AI companies from Canada and AI enabled manufacturers. Their first reference customer, their first contract, proof of concept that scale. 

Speaker 2  (17:37)
We're actively doing that. You've seen me sign mous with cohero, and there'll be others as our office of government. Transformation transform our transforms, our procurement system that will help smell What talent? 

Speaker 2  (17:53)
We've got it, we've got to keep it. Canada has extraordinary AI. Talent, as you know, obviously we've got the 3 godfathers of AI. 

Speaker 2  (18:02)
From vector Jeffrey hitton here Mila with yashua vengio and rich Sutton at Amy. But our university's Waterloo mcmaster uf Tc university of Alberta sherbrook, all across this incredible country, Dell houses, memorial fantastic. We've got we've got the talent, but we've got to keep them here. 

Speaker 2  (18:25)
It is time to stop the pattern. Where Canadians plant the seed and water it, we grow the plant and someone else harvest it and takes away. Our headquarters, our IP, and our best minds that is coming to a stop. 

Speaker 2  (18:43)
Our gold here is not to be transplanted nation. His headquartered nation, keep our IP here. Keep our headquarters here. 

Speaker 2  (18:51)
Keep your families here because you have access to capital talent compute contracts. We will also invest in reskilling the manufacturing workforce. That is going to be important. 

Speaker 2  (19:04)
Reskilling and empowering our workforce for what's coming is going to be vital. And we will invest in that, and let me just say one thing about trust. Technology moves at the speed of innovation. 

Speaker 2  (19:15)
But citizens move at the speed of trust. We have the lowest trust in AI. In the OECD, that's why our adoption rates in AI are 12%. 

Speaker 2  (19:24)
Among the lowest in the OECD, that is not good for the country that invented AI That means we've got to get the trust up. And We've got to make sure workers are not worried that AI will take their jobs but will create more high value jobs. For more workers, and I was talking to Lyndon lena, where they used industrial AI. 

Speaker 2  (19:47)
And they are hiring and growing and Jason's got remarkable data of a 122 use cases that they've tracked over the last year of companies that have adopted industrial AI in their processes. And they have dropped all the metrics of machine time use and they've had massive improvement across their production lines. And they've grown the jobs, so this is a really important moment. 

Speaker 2  (20:16)
Communities are worried about this. We have to build AI and trust and skills with good governance and show people people don't care as much about what AI is. But what AI does, how it's deployed fairly, how it can create jobs, how it can create companies, how the IP being here creates jobs. 

Speaker 2  (20:37)
And we will do that I want to see one last thing about AI. Sovereignty, many of you Our building companies where your main customer is. The United States. 

Speaker 2  (20:49)
I don't tell you this when we talk about AI sovereignty, sovereignty does not mean solitude. Sovereignty does not mean solitude. We are not here to build walls. 

Speaker 2  (20:59)
We are not turning inward. We are not telling you not to sell around the world. In fact, the opposite, we are encouraging it For many people, linmar is an example. 

Speaker 2  (21:09)
The US is the biggest customer. And many of you were seldom in that market. We will fight to protect access. 

Speaker 2  (21:15)
And we want that But we want to make sure that Canadians have options. In other markets. And then we have the IP base, so we can build scale and champion the companies here that is it. 

Speaker 2  (21:32)
We need to protect Canadian sovereignty to be strong. So we can trade around the world. What I love about this room is you're proving it's possible. 

Speaker 2  (21:41)
There are small startups here. There's massive tier one companies here are supplied to the oems, the auto sector their midsize companies. 95% of our economy is small, medium-sized companies. 

Speaker 2  (21:55)
And we have to support that. And AI will be used on the application and the industrial side. That's where we're going to see the big growth The pace of this technology is going to change, but we need to keep up I will say this. 

Speaker 2  (22:11)
The strategy that we have is not going to be like. We went out to Sinai and took 10 commandments on stone. And we brought him down the world doesn't work like that anymore. 

Speaker 2  (22:22)
It's an iterative world, we need to design governance models and strategies that have flexibility and change with the technology, just like you and manufacturing have to do so this strategy, we will launch it, but it will be governed by an iterative strategy where we listen, we will adjust. We will course, correct governments have to be right now. I'm more bold about risk. 

Speaker 2  (22:47)
We can't play It safe. As well or we will not be able to leave. That's why. 

Speaker 2  (22:55)
Canada's AI future has to be run the way a good leader. He runs their company and a good leader runs their community. A great team caring about the workforce skilling. 

Speaker 2  (23:11)
Investing in people. People. And the community, so that means I need your input, and I need your partnership, your candor your willingness to tell you what our policies are getting in the way. 

Speaker 2  (23:25)
Maybe when our programs are missing the mark We got a demand with each other. We gotta be open with each other. We gotta listen to each other. 

Speaker 2  (23:33)
Governments are only as good as the information they're getting for a lot of manufacturers and people. The federal government. Sometimes can be perceived. 

Speaker 2  (23:42)
This is breaking news as slow Too much talk you want action. Not a lecture you want to build Prime Minister Carney is a builder. The team is designed to support Builders and to build this country together. 

Speaker 2  (23:58)
This is the age of pragmatism, I can tell you this. I don't care what flag you fly blue. Red orange, green. 

Speaker 2  (24:08)
This is not a partisan moment. This is a pragmatic moment. Normally, I will say something like I would swear to her, but they keep telling me not to swear us, but I don't give a rat. 

Speaker 2  (24:20)
We want builders here, we support Canadians 10 we. Want builders And by the way, we want to protect your freedoms to do whatever to vote. However, you want, that's the democracy. 

Speaker 2  (24:37)
Believe what you want, follow what you want. But for Canadians that we come together, we work together. We build together, we do it together and then go off, and you're free to exercise your opinion. 

Speaker 2  (24:48)
That's the democracy you want, rugged democracy. We build, we support each other and then we leave your freedoms to choose yourself. And this is the age of the entrepreneur. 

Speaker 2  (25:00)
This is the moment I think when I have 2 kids when my kids look back on this moment. I think they will say this was the age of the entrepreneur. The moment very different when I started my company 30 years ago, when the distance between idea and execution has never been Shorter. 

Speaker 2  (25:17)
There has never been a moment where you can have an idea and execute it in quicker fashion. That's why you see professors at university like mark and white of machine learning. Prof. 

Speaker 2  (25:27)
at university of Alberta has research. Now she started a project at water system treatment. She's raised 10 million bucks. 

Speaker 2  (25:34)
She's like I have a CEO. This is changing how things are working and AI is going to empower companies to change. It's going to empower entrepreneurs. 

Speaker 2  (25:45)
And we're going to move at speed So when the Prime Minister talks about building Canada, strong and being a nation of builders. It's companies that have been here for 50 years. And a 100 years, they are still building, it's companies that have been here for 50 days that are just starting out. 

Speaker 2  (26:03)
It's rooms like this, where people who are risk-taking a risk who are betting on someone who some of your friends are like a new crazy who want to solve a problem. Who are investing in each other? Who are talking to each other? 

Speaker 2  (26:19)
And they're trying to build this country, and I am so proud to support nge, which is one of the best ways to facilitate this environment and these companies and team us. I know the world's going to be hard. I know the risks might be higher. 

Speaker 2  (26:36)
But when AA TBS wins, we all win our manufacturers, powered by Canadian, AI powered by Canadian sovereignty built by Canadian workers, is the version of team. Yes, that we are betting on today. And that's why this announcement is so important. 

Speaker 2  (26:50)
So I'll make my commitment to you. I'll show up, we'll keep backing you. We're going to change. 

Speaker 2  (26:56)
We're going to get some things right? We might not get everything right, and then we'll keep going when you fall. We'll try to lift you up. 

Speaker 2  (27:04)
That's the Canadian way when we fall. We hope we get the same. It's a partnership, it is not going to be an easy route we're in it. 

Speaker 2  (27:13)
We're in it together right now. But we need you, we need your optimism. We need to recognize, and we need you to keep building this country. 

Speaker 2  (27:22)
And be on. They keep the batteries And team, yes, I want to thank all of you for being here. I look forward to meeting many of you and again to end Jen. 

Speaker 2  (27:34)
Congratulations. Thank you. 

Speaker 1  (27:43)
Thank you so much. Minister Salman that was just excellent. I mean, what a great message optimism? 

Speaker 1  (27:52)
Of opportunity of entrepreneurship and I love the message about team. Yes, you know, Mr. Solomon, my father always told me. 

Speaker 1  (28:02)
Tell me how yes, not? Why not? And I told our people that every single day, how, yes, not, why not? 

Speaker 1  (28:10)
It's the same things, it's the same things you have to deal with to make it happen as the excuses. Why you can, and it's up to us as business leaders and entrepreneurs to make it happen. So thank you for inspiring this principle of people in our country. 

Speaker 2  (28:28)
That's 

Speaker 1  (28:31)
Okay, guys. We've got another panel coming up in just a few minutes. The team needs a couple minutes to get the stage set up for the group, so we'll meet maybe 5 minutes until we start the next panel. 

Speaker 2  (28:45)
I'm ready to ask you guys in airlines. 
