
Speaker 1  (00:00)
I'm for 70 years. We used to be called the college board of Canada and for that reason, I joined the organization and always here in Canada in here on my hotel. So some of the comments that we heard earlier, I pictured all of us have some sort of component rating here around me. 

Speaker 1  (00:14)
And the moment in the pride and her failure to be here 

Speaker 2  (00:16)
10 minutes. So what we're going? 

Speaker 1  (00:19)
He's kind of swing from, you know, the fabric of Canada and what the opportunity was to the other side, where the rubber hits the road. 

Speaker 2  (00:26)
So we have 

Speaker 1  (00:28)
Sort of the ngen brain trust here on the stage right now. So, you know, engine is funded over 300 projects and interacting with thousands of organizations and seeing how these products see how innovation works. And this team has seen the ball behind the curtains. 

Speaker 1  (00:46)
So this is a really rare opportunity to sort of mine the brain trust here. Imagine they've reviewed the express test they support hundreds of auto manufacturing projects across internet and quantum housing source. Sectoral focus here, you know, you have a subject matter, expert care that you can qualify. 

Speaker 1  (01:08)
I'm going to introduce and remember the main point. Among Floyd, some analysts here are experts, and I'll just list a few of the highlights. Here, I mean, experts and ib experts in DC experts in midtech, AI and nanotechnology. 

Speaker 1  (01:22)
And so again, the real opportunity here is not only to hear from what they've learned. That's the name of this session. By the way, lessons learned from the ngen portfolio of 300 projects, but if you listen closely, you'll actually get some insight into what's coming next all in different year. 

Speaker 1  (01:44)
So to my left ear, we have John singer. So he's the veteran here he's been here for over 3 years, but he's also seen a lot. So he has been a national director of rmbd, attention rc, and he has specializations in a fire group and mining and energy and clean tech. 

Speaker 1  (02:02)
Today's left, we have George Kelly's and he is at the other end, which is midtech and he also has a strong understanding of you know how technology fuels can be applied to different industries. In his lap, I haven't Papa girls, so another sea. Sweep, so someone who's seen that movie like 8 times and 3 hours have tell us that GE that Toyota, and then Where AI is subject matter of expert here. 

Speaker 1  (02:31)
And to her laugh, we have a Sharon hole, everybody's Sharon hole, where being an airtime Sharon Hoover, top 300 IP strategists in the world. So IP, if not as a factor which we all know it is. She is, yeah, exactly. 

Speaker 1  (02:46)
She is the one finally flavor came in arrow. So he is a specialist in advanced materials. But he's seen that as well has been an operating officer, and he's grown trans materials company too much than 2 top nanocompeanies in the country. 

Speaker 1  (03:01)
So these guys have seen that movie before the subject matter, executives that are now detained the directors that deliver the programs here at NGO. So with all of that, actually, our commitments to Sullivan, ask for around the philosopher went here. And but this is the team that is executed all of those projects and given them around her applauses, except into my senior year. 

Speaker 1  (03:26)
Okay, when that Frannie in mind, you know, most of your manufacturers are in advanced manufacturing or technology providers, so the framing here is pretty much refinished to solve and talk about how do you get the moment? So maybe we can just start at that high level. Considering the domestic challenges, considering geopolitical environments should manufacturers be thinking about investing in technology and innovation. 

Speaker 1  (03:52)
And it's 

Speaker 3  (03:58)
When I see a Roy, royal one had to be here. 

Speaker 2  (04:02)
There's an old 

Speaker 3  (04:04)
In manufacturing, if you want to do technology development, do the right projects, then do the projects, right? So do the right projects is about strategic alignment, making sure that you've got your working on actual operational problems, and then building a team around that collaboration aspect and then do the projects right? Is the execution? 

Speaker 3  (04:28)
So the government's making sure that you've got download. The colleagues also add color and details that I'm probably forgetting so it's the execution part, making sure that the governance is right. And executing and delivering on difficult 

Speaker 1  (04:41)
We're hitting the rubber hitting the road, which again is the That we're very impossible. 

Speaker 2  (04:50)
Being strategic about it, being realistic as well in terms of what your organization can take on and being focused on it. So sometimes it's more beneficial to an interim step, rather than audience, one of the ones that are either going to need a better return, immediately, made it easier to implement to see how we go and build a team up and also to make sure that you have a right human capital in place to do what your project that's been adding the impact 

Speaker 4  (05:25)
I would also like to add to George's point. Everyone is really excited about technology and about technology adoption. But many times as Mr. 

Speaker 4  (05:36)
Sullivan mentioned AI adoption and industrial AI adoption. Is only 12% people have a hard time understanding where to start. So my advice is really start with the problem, not the technology. 

Speaker 4  (05:48)
And really think about the bottlenecks that you're trying to solve for think about? Where are you? Where are your pain points? 

Speaker 4  (05:57)
In terms of timing wasted in terms of quality of your production. Your product and in terms of cost. So really look at the problem, identify, break it down to core elements and start to work your way off the elements so that you can really have a you don't have a firm handle of your problem. 

Speaker 4  (06:20)
You won't be able to handle a firm handle or technolog. Thank you so much. 

Speaker 5  (06:25)
We're gonna follow that every time you solve a problem, you like creating new IP. So where do IP have think about where where am I innovating? And what can 

Speaker 2  (06:36)
The scientists are going to 

Speaker 1  (06:37)
So um. 

Speaker 5  (06:38)
And as you are innovating, a manufacturing process thinks about are you developing those innovations internally? Are you using your internal people to make the solution happen? And if that's the case, are there potential ways to prioritize your solution? 

Speaker 5  (06:57)
You might not just be an internal implementation, but there might be other manufacturers out there that the same problem seem between ones. Would it be possible to monetize this solution that you're solving for yourself? And another aspect is if you not go to develop an innovation. 

Speaker 5  (07:15)
Alternatively, you are likely to collaborate with someone or hire contractors. In that case, you need to make sure that you are thinking about the IQ aspects. What including data right today? 

Speaker 5  (07:29)
In today's world AI informs, some data is very valuable. So think about making sure that it have contracts. Please to superior iPhone's transition. 

Speaker 4  (07:42)
Sir, I'm not a minute. 

Speaker 6  (07:43)
Fall up in the don't do it alone. There's someone in Canada working on this technology. And I work 

Speaker 1  (07:50)
Canada. 

Speaker 2  (07:52)
Dollars that are working together with those same culture and 

Speaker 6  (07:56)
Let me ask you, there's someone with the technology in Canada. That fits your pain point. So, look at home, better textilers, stay here. 

Speaker 6  (08:06)
Healthcare supported here, someone in Canada can help you 

Speaker 3  (08:10)
And workers 

Speaker 2  (08:12)
They were really 

Speaker 6  (08:14)
It really gets obsessed partn. 

Speaker 1  (08:18)
Relative diversity, so at brain transplant, again, these limits the title of this session, these lessons learned so again, it can make about it. There are some common patterns or common signals of successful applicants for successful projects. And so the question I have for you really is around those patterns, it could be a technical success. 

Speaker 1  (08:40)
The project, a post project commercialization, there are at least indicators that you can see for the question really is, what 1 of these proposals come across your desk? And what makes an innovation project successful in terms of the patterns you see and across all of these things? And amid, we'll start when I start writing the fire again, I'm going to give it to you. 

Speaker 6  (09:04)
Sure. I think it comes with starting to realize Bixby and the Indian style of project is that engine doesn't fund companies. We fund products and we are coinbase. 

Speaker 1  (09:15)
Energy structure, a project with the measurable deliverable. 

Speaker 6  (09:19)
During our reasonable time period it's achievable. Then, it'll be a successful project. Where has a good chance of being a successful project? 

Speaker 6  (09:26)
So that framing is really important. 

Speaker 5  (09:31)
For me, because I work with the ID aspect of the projects, the most important thing is having Partners that put these things, what I've been liberated and what I think will be generated from the project and have a plan, have a plan on how to determine leadership have been fix. 

Speaker 1  (09:50)
Bloomberg figure. 

Speaker 5  (09:52)
I have to protect the IP and think about how to find the IP with their commercialization supporting 

Speaker 4  (10:03)
And in terms of my experience, I've really seen projects succeed. That have at the onset of a strong alignment, a strong strategic alignment. The project Partners we mentioned the numbers occur in the stats that we funded 300 projects over a 1000 Partners. 

Speaker 4  (10:24)
And so each project typically repres On technology Partners and many times academic Partners, and so if that strategic vision is aligned from the outset, that's really a key gradient to a successful project. 

Speaker 2  (10:43)
Yeah, so I think you're doing a bit of a year in terms of collaboration and partnership etc, and that's where the appeal for is collaborative projects and Partners, that means that when you're going to submit a project to engine. For example, you need to have that mindset. This is not a supplier relationship. 

Speaker 2  (11:07)
You're working with some communication assets, making clear that you guys have been doing planning together that you need to have memorable outcome and agree on what is success to align on what success is for all the stakeholders. So that the project the right appointing in mind, at the end of the day, everybody needs to have a positive outcome on this success. To really creating it in the sense of you're in a partnership that we're collaborative together. 

Speaker 2  (11:37)
And the idea of this movement and programs to work is, let's say everybody gets something out of the weekend and stay away from the mindset, there's a supplier. And stay with some debt. 

Speaker 3  (11:55)
Collaboration, strong collaboration and governance to make sure that the project is a success. And the true success is the project going beyond the actual engine project. It's about success, get option. 

Speaker 3  (12:08)
So our impliing for the gene management are in hiring, so that the technology is not often is a challenge. But it's not the biggest challenge that goes beyond the adoption. The skill set off as well as that 

Speaker 1  (12:22)
So I would I appreciate the opening ground of soundlos here we got up-and-down, but now I've got to get specific. And I want to ask about IP, it's the Zeitgeist right now. You've heard it again. 

Speaker 1  (12:35)
Whether it be as previously where the innovation asset collectively, a few others. And you know the idea that you can't commercialize what you don't own is absolutely, you know, a beam here and a theme right across the innovation economy as well as the freedom to operate your fto, that you can't compete globally, and so I'm actually going to start thinking about each one of you and you're a subject matter expertise. So when you're up first so sit in the audience so not everybody's a huge organization, a lot of them are probably SMEs. 

Speaker 1  (13:07)
And they're trying to scale. So it's kind of a specific question. It's like a company SMEs, you know, given everything they're giving budgets, they're limiting time, their scope, and how do we build a meaningful IP strategy or position? 

Speaker 1  (13:19)
You know when I'm over presenting themselves here. 

Speaker 5  (13:23)
Yeah, I think it's perfectly expensive, so you need to really think about building something internal. I can knowledge and Ike capacity so that it can take on some of that initial preliminary research due diligence on your own. So it's important while you build this capacity to have an iPhone. 

Speaker 5  (13:49)
Every company should have an IP, even if you're a 3 person company. Just appoints someone someone who will take take IP and really operationalize it for the company. And this person needs to have access to leadership. 

Speaker 5  (14:07)
This person also needs to be freevy to company strategy, business strategy. And in that having this person, you will also really opponents on what makes the company unique. Great, what are your differentiators? 

Speaker 5  (14:29)
What is the technology that brings customers to you? So With that, you need to think about the IP, the wall that you need to fill to help you protect that. How do you prevent something else? 

Speaker 5  (14:44)
Replicating your technology? And another aspect allow them is freedom to operate that work thrown around a lot these days. What does that mean? 

Speaker 5  (14:54)
It's really an understanding of your landscape. Who are the players in your space? What do they have? 

Speaker 5  (15:01)
What IP do they have? That could potentially dobop you from doing what you want to do and operate and commercialize in the markets that you want to that you want to be in. If there is a workflop on IP strategy that is hosted by innovation asset collective tomorrow at 10 o'clock. 

Speaker 5  (15:20)
So please sign up for it. I promise you you'll learn something. Yeah, yeah. 

Speaker 2  (15:26)
So can I just add to that? And nice blood sharing on that. But engines here to help we're part of that partnership, and in this collaboration with you guys. 

Speaker 2  (15:37)
So, Sharon, of the resource for you, and you guys should feel welcome to leverage sharing throughout the whole process. We will challenge the projects develop the shared process around. Are you thinking about a and BC indeed about particularly around IP and part of the aspect of that is that we're still accountable for showing that you're creating that valuable asset perspective. 

Speaker 2  (16:04)
But we're here to help improve that process, including Germany and engines there to start commission with you guys throughout this program, to the projects. So Tonight, endless story on that is to take advantage of us as best you can to help your project be successful. And it's 

Speaker 3  (16:26)
In the anecdote, if you've invented a new mousetrap, and you're so excited about what you're doing, and you want to go tell the world, don't talk to share it first and protect it. I've been involved in a situation where a researcher got accepted to a conference and added a bit too much in the science and this book the actual pattern was the exactly report this patent was submitted. So talk to Sharon porch at home was not around. 

Speaker 3  (16:55)
If the Sharon Jerome are idea expert 

Speaker 1  (16:57)
Thank you very much. I'm just curious even though one's just eating here. So how many ice should test the audience turn off that? 

Speaker 1  (17:04)
How many types of body are there? Third D beyond hats beyond trademarks, beyond operator I've been asking the question and even by a noise, how many people have any intellectual property officially in the audience with a knot on their hand I'm lining up here and what about IP strategy behind that just not just ifp but this strategy that drives it to monetize it. 

Speaker 6  (17:35)
Yeah, of course. 

Speaker 1  (17:37)
It's just the one thing. So sharing sharing all okay, listen, let's talk about, because again you guys have seen all of these projects. I'm curious about I'm gonna again pick on you, George. 

Speaker 1  (17:47)
Because I know you are kind of AI don't want to say the back end of the business. But the one that sees all of these and evaluates us. So I kind of cares if this is the rubber, it's the road section you know? 

Speaker 1  (17:58)
Back to distinguishing patterns, you know what distinguishes are really well executed and jam project. And without naming names, kind of give us the good, the bad, the ugly, so that people have a sense of what's good and what are the challenges of doing that? 

Speaker 2  (18:14)
Somebody's points already. There's a deeper conversations and questions about partnerships. Collaboration, measurable outcome, what is success from a project that runs smoothly is one that has all its elements collected. 

Speaker 2  (18:29)
And so there's good planning, there's great communication across the Partners, and if they're preemptively thinking about not only what this engine want, but how will we be creating value? As a team and it's really about that. Teamwork. 

Speaker 2  (18:47)
If we start by at the beginning, I'd say the projects that seem more successful are the ones that have gained the engine going on. We have an entire project That is there to help us build your applications from the take advantage of them that if they're there to help and do that process to provide some input in the delivery, useful application. And then if you're successfully funded by agency, the larger the rest of the team here throughout that we're going to hold you accountable to your public funds, we're going to hold you accountable for execution a problem to be successful. 

Speaker 2  (19:27)
But what we're asking for is also the challenging that I mentioned earlier around, how are you creating about it? How do you measure those successes so that you can be successful? We want every single one of these engineering graphics to be a success. 

Speaker 1  (19:43)
We did support it more on that. Because there's something around the top side of it, whether it be posts like alumni training, I'm trying to get in the human side of this. You can have a domestic knowledge in the world in front of the team or the talent to execute on your kind of activity. 

Speaker 2  (19:58)
When everyone's looking at a lot of tendencies to talk about. Other people speaking, but we mentioned this earlier on human capital. Having the right people 

Speaker 4  (20:09)
So honoring it 

Speaker 2  (20:10)
How in? 

Speaker 4  (20:14)
And so as our infrastructure broad projects as we mentioned, we are very deliberate on having that collaboration structure because we do believe that part of the risking innovation is 3 slices together and hopefully those different kinds of talents and those different kinds of works together in order to really help derisk the project. So in terms of the survivability of companies that really just kind of amplifies, when you do that derising and the cooling of talents and one of the things that we look for in our projects is really a description of how these 3 types of organizations really are going to be working together. 

Speaker 4  (21:08)
So we look at the human side of it. We look at how the talent is going to be working together. And we look at how surgical are you going to be in your execution? 

Speaker 4  (21:19)
And those 2 are completely dependent on one another. 

Speaker 3  (21:24)
A quick word made me on alumni training. So we do have 300 plus companies that we funded over the course of the engine, and we do do leadership training for the sea suite. And we've had some stuff in Toronto, and we're looking at training, and I cover it much. 

Speaker 3  (21:41)
Also, so we do also look at that aspect of that. 

Speaker 1  (21:45)
Fantastic. I'm almost trying to get us back on track here. But I want to focus on what in terms of timing, but I want to talk about one big big question here, because each of you have subject matter expertise and each of your domains so I kind of want to say, you know, we looked at this and talked about what makes projects successful, but if we could crystal ballet for a minute start looking forward so everything that you've known, you know, in terms of where Canada win. 

Speaker 1  (22:13)
Where are the areas of domain expertise that you're seeing in the past? And that you're starting to see from down the pipeline, where should Canada be doubling down? So what manufacturing domains plus Canada? 

Speaker 1  (22:25)
Only going forward then. 

Speaker 3  (22:27)
I'm trying to settle it. My whole goal is for quantum quantum technologies. There's a actually, there's a bunch of boots with quantum technologies here at NV. 

Speaker 3  (22:38)
So those who go and visit them so quantum and optics can that actually punch us above its weight in terms of quantum technologies. So I think that is the place where we can make a difference. And we can own that space in terms of development. 

Speaker 3  (22:54)
It's still early days, but I think there's I think we're essentially in quantum where we were in AI 15 or 20 years ago. So still ways away, but I think it's a good play for us for Canada to be able to position itself. 

Speaker 1  (23:09)
That's the year the comments from minister sulomon. I think Lisa is in a panel this afternoon from quantum industry Canada, so we have a lot of subject matter experts here, so it sounds like you're voting. We started a trend of voting quite a month and apparently says yours. 

Speaker 1  (23:21)
What's your vote? What are you doubling down Canada on 

Speaker 2  (23:23)
Yeah, so I'm actually going to split my vote. So I'm a medtech guy in background. And you know So obviously healthcare, new medical devices, new technology, there's a whole bunch of work to be done in terms of software as a medical device as well on there. 

Speaker 2  (23:41)
But I also did spend time in the forces so defense and Socrates is a huge piece for me as well. And I think we're seeing that the minister spoke about that, we're seeing the news a lot now, as well, and we're hitting our GDP targets etc on that. So that's definitely an industry, and I think it's an industry when we talk a lot about fuel purpose industry that's going to see a lot of overlap. 

Speaker 2  (24:03)
In what we're doing so we might have conventional commercial products that can then be iterized, for example, and using the defense industry or vice versa. So there's going to be a lot of overlapping when you need to work with people. I'm not actually pleased to make sure that 

Speaker 1  (24:22)
National types of red side provides a DEA. 

Speaker 4  (24:26)
So if going back in our historical careers, I've spent a lot of time in manufacturing in my name, in automation and integrity and advanced materials and sector. 

Speaker 2  (24:41)
And 

Speaker 4  (24:42)
So I think all of those sectors that I've had the privilege of spending some time have been really areas where Canada has some quite a bit of domain expertise, manufacturing and mining. And I think For the future, for future view, I think we have to continue to play to our strengths, but I think we have to really accelerate the optional technology, specifically AI and automation, where we are lagging an OECD perspective, and I think we just really have to really continue to promote the option of this kind of technology to really bring those sectors into really the next stratosphere, and everyone is looking to Canada for that domain expertise in those areas. 

Speaker 6  (25:33)
I found so I was at the Saskatoon aerospace and defense conference a couple weeks ago, and I saw very clearly that Kind of dual use is a big deal. Going forward. We have a lot of expertise because of our primary resources. 

Speaker 6  (25:47)
And agricultural resources people making the tractors and the combines that skill set is transferable to defense industry. And I think there's a huge push. And a huge opportunity to leverage that no happen and to extend the ability to make tractors, for example, into the defense needs of our country going forward. 

Speaker 1  (26:08)
Fantastic, you know, we skipped over a Sharon, but I'm going to actually feel on intellectual property as a lens to define where Canada has technological strength in global specialization. So in the research we know we did an lq to find out where we have the highest concentration patents, then we then should share find out what we're calling faster than every single OECD nation. And when you over there, they can overlap them. 

Speaker 1  (26:37)
It's almost like an acg major single DC where Canada is leading anyone want to guess. Well, we do our number. Anyone want to guess what? 

Speaker 1  (26:44)
Number one is Definitely, manufacturing, you could imagine anything that's oiled like gas extract that was high up there. But surprisingly, someone on this panel would like dancer to number two in the tree and you want to guess 2 and 3 sectorally. Primary industries, actually, the primary industries is like our cash power, where I'm going to be very strong. 

Speaker 1  (27:14)
The answer is, number two and 3 is biotechnology and pharma. So life science is interesting enough, which could be advanced manufacturing, because it's enabling meaning that one that's the most emerging we found so still small but the fastest growing belonging shift share was the advanced materials. Now and we call them semi structural materials, which is really quantum the underlying materials for quantum. 

Speaker 1  (27:36)
So even from a true research analytical standpoint, the country has absolute strength. So to your point, we kind of skipped over you, but if you don't have the right to charge and collect those rents for our ideas, we actually have them here in Canada, as a common source of great voting that you've done I want to do a quick lightning round of what advice would you give and then we can all head out to a lot of so essentially. I'm assuming everyone here as it applied for the interest in applied for undeliberable capital, whether that betended for and so the question I have for your lightning ground is if they're making up a blind thing. 

Speaker 1  (28:19)
Like one piece of advice would you give particular? We'll do a sturdy stop that they should either start doing and stop doing to make them something more successful. If those applications 

Speaker 2  (28:31)
Go ahead by that guy. 

Speaker 6  (28:32)
I would interact with us. We're here to help 

Speaker 1  (28:36)
So start getting in touch with the panel. 

Speaker 5  (28:41)
This is thinking about myths. You know, when the IP think But that's not amazing. So people are missed. 

Speaker 5  (28:54)
I think that's one thing that can really hurt the company in terms of socialization. 

Speaker 4  (29:02)
I would say, start thinking about those collaborations. People seem to be a little surprised that engine funding is available for projects, not companies. And so really start thinking, strategically and not only for engine funding, I think you should always think it strategically, thinking about your alliances and your collaborations. 

Speaker 4  (29:23)
But start thinking about those alliances, the collaborations that you watch students bring into your ecosystem to help you really speed up more than your buildup and come to us with the ideas and more than happy to help and also be aware of any other types of nonverbal funding, we're also here to help who can give you some guidance on how additional programs that are out there? I do want to mention, though later on this afternoon. There's a workshop downstairs for the smart irrigator program picking up, not that they're funding at 1 PM. 

Speaker 4  (30:00)
And tomorrow R French brother, the EU delegation are going to give a session for horizon Europe and there's night €3 million available for research innovation projects. So I just wanted to put that little plug out there in case you're wondering what your tomorrow and this afternoon might be wrong. 

Speaker 2  (30:19)
Yeah, so it's kind of building off of what Flavia was saying. But early engagement with engine, understand what our programs are asking for read the questions and know. This sounds really simplistic, but there's a set of questions in every application really understand what they're asking for and where those questions are coming from, you know, I don't want to get to the mechanics of a well structured application, but a lot of that is when it comes down to is how you've structured? 

Speaker 2  (30:45)
How you've answered the questions. Is there relevant information in there? Are you succinct in the presentation of that action? 

Speaker 2  (30:53)
And then being transparent with us through what the entire process mentioned this earlier were a partner in this with you were there to help you to be successful and you need to understand where we're coming from again. Public funds et, cetera, we come to build And how our system works, but ultimately, we're there to help you through it. Okay, where we want to see you succeed, and that should be the mentality that you take going into this 

Speaker 3  (31:20)
I agree with your colleagues. I mean, engaged early as early as possible. If, for whatever reason we can't help you, we're happy to introduce you to Other programs, other funding development agencies so engage with us early and often 

Speaker 4  (31:36)
And also, if I could add once our programs open, we also work very quickly. So you have to be really ready to have all your kind of ducts in a row, be ready to respond, because we're here to help, and because the program is kind of statistically comparatively quite quick, quite fast. Leverage users, but be ready to work. 

Speaker 4  (32:01)
And then accelerate accelerated pace with engine. 

Speaker 1  (32:04)
What a perfect way to end the panel? I wanted to thank the panel. This is the brain. 

Speaker 1  (32:08)
Trust you've heard some of the lessons learned here. 
