
Speaker 1  (00:00)
It's organizations successful The same as people I don't always want to analysis. If people know how to learn and how to write out how to knock their work with that as well as someone to know something today. 

Speaker 2  (00:16)
Shameful blood come to my workshop at 4 PM uncovering my thought. In terms of capability now, I think it's Right? That supplier, fire vendor and who should be in charge without even mentioning that from the impact of iteration is every 3 months. 

Speaker 2  (00:40)
So every 3 months, absolutely need to be Who should be in charge here in Canada? I had a jury, and then so maybe I could take a stab at this from an AI for manufacturing in Canada, which is the engine subcluster. That was generated in front of a partial AI engine as well. 

Speaker 2  (01:03)
That group is an industry lit group from the president of the board and it's essentially more than 40 companies that are getting together to educate and classify all the use cases. And as a use case Explorer, for companies, money enlarge to see what works. What doesn't work with the processes? 

Speaker 2  (01:24)
And as the 40 companies in our industry and companies, they are in the industrial AI Space, specifically, and they essentially do all the survey of technologies and changes in the, you know, fresh and aware of what's going on what works. So I think that as a source for AI, from the production Canada, it can go through that website and see that there's the maps of various suppliers, what they do. What they use space Explorer, I think, is the key, and we're working on right now as A Pursuit to pull away for our Canadians. 

Speaker 3  (02:02)
I think my question. I'm pretty sure Christie from the agent, the chief, the chief asked me to open a question, and it seemed like a perfect Christie question. It's amazing any other shaping your head. 

Speaker 3  (02:17)
Many other questions I've applied to questions throughout the Powell. Just want to go. Applauding these questions 

Speaker 4  (02:30)
So this is a question for Linda, I think I had an opportunity to ask life to do some work on work. And the culture there always stood it for me. So questions, what do you have to change or have you changed in the culture to help technology to be adopted? 

Speaker 5  (02:50)
Yeah, I think that a really important part of the liberal culture has always been around continues improvement. That's always been around. How do we improve every single day? 

Speaker 5  (03:02)
You know, every single day with oil on our shop floors. And we look for ways to do things better, and every day we find them. And you know, we like this as an example, we have a program that I personally run at land of our health costs attacking Pat, and I go around to every one of our plants and I spend hours with them going through ideas around how we can do things differently, and even though some plants I've been to multiple times every time we go back and we find something, and that's because technology is constantly evolving. 

Speaker 5  (03:36)
Right? So there's always new technologies, new tools, new software, new suppliers, new ideas that we can employ. So how can that culture that he looks for that? 

Speaker 5  (03:51)
That is an afraid of change? I You brought up change change like being okay with change, not just okay with it, but looking forward and excited about it is a really critical part of a culture that really embraces these new technologies. So, you know, having the trust, you know, not trust goes by that, you know, the, you know, every time you get better, we get stronger on that Cris. 

Speaker 6  (04:18)
More opportunity to keep farming, and there's more opportunities for us. So driving that 

Speaker 5  (04:24)
That image in your culture and I think is sort of a critical part of these interpretations. 

Speaker 1  (04:31)
It was like, just to throw something kind of like general like there was we talk about culture, something I always think of as culture is created like behavior rewarding every punch to say, beyond the system where you're going to try and find improvements where we have people bringing those improvements. We say, great job you want to be more like when doesn't do that? When you have people like come on, I'm not going to do that part of your change. 

Speaker 1  (04:55)
And I don't want to do that, it's caught in your organization, the people in there and be like, hey, that's not what we do. We have a culture of change. We have a culture of improvement. 

Speaker 1  (05:03)
And that's what they do the way you're acting. That's not what we did. It sounds simple. 

Speaker 1  (05:08)
Sounds easy. All it does to do that do more of this level. That's not easy when you want to date a d***. 

Speaker 1  (05:12)
Sometimes interior your top person, who's not actively. You want them to be, you can't act you have to push back on that. And it's on the leaders to do that. 

Speaker 1  (05:21)
If you're a leader in everyone's leader, in my opinion, the fear is that his actions, opposition is something that I can think of know. But that's how you make change within your organization. Create a culture of what you want to see. 

Speaker 5  (05:33)
Yeah, it's so interesting, because Amber Pat's session we start off with why don't we do cats, because they embody our culture as northernization of being responsive and doing things today and not waiting for tomorrow. And how yes, not? Why not? 

Speaker 5  (05:51)
I am looking at small things as well as big things. And you know, not just being about cost improvement, but about teaching and learning like I learned every single path I teach things like great ideas and sometimes we come up with ideas right there. And then that can then get rolled out across the organization. 

Speaker 5  (06:11)
Every Pat we start with that little script of this is why we're doing it. This is why it's an important part of our culture and activity. I you know whether it's a plant that's dark portic. 

Speaker 5  (06:23)
So we're at 9, we start with that, will 

Speaker 6  (06:26)
So latter. 

Speaker 5  (06:29)
It's important and also to you know, one of the really important things to say is we're not here to catch him in something wrong. We're not here in a negative way to look for oh 

Speaker 6  (06:40)
Put it, you know, you put it down magically, and you're not doing 

Speaker 5  (06:44)
We're here in a positive way to find new ideas, bring new ideas, stuff that you never even thought of when you put this program. I am in a place that's you know, new and we're running to the table. This is not about finding blame or that you've done something wrong. 

Speaker 5  (06:59)
And I feel like that's really an important part as well. We began. 

Speaker 6  (07:04)
These programs is to make people realize 

Speaker 5  (07:06)
This is about blame and negative. This is about positive and that we're excited about learning, we're excited about finding opportunities together. Otherwise, we'll be implemented $81 million of implemented improvements last year. 

Speaker 5  (07:22)
Then, the cap program 

Speaker 1  (07:24)
When you're talking about when you talk to people, what's in it for me? It's not how lean it's about a possible experience. This could be better for you, if this is why it's going to be good. 

Speaker 1  (07:33)
Here's the benefits. I see if you can't question that to somebody, and I say I want you to change and I go, you know, what's in the movie every Maybe something you ask what planet it might be if I get a little benefit. 

Speaker 3  (07:48)
Let me ask you. I like the hospital just one last question. And kind of just add something hidden. 

Speaker 3  (07:54)
You could maybe think about in 10 years time for your pocket rather than fundamentally, at wrong points. Original pathologies, we could think about liquid neural networks and benefits and white law decision-making for AI. And I thought you might actually change the public perception. 

Speaker 6  (08:14)
Yeah, I mean it's impossible for David, which mindset we've underestimated and underestimated necessarily, but I think They, you know, in general, you are overestimate the impact of a technology in the short-term and underestimated in the long-term. So 

Speaker 5  (08:30)
You know, I think that 

Speaker 6  (08:32)
I'm sure there's things that were underestimating right now and things that were overestimating. But the point is to always be improving and always, you know, staying harassed at the latest. 

Speaker 5  (08:44)
Technology has left between overall here. 

Speaker 6  (08:47)
So do you like to learn from all these amazing companies about the things we could do the question around how to get SMEs, you know, how do they approach? This first is awareness, right? What's out there and what can't consider so much that I think we don't know that we can already do. 

Speaker 6  (09:05)
So let's start doing those things and then keep building on it. 

Speaker 2  (09:09)
10 years is a longtime frame, but let's say finally back in 10 years. I would hope that I'm seeing that shockwave changes actually. We're depositive in the next 10 years later. 

Speaker 2  (09:22)
I'm hoping that that's what we'll figure out. Despite pray now, I am in the last couple of months, a year has been challenging. Development challenges ahead, I'd like to help you out. 

Speaker 2  (09:36)
And various permentations this morning about, you know, seeing life through a little bit of our place with cracks and we're seeing light seeing where the board. So it's kind of that kind of attitude that I think would be through And make changes and yes, shockwaves are difficult to handle and difficult changes are difficult to handle periods. But I think what we'll see happens in thin years. 

Speaker 2  (10:05)
We will all be clear in the glass that we need to exchanges in the 2026. 

Speaker 7  (10:11)
Now it may have just happened that, you know, with every revolution that's happened. There's no light fear about what will mean. But overall Humans have been kind of better off on the other side that progress in produce quality. 

Speaker 7  (10:24)
Like and I think whether it's AI, whether it's quantum, there are real insulin spirit about it. And the impacts it on that. But humans are resilient on the other side of that, that efficiencies benefits the lower development. 

Speaker 7  (10:38)
So much better than it doesn. 

Speaker 4  (10:44)
The pronouncement of it. 

Speaker 8  (10:46)
My external times but also with that massive time for opportunity, I think the massive time for recess in our country right now. And a lot of the conspiracy I don't use your technologies, researchers and selections as well, and maybe going back to the trustee's candidates. Whether you trust it, our researchers trust it. 

Speaker 8  (11:04)
Our companies are trusted earlier. When it's a massive opportunity for us to leverage right now, to bring that in not just the veteran of our country. But for what we've been sharing, which has to Partners and allies internationally, and I think we can do a lot right now to be revised by example. 

Speaker 8  (11:18)
And that's why you hope we can move back into years from now. We're really, really proud of the choices we're going to be today for where it's going to bring us to phase of 2036. 

Speaker 1  (11:29)
So I think When we look back at the importance of our grails and responsibility and these data, I think it's been something we look back on. On that tweet, we will be here at the forefront of anything, but there's not a lot of people in that space, in my opinion and we'll be implementing their own understanding and how brightness and burial's narrative that there would be examples for that activity that both situations have to deal with. I think I have to worry about that some of these things. 

Speaker 1  (12:01)
But we don't know where those are. That's the problem when it comes to these things. That's not the right answer, but it is a good understanding. 

Speaker 1  (12:10)
Why you measured all those things, which is all these sexual deals. 

Speaker 3  (12:16)
I'm gonna have my list of hired. Will that blocks the power of a flight to flight flight? The palace for such great fit and discussion 
