
Speaker 1  (00:03)
So I perceived my role to be. Well, we're gonna just work on upskilling or reskilling employees and work in the workforce. It's kind of scanned and beyond that a little bit more and really uptake a broader view and trying to look at that we did some research around whether skills required things that understanding research, but also understanding how do we bridge the gap between academia and industry. 

Speaker 1  (00:28)
So, really? I mean, a lot of the training happens that academic institutions and but then there's also research projects, and you know, when I came from the university sector as well as college sector I used to be a director of research at state their college and Windsor I'm very familiar with the academic world and industry. Always in the manufacturing many years ago. 

Speaker 1  (00:47)
So I kind of it's a perfect role playing, and so one of the things I found was doing research projects with companies we would engage with them. But then that was really the first step, and then there's the training that has to happen as well on the upskillion. So now I'm trying to morph into, let's engage with get academic institutions and the industry engaging, I'm a projects and integrate the workforce transformation app. 

Speaker 2  (01:16)
Gasping, does that fascinating? I mean I mean, I'm doing my PhD at Dahl's university and my main major is electric car. Engineering, while focusing also on AI how we can use AI. 

Speaker 2  (01:27)
In some kind of in the grid, like no social power, or something like that, because obviously they do have an issue the main thing that every time I just see as barrier I just adore big door is that industry somehow doesn't trust the Academy at some point, because they say that we're here Academy is here, all of the ideas that you say super fantastic. But implementation, how we have to change the classic way how we have to train people, how we have to deploy everything is an issue by seeing that seeing some kind of programs like laptop market, actually, the idea of laptop market is like this. 

Speaker 2  (02:03)
You have an idea. Move it from the lab, put it in an industry that's where we have to talk to people all this kind of things that actually you train people you educate them, that how we can grow for people going to connect it, that's a real, huge need at least, so I can say for Canada right now. It's 

Speaker 1  (02:19)
It's the adoption. This 

Speaker 2  (02:21)
Yes 

Speaker 1  (02:22)
It is now actually the focus of our dis 

Speaker 2  (02:24)
Oh, my God, I missed it. I was just going because yesterday. I wasn't very active and today I was just talking with the people in the group so yeah, I missed that but probably yeah, but, yeah, for sure. 

Speaker 2  (02:35)
Can I have your maybe some kind of recard? I'm sorry you're doing yeah, Exxon, thank you very much appreciating it. 

Speaker 1  (02:44)
So our meeting wasn't posted anywhere. There was imitation only oh, really, so that's why. 

Speaker 2  (02:50)
So okay. 

Speaker 1  (02:52)
Like I said, what I was trying to do all the all bank contacts that I've had across the country. I just sent an email to say, hey, come to the conference and And then I also probably had a dated list. So the list that came out while the attendees I just looked at all the academic email addresses. 

Speaker 1  (03:14)
I added them to the email list. So I'm not sure when you were added to this list but I didn't have your name on it. 

Speaker 2  (03:19)
Because the issue is that even yesterday I went to some kind of the front booth to get my some kind of car and they told me that we don't have your name over here. So how is that happening? I paid for that. 

Speaker 2  (03:31)
I know. I'm here, and that's why I mean they printed after that. So that's maybe the issue. 

Speaker 2  (03:36)
But, yeah, again, so thanks that I saw you over here. I mean, there are so many people around, how is the chances that we can make? Yeah, thanks. 

Speaker 1  (03:45)
You're the connector what do you do then? 

Speaker 3  (03:52)
Open wide new, or what is my company biggest boat we make To make artillery shell factories, we make nuclear submarine halls. The semiconductor part. So we make We make stuff that's impacted, and you know, build out from there. 

Speaker 3  (04:11)
So 3040 years ago, we made big asset hydraulics. Where the North America's largest hydraulic press manufacturer, and we're the world's broadest press manufacturers, typically authorities. And it's not that we're What we're good at is a here's a challenge. 

Speaker 3  (04:38)
We'll throw 10 engineers at it or whatever and solve the challenge and mock up all the types of sensory and respect why we. So, you know that's why we have such a fraud capability. 

Speaker 2  (04:52)
Holy Canadian. 

Speaker 3  (04:54)
We've done 5 projects. 

Speaker 2  (04:56)
Do I think 

Speaker 3  (04:58)
Super plastic gas oscillation, super plastic forming The gentleman not sitting in our boost. He's a ph school invented that Kind of cool. That makes sense for me right now. 

Speaker 1  (05:15)
Where you're looking 

Speaker 3  (05:21)
You have 2 facilities in 

Speaker 1  (05:23)
Okay. 

Speaker 3  (05:24)
One in Kingston, one in the US joint venture in Mexico want a company and 

Speaker 2  (05:46)
That's the booth I was looking for yeah, I was just looking for a d*** Aon 3D I guess yeah, I was just looking for a name just moving around moving around. But the discovery, yeah, no, no, no, I'm not, yeah, which is I wasn't short up my apartment. 

Speaker 3  (06:12)
It's a challenge, the corporate and Academic growth I taught I taught for 3 years. It was hard time for me, but it was a whole time position. And a Business School I learned a ton. 

Speaker 3  (06:31)
And the way I reason why I thought was there a lot of really good All right, so how do you tell them? And still got our teeth I mean, that wasn't the only reason why One of the reasons student language It's good. So do you enjoy the research side? 

Speaker 3  (07:02)
Or do you enjoy the like? 

Speaker 2  (07:05)
So the idea that I started my PhD at the beginning was, I was so into AI and I really would like to move it to the next level. By obviously reading more published more going to the conference going to done up events find some fascinating people like you. But another reason that I was going to pursue my academic, some kind of cooler thing and hopefully become a faculty member become assistant officer, because I'm so into teaching. 

Speaker 2  (07:35)
I mean, I used to teach at navy college. We had it at some kind of calipex, so I used to be there for 3 and a 1 years. I also thought feed our housing university since 2021I enjoy teaching and most importantly, I enjoy learning. 

Speaker 2  (07:54)
It doesn't matter what kind of specific is that my background is electrical engineering. But right now I'm into mechanical, I'm into computer engineering. I'm into everything I'm into aerospace recently, because I have to have some kind of knowledge, but yeah, I mean, I sense that I sense the issue between academic and industry, that's what I was telling you so that we do have fascinating projects, very talented people at the university. 

Speaker 2  (08:20)
But they cannot enter the area of industry because of all the deployments as some kind of their adoption issue that we do have. Yeah, that's the sea. I mean, most of the people, especially the PhD ones they're just staying at the lab. 

Speaker 2  (08:35)
They use some kind of research. They don't know what is happening in the outside of war. So since I came from the background that they talked with industry people I talked with so many people I said that. 

Speaker 2  (08:45)
Okay, right now I'm a PhD, but I also have to be industrial person. I have to know how I can use my research in the industry. I have to find a use case for that. 

Speaker 2  (08:54)
So that's why I'm over here. I mean. I'm not funded from anyone else. 

Speaker 2  (08:59)
I just paid from our own pocket. Because this kind of this kind of conferences is just not very diamond. It doesn't so you have to find them that you have so many great people to talk to in person. 

Speaker 2  (09:11)
Yes, I can't send you guys email to say that. Okay, who the heck is this guy? I mean, I don't know, but right now you see me face-to-face, you see that I'm passionate about my work, I'm about learning about knowledge so I can connect with you. 

Speaker 2  (09:24)
And maybe feel some kind of more connections with some kind of it. That's the reason we have. 

Speaker 1  (09:29)
Talk about what sargasso 1 o'clock on the pitch stage, we're going to have a number of academics pitching their work. So okay, let's go with one in ground 2 o'clock for now. 

Speaker 2  (09:42)
Probably yeah, I have to check yeah. The pitching is very important recently accounted out. I mean, I'm working on my pitch, but, yes, so elevator page or any kind of page, but 

Speaker 1  (09:52)
Yeah, it might be good just to stop by. 

Speaker 2  (09:54)
I don't have to see what's going on. I'm sorry you were saying 

Speaker 3  (09:56)
I was going to say, you know, the evermore guys. If a booth from the far side 

Speaker 2  (10:04)
Answer. 

Speaker 3  (10:05)
Evermore their AI consultants? Okay, I mean really their guides that have worked in In fact, the environment I linked them up with our guys in academia. As PhD right, I don't know, maybe longer. 

Speaker 3  (10:23)
But the idea is, you can't do everything so with your AI interest, what are the run workshops? You're talking to my guys saying, here's some stuff we can do to make you aware of things. The model of different things. 

Speaker 3  (10:42)
I mean, our company is growing really rapidly. We've probably only used AI to read manuals and to do some stuff like that, which is okay. 

Speaker 2  (10:52)
Right, sufficient. 

Speaker 3  (10:55)
I do it because I'm new to the industry. I'm in and I don't understand anything. So I can read about it. 

Speaker 3  (11:01)
And ask it questions. If it were fortunate well for 

Speaker 2  (11:04)
It's fascinating, correct. 

Speaker 3  (11:06)
Continue to another level if you're building a factory that you know? Temperature changes change temperature lag times or whatever you have to build lots of you know, exit ramps and then I'm sure and we do have quality challenges. Because a lot of them, what we did to do 

Speaker 2  (11:25)
Sackled, yeah. 

Speaker 3  (11:27)
I've been people hire us because they want insistent results, right? And so when you've got 50 different touch points, the more accident Hey, how do we do it change this little? Established, speed it up, heat it up. 

Speaker 3  (11:43)
AI is going to help with 

Speaker 2  (11:44)
Exactly, that. 

Speaker 3  (11:46)
So that's what they do, which may be of interest to you. 

Speaker 2  (11:49)
Whenever the levelmore you mentioned right, I have to see 

Speaker 3  (11:52)
There's going to go see, oh, my gosh. I figured if he says, yeah, the suspended probably. I need to break down that thing. 

Speaker 3  (12:04)
It's time for me. 

Speaker 2  (12:05)
The maxims. 

Speaker 3  (12:07)
If you want to talk to somebody, because he see Shen. 

Speaker 2  (12:12)
So what is the name of your belief? Again? Yeah, that was fantastic. 

Speaker 3  (12:18)
Like so somebody came and said, I have an idea about The gas oscillation for plastic form and we said, okay, and they didn't even understand about the intellectual property, the person that said it was more AI than the problem. We can help you with a kind of like a Big Brother shop like this. So sea Shan worked on that as a student for years, and that's how simple the place, right, so he sir, I'm going how you doing with the show. 

Speaker 3  (12:54)
Because while there are different, don't do this, because I kind of like the research. More, but I want to You know, set him up and you know, let him what we're learning from each other. 

Speaker 2  (13:08)
Yeah, that's a good thing. 

Speaker 3  (13:11)
Okay, every more guys are there and rock? Is the guy's name? I talk one of the founders. 

Speaker 3  (13:17)
Yeah, it would be good for you. Definitely to different angles of what you 

Speaker 2  (13:20)
The infrastructure. Check out 0. Take care. 

Speaker 2  (13:24)
Take care. 

Speaker 1  (13:29)
So I find universities We're really difficult to navigate, because there's so many people there, so many different researchers that are doing the different types of Would you have specific? Would you know of any researchers that would be good to connect with? I mean, maybe yourself or 

Speaker 2  (13:51)
Being Gumi? Has I mean, that's a good one? Because my supervisor is also trying to find a way to connect because we do have a team team of 1012 people master. 

Speaker 2  (14:02)
And PhD students, we are working on mostly working with the ideas related to noble skill power, so it's about electrical grid, mostly I mean me myself, I'm a little bit, not the like others, I'm trying to some kind of see what I'm curious about different kind of sectors. That's 1 and 2 mechanical side, and my supervisor would love to be connected to some kind of different people. So probably I can send you an email and say that introduces is my Prof. 

Speaker 2  (14:32)
from the house university. He's the only because we do have different kind of sectors in electrical engineering. We have power communications processing. 

Speaker 2  (14:41)
Anything is the only Prof. from the power part in a power in our department. So he would love to be connected to people and probably even can talk more about his students because obviously I don't know all of them. 

Speaker 2  (14:56)
But he can see that one, and this is a very good thing. Because he told me that when you go to this kind of conferences try to find people that actually would like to be connected to some kind of Academy game. Yeah, I mean we saw that the guy was working on Academy said you want a job here. 

Speaker 2  (15:13)
Why not? Yeah? Yeah? 

Speaker 1  (15:15)
Trapped I just saw the message from Sharon. I will be doing the academics. No, you will be yeah. 

Speaker 1  (15:22)
So I've not checked any coming in, but Yeah, I'm definitely done by one. 

Speaker 2  (15:37)
We kind of diluted the graph because of lunch. You know, so 

Speaker 1  (15:46)
The share supervisor has the interact with industry. Did you partner with industry? 

Speaker 2  (15:51)
I'm not partner wise, but he's so active and he has lots of connection with industry. That's why he encourages us to go around. Do some kind of make some connections. 

Speaker 2  (16:04)
But to be honest with you, most of the students and most of the people they don't like challenges, they said, okay, I do my research. I'm at the lab behind the computer, do my AI stuff, and that's it. So that no, it doesn't work like that. 

Speaker 2  (16:17)
You have to be out there, you don't want a job. You don't want to know people because these people are going to lead you to a job. Right You have an idea, your idea is fantastic but in the lab on the papers. 

Speaker 2  (16:28)
So it's going to give you the validation. You cannot say that yeah, I do have a super idea. You wanted to say it. 

Speaker 2  (16:34)
Okay, they, did that who. Are you working who? You know, I mean most of the people when I'm reaching out to them said that I talked with a guy, you know how to say that yeah, I know that guy said that okay, I talked with him. 

Speaker 2  (16:44)
So they would say, okay, I'm listening to you now. I mean, that's the way it is, right? That's how it works. 

Speaker 2  (16:49)
So you're some kind of my friends, I'm trying to encourage you. To say that okay come, around see, them war, we, don't want it regulated that I didn't see you there. 

Speaker 1  (17:07)
Sorry. 

Speaker 1  (17:33)
It already settled on air quality. Yeah, exactly. So did we hear? 

Speaker 1  (17:50)
So no I don't know Arthur. 

Speaker 2  (17:57)
There you. 

Speaker 2  (18:21)
I'm so confident that there 

Speaker 1  (18:24)
So stage? 
