
Speaker 1  (00:28)
Good morning, everyone. My name is Guyon I'm the CEO of founder of a company called satan. And today we're here to talk about, you know, this massive information that we're all having to deal with, certainly, we have to deal within the day-to-day running of the business. 

Speaker 1  (00:44)
Whether you own it, whether you're a manager, whether you're a supervisor it's all about documentation, it's in all its forms and your ability to extract intelligence from information. And then send it, get it. Do something with it and send it out. 

Speaker 1  (01:01)
And if I had to guess why you're here today is your day-to-day probably looks like this certainly your week to week. There's probably a time in your work schedule in your work. Planning, time or your thinking, either you're overwhelmed or your department is overwhelmed, or your colleagues are overwhelmed with information. 

Speaker 1  (01:24)
And when we talk about documentation, we don't just mean simple paper, we mean everything that is documented in a company where AI could play an important role in helping you extract information quickly move faster than the competition and certainly answer to your clients at the speed at which they're expecting answers because I would caution everybody in today's world if your client is starting to use? AI E is certainly expecting you to be using AI which means he's probably expecting you to work faster, not harder faster with the information that you're providing him on a daily weekly, monthly annual basis. 

Speaker 1  (02:04)
And so that's where we're here today. We created a workshop to give you some ideas as to how you can introduce artificial intelligence in our case, we use agents. So as we so as to say, really the time for companies to have to build these things and manage them and teach them how to chat and use Claude, create agents that they can really share eternally. 

Speaker 1  (02:25)
There is an easier way, and we'd like to share that with you today. You know, people think that we've gone paperless, and we have to some degree, but that's certainly in my lifetime. And I've gone from the full paper to the full digital I've never been as overwhelmed with information, as I am today, it's just too easy to send a PDF. 

Speaker 1  (02:43)
It's too easy to send ACS me to 50 people before you have the photocopy something and it took work right, so you thought twice before you did, 10 copies of something. And then, before you know a bit after that, you could copy a bunch of people, but you were limited in size as to what you could send. So then you had to figure out Sen. 

Speaker 1  (03:00)
John or Jane, because I really don't have enough, you know, data or capability at the it department to push out all this information, it's no longer an issue. So we're all receiving some sort of digital data in almost on real-time basis. And so for us, you know, we're seeing, certainly with a lot of the clients that we work with is people are trying to use ChatGPT and Gemini in COD and Microsoft gold pilot, and they're finding that it's very good for something from certainly useful products as well. 

Speaker 1  (03:30)
But they hit a wall, especially when they're starting to talk complex environments like in manufacturing, you know, whether you're building plane trains or automobiles or anything that you know, is supplied to that ecosystem or supports that ecosystem, you're going to be dealing with complex information, what do we need by complex information, not just words. But graphs and tables and csbs and Excel's where the information that you need, and that you need to convey your customers to your auditors, to your qate department, discontained in that information, and it takes you days, really, it should take you minutes if you had the right tools. 

Speaker 1  (04:09)
And so what we're seeing in Canada and it's been well documented and certainly why the government at all levels, really municipal provincial federal are trying to incentivize companies to adopt technology to gain productivity. Right, and it's not to put people out the door it's to realize that we have a shortage of resources essentially. And you've got a growing demand for your products and services. 

Speaker 1  (04:33)
And so, how do you reconcile the 2 usually technology ends up playing a role and in today's world? It is certainly artificial intelligence. If you can figure out how to use it properly in your company. 

Speaker 1  (04:50)
So today there's a little workshop feel to this. It's very interactive. Who we are is we're really a company that provides tools for employees, tools that want to use in their data day as I like to say to people, you know, I believe that an AI can take a lot of the stuff that you don't like to do that. 

Speaker 1  (05:07)
Your colleagues don't like to do and help you do a better job and more stuff you actually enjoy likes to get app in the morning and figure out how to spend half my day compiling information, like you didn't go to school for that, you certainly didn't do a career, because of that. What you really want to do is to save how do I use my time? My knowledge, my expertise to add value beyond the compile. 

Speaker 1  (05:29)
Beyond the just looking at Excel tables and building yet another pivot, so you're going to see a few examples of how you can do that today. We hope that the main takeaway out of this is that you'll see the data. As you know, the Tylenol to your documentation problems. 

Speaker 1  (05:46)
Certainly, you know, we like to believe that we eliminate bottlenecks throughout companies or processes at different levels of the business. So I'll do a little bit true on documentation. I started. 

Speaker 1  (05:59)
I'll talk about this bottlenecks and give you some examples about 1520 minutes of this workshop is concrete examples that we've recorded for you these examples. By the way, are examples from clients that have talked to us and said, I wish I could solve this problem. However, all the data that I'm using in these demos are open source data. 

Speaker 1  (06:17)
So there's no client data being shared here, even though you're going to see some client name, as the examples of what can be done. But the wrong relation, and I'll explain it as received examples. One thing you're not going to see today though I could have brought my AI expert so I could have overwhelmed you with tech jargon. 

Speaker 1  (06:34)
That's not the purpose. I think too many of these conferences start talking about llms and agentic and machine and deep learning. And you know, claw and all these technologies and really, they don't mean a lot unless you deploy them in a way that is useful. 

Speaker 1  (06:49)
So that's not the purpose of certainly subtain the other thing you're going to see today. If you're expecting, you know, to see a presentation on long, costly AI services that are going to take you months to deploy you're in the wrong room, we're all about out of the box solutions that you can use very quickly in your data. They work. 

Speaker 1  (07:09)
A little bit of background in how we got here today, we actually used to do a lot of AI services we used to do like a lot of companies, especially 4 or 5 years ago, you really didn't have a choice, because the tools weren't available yet, for people in general, to be able to just use off-the-shelf AI unable solution and plug it into their operations. So you didn't have too much choice. You kind of had to go through an AI consulting firm unless you had built up your data, scientists and ML engineers in-house, to be able to deploy something. 

Speaker 1  (07:37)
And we've done that. We've worked with some big companies, some small, medium-sized companies across Canada, and we decided about 2 or 3 years ago, by listening to our customers that most clients were looking for solutions out of the box. They weren't looking for these long hour wise or yet to spend 8 to 10 months. 

Speaker 1  (07:53)
You know proving that a solution will work in your operations. And then, you know, making sure that we can get that return on investment over 2 or 3 years. There's no appetite for our oil that takes to 3 years anymore. 

Speaker 1  (08:05)
If you can't show your boss, if you get a turn something to 6 months, you know, returnal investment. Most people are, and so that's why we committed. And we created the platform what we realized is that clients, people like ourselves don't buy AI. 

Speaker 1  (08:20)
There's this fallacy out there that we're going to sell AI. You're not selling AI you're selling what AI you can free just like you use tools and your daily data that is not AI that are not AI driven and you expect them to deliver some sort of result, some sort of a value. And so if what you're looking at is not simplifying you or your team's life in a short order, then you should pass. 

Speaker 1  (08:43)
Because there are certainly platforms out there, as in others that can help you really accelerate how you work effectively as a team inside your organization at various functional levels. Call It. And the other thing is, AI is creating an automation tool. 

Speaker 1  (09:00)
Right? I mean, if you think of it, you're asking a software that's all the other is an algorithm that's going to do something hopefully better faster and cheaper than it would either in existing software, an existing sax, an existing legacy platform that you may have or a team of people that will be unable to work more effectively together, that's the real value that can need to ask yourself when you're looking at these platform. It's talked a little bit about document intelligence. 

Speaker 1  (09:30)
Document intelligence is the notion that in your documents, whether they're PDFs, whether they're words, whether they're diagrams, whether they're drawing, whether they're tables, whether they're C sbs, Lasalle, yet lies within a lot of powerful inflow, that either you don't have the time to analyze, or take you too long to analyze, or that you have to convert from data, sometimes on structure, sometimes structured into something that you have to pass on, either internally or internal customer or externally into somebody else. 

Speaker 1  (10:00)
And there's a decision that goes along with, that's the purpose of documentation either informs you or compels you to act and unfortunately, in too many cases, companies or information, rich decision, poor because they can't take action on this notion of information. And so what do you do you look at different tools, but usually, there's a bottleneck that creates itself, and if you think, for a minute, as to your own function, your own business, or the colleagues that you work with either people that you receive information, or you need information to internal or external, you can probably think of bottlenecks where things just stay too long. 

Speaker 1  (10:42)
Right, it just takes too long to get that information to compile some sort of a decision and to pass it on to somebody else and so many companies and you've seen this before, but many companies, whether it's extracting from diagrams stables, you know words, whether you're a human resource or finance. Or operations, obviously here you're going to be facing and you're facing this today, and so where does that bottleneck come from? Where does the bottleneck come from? 

Speaker 1  (11:09)
It usually comes from either not enough. Time. Because, you know, you're getting more and more of these requests coming up here either, because somebody else is using technology that you're not or just because the business, the business is moving to more kind of kind of. 

Speaker 1  (11:23)
You're either increasing the level of complexity of information that is required. People expect more from you or from your department than they used to 5 years ago. Maybe there are increasing the level of volume and frequency, meaning more reporting, taking the word governance, more meaning, more governance. 

Speaker 1  (11:41)
You hear that all the time in these days, we need more governance, more reporting around QA operations, manufacturing production, and these are all bottom links that are created within very individual working. And your individual worker workers, our you're just adding more capacity to the file right? Somebody says, well, can you also remove this? 

Speaker 1  (12:01)
And you don't have some resources that count, and you don't have that picture. And so what I thought we'd do if you don't mind everything, I've seen a sticking in a head. Quite inside you and it comes one either on your chair of the side. 

Speaker 1  (12:19)
If you could each of you take a minute and think, where is there a bottleneck inside my organization related to information? It could be either a neuron function or a function that helps you it could be something that you're seeing in your colleagues struggle with. Or an extra client that expecting information, and it's just picking up. 

Speaker 1  (12:48)
So take the bottle 2. And if you write about allegibly on that statement, one is that you want to do 23 or 2 prices, whatever 

Speaker 1  (13:39)
This is not a trick. We haven't called it quite, it depends that we're in front of you so that you are or what you're doing now. And what we're going to hear is, until Sheriff, and we're going to use these statements 

Speaker 1  (14:14)
So what I can do is train that stick, and I'm going to put on the back of the chair that's in front of you. And first, we'll share in front of you today, our head of business development. Collective. 

Speaker 1  (14:34)
It's really honestly great. But it's also to see if we're presenting and the examples that you might have written down are going to show up on this on this examples. And during a Q&A session, we'll invite, we'll read some out. 

Speaker 1  (14:52)
All right, so and we won't know where they came from. If someone wants to grab their hand and say, that's mine great. But certainly not an obligation, and so the remainder of the presentation you're going to see is going to go into a lot of examples. 

Speaker 1  (15:08)
So you remember these 2 from earlier on Jane and John, you know, you and your colleagues dealing with delivering making decisions and answering, maybe rfp, splits and proposals. Maybe you're assessing suppliers, maybe you're using documentation for standard operating procedures, struggle, shooting maintenance, and you've got all these volumes of data and the machine Greece down and then a new technician that doesn't have 20 years of experience has to figure out how do I troubleshoot these things? 

Speaker 1  (15:37)
I've got 4 oem documents that are all outdated. And I got the modern SOP and I may have a repo of different bugs or anything or problems that we've had documented in the past and they've got to figure out how to turn around the device quickly or you've got to respond to a proposal that you've got. A wall in terms of the rfp deadline. 

Speaker 1  (15:56)
And it's a maps the document or you've got to produce operational reports, and you need to do that on a regular basis, and you're stuck because you don't have the right tools to do it. So we're going to show you a bunch of different examples. I love this particular ad from fiber fiber. 

Speaker 1  (16:13)
I don't know anybody knows fiber, but they've been around. And they've been this platform, one of the first platforms that democratized a lot of back office work we used to pay $5. Thus the name fiver and the idea was, you put a fiber and we need a marketing in something or a translation, something or anything. 

Speaker 1  (16:31)
And there's somebody there that offers the service. There's stars, people are rated, I've used it many times over the years. And within they give you a quote and say, that'll cost you 5 watch of the first one and then you know, maybe 50 bucks. 

Speaker 1  (16:42)
It's really cheap in terms of the total value. And then AI came along and they came up with this ad and they said to their own people, if you don't use AI at fiber, you're going to be out of the job or use AI and it'll take your job to the next level. And I always like that. 

Speaker 1  (16:57)
Ad, because really it's what AI should be able to do for you. It's about raising your capabilities without putting more work on you assumption. And so here's an example that we put together on how you can use platforms like ChatGPT, copilot and engine Gemini and first of all, anybody here who uses these platforms at home. 

Speaker 1  (17:21)
And you know, for your league planning in Paris? Anybody used it for work. Okay, thank you. 

Speaker 1  (17:30)
I'll see you okay now. Have you heard of shadow ayahuas? So shadow AI is the concept that employees are saying I need to use AI. 

Speaker 1  (17:41)
My company has employed me. I could yet, but I'm going to use it for work. Because I know it's going to simplify my life. 

Speaker 1  (17:48)
But in theory, I should, because, you know, I don't have a governance yet, the company hasn't given me the licenses and so on. This is a really issuing company study. Why it shouldn't be a good thing? 

Speaker 1  (17:58)
But it is because when you're using shadow AI, it's usually a license that shares all your data with the AI provider. So whether it's chat or Microsoft or one or the others, unless you're using a throw license from work, the chances are all the data that you're putting into these platforms are going outside the right. And that's the problem, the shadow of AI, how having said that these platforms, if they're enterprise grade, we should tomorrow allows you to do a few things. 

Speaker 1  (18:24)
But what you're going to see here is an example. And I published art what you're seeing here is a chat called piloting and Germany, the idea here is it's really a chat interface, right? These products basically assume that you as a consumer will know how to chat in a business manner to create a series of prompts that eventually give you an answer in this case. 

Speaker 1  (18:53)
No analyzing data from an aircraft again publicly open source data on various aircraft cargo details that in this case, an airline would use and the idea here is really to show that I am so continuous first. We're using coal pilot, and you're getting some structured information, but it's already struggling. Because the data provided was not structured enough for coal pilot to give you an answer. 

Speaker 1  (19:25)
So it starts telling the user, can you add more information, please? So that I can do a better job at providing information. So it's smart, right? 

Speaker 1  (19:33)
It must ask the question, then what you're seeing at the bottom here is we're going into another platform. And then saying, okay, we're not getting enough. Good answers from the first open platform. 

Speaker 1  (19:43)
So we'll switch, and we'll ask it in different question along the same lines, to see if I can get more information. So now what you're seeing is it's Have you checked? How many insights were now you're getting a lot. 

Speaker 1  (19:56)
More information provided in terms of the breakdown of the information. Still not good enough. So number one to co filing coal filet's a little more technical. 

Speaker 1  (20:05)
So then the herea, you know, not an it or something, it becomes a little more problematic to get comfortable with the platform like Coke Violet, though, it gives you a lot of out of the box functionality for simple things and what do we mean by simple a connected are Okay? And then So insights provided, but at a high level. And one thing that you'll notice in most people's life is the sources or extra, or additional or an extra step, which means if you want to validate what the platform is giving you you've got to go play sources, and most of the time, you don't get a very specific source that you'll get a general area idea as to where the AI from that platform want to get the information to give you an answer. 

Speaker 1  (20:50)
So it's a good way to trace if you sort of high level traceability for some people, it's enough for others, it's not to not get back to that element. So these platforms have a lot of utility, like I said, we use them a lot before use them. But it's Then, I'll ask the question hallucinations, everybody here heard the term hallucinations when it comes to AI. 

Speaker 1  (21:11)
Yeah, so we hear this term, right. What is hallucinations? And it's funny because we hear it along the world that I don't really like, kind of know what it is because I don't know what it means. 

Speaker 1  (21:19)
But what does it mean in the ice in the world of AI? Hallucinations are simple. Most AI algorithms at the core of AI have been trained to please the user take their incentivize to give you an answer. 

Speaker 1  (21:34)
So hallucination in AI is what the algorithm sought or daughter really wants to please mummer, dad and says no matter what I'm going to answer the question and they'll go as far as invent information to give you an answer and an AI. It's really easy to do because the world of information is there. So guess what? 

Speaker 1  (21:53)
You're asking me, you know what the weather's going to be like tomorrow? I don't have enough data to tell you I'm going to make up an answer that looks really, really good. So I'm going to tell is going to be sunny 25° all day. 

Speaker 1  (22:02)
Because that's what you want to hear. But it may not be that at all, because I don't have the fact that out, okay, so in the world of AI, big problem. And I'll show you an example here here what we took is. 

Speaker 1  (22:13)
We took a complex document. This is a Boeing, 737 spec from the airline Ryanair and we ask questions. And it's very simple. 

Speaker 1  (22:25)
We took the document and we said, can you provide the information on the air brake system of this particular aircraft and This particular platform which is ChatGPT, needs to work really hard at looking at the site of the document. In this case, BDF format I'm saying neurotic system schematics has referenced the argument. It's been found in automatic flight. 

Speaker 1  (22:57)
Flight controls like blah, blah blah, blah, blah Vs breakdown of the air rate system, speak rates or panels at the upper wing surface that increase drag these flight spoilers and Rock spoilers and reasons and flight actuation spoilers of hydraulically actuated, unwriting deployment and TV. If you check the take up, our kilogram position is deployed, supplementations etc. Etc, so you're going Here you go. 

Speaker 1  (23:26)
All right, we're going to say in terms of I don't know what this is real-time. So it's given to human science. So real-time wakes up. 

Speaker 1  (23:33)
The problem is there is no airbreak system 370 There isn't so we put it to our platform and we ask the same question. Same argument describe the air from systematic. Our platform says I cannot find air grace schematics. 

Speaker 1  (23:51)
In this thing, it doesn't exist. However, you might have been thinking of another type of system related to breaks or air, right? Because it's a swording platform, so it provides the information, but more importantly, it gives you all the sources at the very line item table or drawing that kind of stretch that data force. 

Speaker 1  (24:12)
Then, that's the difference between hallucinating. Usually this information given to you and an authoritative manner. You believe it because it sounds right? 

Speaker 1  (24:21)
And you've got to be very careful if you're an engineering manufacturing operations airline, you know. If you're in all those types of industries, you know, some information you can get away with getting, you know. So so others you can't, we believe that most platforms today, if they don't get, we use source traceability and down to the line item, it's putting too much risk in your decision-making, because you're there to empower the human at the end of the day. 

Speaker 1  (24:46)
And you own the human being to be able to go I know my business. I'm still going to review the recommendation. And if I find something doesn't add up, I want to click and I don't have to re-read the document. 

Speaker 1  (24:57)
I don't want to be sent to a general section. I want to know exactly where the AI is. Giving me its information, and why that's the difference between a hallucination and an on hallucination, really important when you're trying in some of these different platforms. 

Speaker 1  (25:11)
So when do you need something more performant than a chat or cold pilot? The Gemini, or even a call Well, we think because we've been working with all these industries that whenever you're dealing with complex information complex can be drawings mixed with schematics mixed with stables mixed with pdfs, obviously data excelsiz, and you've got to take action. You need a platform that is a little more performing than what you can find sort of on the ecosystem today. 

Speaker 1  (25:40)
And so there are 2 ways to look at AI and deployment in your companies. Some people go the cop by the group and for some things. But then they have to build governance as to when it cannot be used. 

Speaker 1  (25:50)
Some people will go the build your own agents in the house. The problem with that is, on the one hand great stuff because you get agents deployed, usually they're not standardized, they're hard to deploy that scale inside a company because they're developed in a limited infrastructure, and they're very hard to collaborate. Also, you use 1 unusual 1, you use one. 

Speaker 1  (26:08)
But then if we want to use the same one together, more complicated, and most of them don't allow you to share. And collaborate information. So when you're looking at your AI solutions, if it's just for you in your corner it works, but if you're going to want to collaborate with team members in or out of your organization, you want something that allows you to share files, work on the same files and advance the process in an organized way and in a repeatable way, and so in our case, we'll find others. 

Speaker 1  (26:36)
We believe that the way to help organization is to have these AI. Tools that you can use the word agents, but they're essentially a tool that allows you to get started without having to check your way through the chat structures already being set up if you normally get it that way and you're able to just pull a tool. So in here, you're seeing examples such as an document capability, mapper to map through your capabilities. 

Speaker 1  (27:02)
Maybe a bit the artificial process tool of data science, qrl, Canada bio. So we use this kind of advice here to look for opportun. It's a big source of information. 

Speaker 1  (27:15)
Many people will spend days and weeks trying to figure out the thousands of the living items so we created an agent that goes into Canada, vice maps to your capabilities and says, you do, these will be 18 opportunities that you should look at. And then allows you to extract the 18 download it in the platform. Figure out a goal, no, based on your capabilities. 

Speaker 1  (27:33)
And then down, select your top 3241 and then begin to map out an art in the matter of hours, not days and weeks. So that's just an example of how tools network together, and so you end up saving quite a bit of time I used to do this presentation. And we talked about 10X you know, 10 times savings on people time resources, AI at the speed of AI today. 

Speaker 1  (27:57)
You're talking 30X50XA 100X in some cases, and in some of the devils, you're going to continue to see are filmed in real-time. One devil goes through thousands of documents in a few seconds. To give you meaningful trustable information, it's no longer A10X game. 

Speaker 1  (28:15)
It's hard to fathom in some cases, even when we use these internally. So, for example, we have a client using one the rfp platform for bids and proposals. They're going from 45 days to 5, and that's a major you know, a major opportunity gain, because now for them, it was actually, they couldn't increase more people. 

Speaker 1  (28:33)
They just wanted to use the same people to bid more without overloading them on having to work harder. So now you're saving time, and you're doing better proposals. Another one is using it for subcontractors. 

Speaker 1  (28:43)
So they procurement, you know, you're getting a bunch of tenders yourself, and you gotta figure out who am I going to pick and you want to be able to defend your choice, that's another way to think of AI and operational shooting, the recording would be another one, but you can see The Times of gains here are pretty massive and they're not exaggerated. So you know, some people say, well, what's the difference between the copilots and chat versus a platform like the tame? Well, you know, there are many, one is most of those pilot questions. 

Speaker 1  (29:10)
All those platforms cannot handle big documents as soon as you get outside of about a 100 or a 100 and Max pages. And if, certainly, if they have drawings and a bunch of things embedded, the platforms can handle it. And so now you end up parting, parsing out, like little pass, little tasks, and it's very inefficient. 

Speaker 1  (29:27)
And so that I would say is one of the major differences, but also you'll see here But a platform like ours structures, the vehicle, right? So you have to spend weeks and months, the yellow lab is an AI. You need a large language model. 

Speaker 1  (29:43)
Shouldn't that very well mean what we call orchestration in the background, we will take the best AI platforms, but tools that are not using. We've made the magic happen so to speak about it, we certainly have full traceability, as we saw in the CBS to get the exact defenders. Diversity matching from the data once you do something on the platform so, you use it as you would any other tool normally start a chat if. 

Speaker 1  (30:29)
You have something that you say you can do a difference only later, months later, to see how things in the progress, unfortunately fall in terms All right, so I'm going to give you some hard examples that hopefully will match some of the stickies that we've seen provided today. First, you're going to just give you an overview. The platform allows you to work in a canvan environment. 

Speaker 1  (30:54)
So you can set up a project you can share project you can collaborate on a project. You can have multiple projects at the same time. Whatever the documentation related activity is And it allows you to sorry There you go. 

Speaker 1  (31:14)
And what you're seeing here is the north P from the Canadian space agency that has dozens of files and declined and not a client with the user. Here we use mda as a fictitious client, by the way, I drive by the NDA facility almost every day near where I work in Montreal. So I want planet, all my team, let's get a space example. 

Speaker 1  (31:36)
And we went to get a Canada, buys a lunar vehicle rfp, and we did a scrub of the. MBA website and all the capabilities in this public, and we matched the 2 and we created this demo, but it could be anybody, but what you're seeing here is that the use case is not just the rfp, most of you probably have Q&A question and answers that you can go back-and-forth. With with a bitter before the bit is before the deadline. 

Speaker 1  (32:03)
And so the incorporates the goals and incorporates any other relevant information to the pit so that you're able to extract a summary. In seconds, it gave the summary is, you know, high level summary, that matches your particular templates internally to decide. Should you bid, not bid it allows you to extract and we'll come back to this demo in a few minutes. 

Speaker 1  (32:24)
It gives you source traceability to every single document that you may be basing a decision on, and it allows you to then tend to create templates that you can reuse each time afterwards, right? So once you've done a company set the templates that match yourself, not the generic templates that change for the products, then you will use that template and you standardize across the organization, which is a huge productivity data. So what' You also will get the ability to assess requirements as functional or not. 

Speaker 1  (32:56)
You know, critical or not. And if you push into the extreme, which we did in this demo, you're able to see in my capabilities, because you all have capability documents internally, whether it's an old rift that you've done, which by definition has your capabilities, you use those documents and you create a capability template that you can then match the new opportunity to, but it could be an operational record and you want to So we have a canband we have the ability to chat and create full workflow, so instead of using the toolkit, like a writer like a requirement extractor a reporter like a web analysis, a planet, some of the tools that you saw we also created full workflows. 

Speaker 1  (33:39)
So the example here is, you know, the bits and proposals workflow, so bits and proposal that's 5 or 6 stages that everybody does you all do a differently in your company, but you're all doing the same steps, and so we created a workflow, so people can either go and use a tool or they can say no I don't want a tool that I want is the ability to start the workflow, I want to get a document I want to analyze and create a summary step. I want to extract the important steps that forward. I want to share internally with feedback. 

Speaker 1  (34:09)
Step 5 and then I want to consolidate all that and make an executive report stem 6, so you can work through a courtflow, or you can go pick an individual program make sense. And then because Chad people still like to chat with documents, because at the end of the day it may not give you awful, what you need. We still provide a powerful chat function, and so for at some point you go okay. 

Speaker 1  (34:33)
I like this paragraph. Can you tell me more? You can do that within the platform as well. 

Speaker 1  (34:40)
All right. So here's It's a third use case. And here what we're going to do is you're going to see again. 

Speaker 1  (34:51)
A reading of a pretty quick requirement is to the job and your reading Vs that requirement, whether it's an engineering, the technology, a program management type information. But, again, you know, substitute any sort of documents to this one. And then it allows the user to then progressively go through the assessment and make a decision on the outcome. 

Speaker 1  (35:15)
Remember I always say the user, because it truly is a human and a little platform, it's there to help people work better. It's not there to just, it's there to replace the tedious work. It's not there to replace the value editor Okay, the other one is an operational use case. 

Speaker 1  (35:32)
So in this case, what we've done. As we've taken a document which is a speck from a Crane from its war It's manual Australia, and this one shows you that sometimes the information that you require may not be written in a paragraph. The information that you require in many companies in many industries actually lies in the drawing. 

Speaker 1  (35:57)
There's a lot of words, blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah might tell you something, but the customer is going to hold you to what's from the drawing or what's in the table and so what this allows you to do which other platforms don't is it allows you to trace the information down to any source possible? So in this case, the specific data that was requested. Each museum is a little clickable numbers. 

Speaker 1  (36:23)
They're facing resource information, and you'll see that in this case, the information can produce 2 places a drawing. And a table and other platforms should not allow you to do that. But a lot of the people in your competence actually need to find information wherever the source comes from and what they Don't WANT. 

Speaker 1  (36:42)
You have to do is jump from one platform to another to another, to another. Right? And so this allows you to do that. 

Speaker 1  (36:48)
So if you're in that operational role, where you're doing reports, where you're doing even oem, that evaluations or supplier evaluations, or you're comparing 4 spec, because somebody tells you I need you to buy it, we need to get a Jack or a sky a skylift, and you have to assess forced suppliers while you're able to do that very effectively. And more importantly, when somebody doesn't win or doesn't get a job or doesn't meet your requirements, you're able to tell them why very concrete so the traceability from an internal or external governance is really overhearing. 

Speaker 1  (37:23)
So the third one is a procurement use case here what we did is we took a national research center proposal. And then we took a Washington State public school. Also proposal and pay attention, especially to the second one, because there what we're doing is we're comparing and what we were able to do that by the way, because this is public information, so the issue ersp and then the part of the rsp was you have to allow the government or the state to publicly publish the results right, so it's a fully transparent system. 

Speaker 1  (37:57)
So we're able to get the original source rfp, and we're able to get the bids and we know the winner was, and then we just pulled our platform matchups, as if you were the procurement person to the rfp and see who wanted in fact, we validated, but you know with our own platform that the winner should mean the winner. And we did that in order of life I've meant So what you're seeing here is natural research center, aluminum casting cell from the NRC submission instruction on a fee. So in this case, we're looking at it from the rna NRC, receiving all this information and having to then spend weeks analyzing the seed who should be awarded the contract and again, same kind of concept can hit the data, but you're able to assess very objectively, you're not able to do the new supplier balance as well and not for switching to the question that the state one or on top because 2 will there are 3 billion? 

Speaker 1  (38:58)
That's estimated to be deliver. And we assess both downward percentage ratings in terms of how well these things meet period this could be a choice. This could be opportunity. 

Speaker 1  (39:12)
Documents that you're trying to figure out if you're reading, this could be our, this could be your internal reproduction data, it could be whatever you want it to be. But the idea that you can hold 234 inherableness and parallel analyze them or consolidate them. However, you want and again taking minutes instead of hours and day. 

Speaker 1  (39:46)
All right. So I think that's the part of it really safe. For example, you saw some Microsoft, some copilot, some Gemini, you saw some chechty in there and you saw how to use it in terms of your data, the ec quick research stuff when you need to, you saw stuff around carefully hallucinations, when it matters. 

Speaker 1  (40:14)
Because, you know, if you're making decisions on stuff, that's critical. You want to avoid that and then we jump into, you know, a lot of rft based or causal small documents, large documents, operational reporting and procurement type of activities. The examples are endless, so I have to read for and at the end of the day, the only 2 or four things you want to think about is you deploy AI. 

Speaker 1  (40:37)
And currently is one It could It's not a technology, it's broad adoption. In all the research is showing right now that many companies are training at the adoption in Germany is less than 20%. So I think there are some degrees. 

Speaker 1  (40:53)
Some athlete, currently important to use about AI. And frankly, what we're seeing more and more is employed for somewhere where 15 maps are only valued, all of their whole notifications should be very careful. And then number three is how much heavy lifting you can have to gain the information that you mentioned. 

Speaker 1  (41:28)
And some of The New York Times Could be an issue some industry healthcare sites? I don't care, but some great it's not carefully deliberately surprising. So having said that, I'll open up the Q&A have Any questions, and at the same time, I'll let mark deeply. 

Speaker 1  (42:09)
Think about information that we're bringing up first any questions about Right here, right? I didn't like the temptation one question. Is it important to say it? 

Speaker 1  (42:27)
Yeah, so our platform made it by designing the process. 
